<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="100">This ring was named after Havel the Rock,
Lord Gwyn's old battlefield compatriot.

Havel's men wore the ring to express faith in
their leader and to carry a heavier load.</text>
<text id="101">The rare gem called tearstone has the
uncanny ability to sense imminent death.

This red tearstone from Carim boosts the
attack of its wearer when in danger.</text>
<text id="102">Ring granted to those bound by the
Darkmoon Blade covenant.
Answer Dark Sun Gwyndolin's summoning.

Gwyndolin, all too aware of his repulsive,
frail appearance, created the illusion of 
a sister Gwynevere, who helps him guard
over Anor Londo. An unmasking of these
deities would be tantamount to blasphemy.</text>
<text id="103">Ring granted to those bound by the
Forest Hunter covenant.
Answer Alvina's summoning.

The white cat Alvina speaks a human tongue
and has lived since the early Age of Fire.
Alvina was a trusted friend of Knight
Artorias and the Great Wolf Sif.</text>
<text id="104">This ancient ring, engraved with a large
green flower, is of unknown origin.

Hastens the regeneration of stamina.</text>
<text id="105">Stoneplates, the symbol of a true knight,
grant the strength to face various hardships.

The red stoneplate symbolizes fire,
and boosts defence against flame.</text>
<text id="106">Stoneplates, the symbol of a true knight,
grant the strength to face various hardships.

The yellow stoneplate symbolizes thunder,
and boosts defence against lightning.</text>
<text id="107">Stoneplates, the symbol of a true knight,
grant the strength to face various hardships.

The blue stoneplate symbolizes souls,
and boosts defence against magic.</text>
<text id="108">Stoneplates, the symbol of a true knight,
grant the strength to face various hardships.

The precious rare speckled stoneplate grants
a small boost to defence against magic,
flame, and lightning.</text>
<text id="109">One of the infamous bite rings
commissioned by Sir Arstor of Carim.

Despite the dreadful rumors surrounding its
creation, this ring is an unmistakable asset,
in its ability to help prevent bleeding.</text>
<text id="110">One of the infamous bite rings
commissioned by Sir Arstor of Carim.

Despite the dreadful rumors surrounding its
creation, this ring is an unmistakable asset,
in its ability to help prevent poison.</text>
<text id="111">Ring made of an ancient tiny red jewel.
Grants small increase to HP.

Rings grant powers large and small.
Their discovery, and effective use,
can make one's journey easier.</text>
<text id="113">One of the infamous bite rings
commissioned by Sir Arstor of Carim.

Despite the dreadful rumors surrounding its
creation, this ring is an unmistakable asset,
in its ability to help prevent curses.</text>
<text id="114">A divine ring entrusted to the head bishop
of the Way of White and apostle to
Allfather Lloyd, uncle to Lord Gwyn.
It grants additional attunement slots.

The head bishop of the Way of White is the
guardian of law and caste, and one of the
great royals of Thorolund.</text>
<text id="115">A special ring granted to only the most
accomplished sorcerers at Vinheim Dragon
School.

The ring is engraved with an everlasting
dragon, and boosts the strength of sorceries.</text>
<text id="116">This magic crown-shaped ring was granted
to Princess Dusk of Oolacile upon her birth.

The ringstone allows its wearer to cast
additional magics, but at the cost of
one-half of HP.</text>
<text id="117">One of the special rings granted to the four
knights of Gwyn. The Hornet Ring belonged
to the Lord's Blade Ciaran.

By boosting critical attacks, its wearer can
annihilate foes, as Ciaran's dagger laid
waste to Lord Gwyn's enemies.</text>
<text id="119">One of the special rings granted to the four
knights of Gwyn. The Hawk Ring belonged to
Hawkeye Gough, who led the Greatarchers.

Boosts bow range, so that arrows fly like
they were shot by Gough's great bow,
which took down high-flying dragons.</text>
<text id="120">This ring belonged to the Knight King Rendal.
It grants its wearer protection by boosting
defense against physical attacks.

Of the many legends surrounding the Knight
King Rendal, one of the more well-known
speaks of his standing down a giant drake
and slashing it to pieces.</text>
<text id="121">The serpent is an imperfect dragon and symbol
of the Undead. Its habit of devouring prey
even larger than itself has led to an
association with gluttony.

This gold ring, engraved with the serpent,
boosts its wearer's item discovery, so that
more items can be amassed.</text>
<text id="122">The serpent is an imperfect dragon and symbol
of the Undead. Its habit of devouring prey
even larger than itself has led to an
association with gluttony.

This silver ring, engraved with the serpent,
rewards its wearer with additional souls
for each kill.</text>
<text id="123">This ring was secretly worn by a certain
surreptitious sorcerer at Vinheim Dragon
School.

The ring is engraved with an everlasting
dragon in silent slumber, and masks all
sound emitting from its wearer.</text>
<text id="124">Those who befriend Alvina are given this
mysterious ring. It resembles a pearl with
its robust pure-white fog.

The ring camouflages its wearer's
presence, helping to prevent detection.</text>
<text id="125">This iron ring was used to shackle the
guilty. It is terribly rusted, and faintly
stained with blood.

Those who find this strange ring to their
liking will be pleased to find it easier to
gain footing on poor ground such as swamps.</text>
<text id="126">This mystical ring was created in a
sacrificial rite of Velka, the Goddess
of Sin.

Its wearer will lose nothing upon death,
but the ring itself breaks.</text>
<text id="127">This mystical ring was created in a
sacrificial rite of Velka, the Goddess
of Sin. The magenta-shaded ring is
especially rare.

Its wearer will lose nothing upon death,
and will be freed from any curse whatsoever,
but the ring itself breaks.</text>
<text id="128">This special ring crafted in an Eastern land
is made of gold, but with a wood grain crest
on its surface.

Agents of subterfuge in this faraway land
are particularly fond of the dark gold wood
grain, which greatly alters its wearer's
rolling action.</text>
<text id="130">This ring is granted to those who enter a
Covenant with Gwynevere, daughter of Lord Gwyn
and the Princess of Sunlight. This slightly
warm ring boosts the synergy of miracles.

The Princess of Sunlight Gwynevere left
Anor Londo along with many other deities,
and later became wife to Flame God Flann.</text>
<text id="137">Old ring from an old witch.

Engraved minutely with indecipherable
script, but seemingly useless.</text>
<text id="138">This ring symbolizes Knight Artorias's
covenant with the beasts of the Abyss.

Its wearer, like Artorias himself, can
traverse the Abyss.</text>
<text id="139">An orange ring enchanted by a witch.
Reduces lava damage.

Since his sores were inflamed by lava
from birth, his witch sisters gave him
this special ring. But fool that he is,
he readily dropped it, and from that spot,
a terrible centipede demon was born.</text>
<text id="141">A special ring granted to only the most
accomplished sorcerers at Vinheim Dragon
School.

The ring is engraved with a lingering
dragon, and boosts the length of the
effects of sorceries.</text>
<text id="142">According to legend, this ring contains the
spirit of the evil eye, a dark beast which
assaulted Astora.

The strength of the evil eye does not waver,
and HP is absorbed from fallen enemies.</text>
<text id="143">A ring symbolizing the favor and
protection of the goddess Fina, known
in legend to possess "fateful beauty."

This ring boosts its wearer's HP, stamina,
and max equipment load, but breaks if
ever removed.</text>
<text id="144">One of the special rings granted to the four
knights of Gwyn. The Leo Ring belonged to
Ornstein the Dragonslayer.

This ring strengthens counters with pierce
weapons. His lugged spear is said
to have sliced a boulder in two.</text>
<text id="145">This special ring crafted in an Eastern land
is made of gold, but with a wood grain crest
on its surface.

The ring slows the loss of weapon durability
and is particularly useful to bearers of
delicate swords crafted in the East.</text>
<text id="146">One of the special rings granted to the four
knights of Gwyn. The Wolf Ring belongs to
Artorias the Abysswalker.

Artorias had an unbendable will of steel,
and was unmatched with a greatsword.</text>
<text id="147">The rare gem called tearstone has the
uncanny ability to sense imminent death.

This blue tearstone from Catarina boosts the
defence of its wearer when in danger.</text>
<text id="148">Lord Gwyn's firstborn, who inherited the
sunlight, once wore this ancient ring.
Boosts the strength of miracles.

Lord Gwyn's firstborn was a god of war,
but his foolishness led to a loss of the
annals, and rescinding of his deific status.
Today, even his name is not known.</text>
<text id="149">This ring is granted to adherents of
Gwyndolin, Darkmoon deity and
last born of Gwyn, Lord of Sunlight.
Grants additional magic attunement slots.

The Dark Sun Gwyndolin is the only remaining
deity in Anor Londo. His followers are few,
but their tasks are of vital importance.</text>
<text id="150">A ring enchanted by the orange eye
of Kalameet, the bringer of calamity.
Doubles damage received by its wearer.

A useless ring befitting of no finger.
Best left unknown, or at least well hidden.</text>
<text id="133">This black diamond ring is granted to those
who enter a Covenant with Velka, the Goddess
of Sin. It automatically counterattacks when
its wearer inflicts sustained damage.

Velka the Goddess of Sin is an eccentric
witch versed in various secret rites.</text>
<text id="134">This ring belonged to the seal guardian
of New Londo. It prevents its wearer's
discovery by cursed ghosts.

There were once three guardians of the seal,
but two of them tired of their eternal task,
and left New Londo long ago.</text>
<text id="140">The ring of a lost miracle of New Londo.
This ring takes damage in place of its
wearer, but has a fixed chance of breaking.

As evidenced by this ring, the culture of
New Londo was unique, and its flooding
is widely considered to be a great loss.</text>
</entries>