<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="100000">Weapon type: Dagger
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

This standard small dagger has only a modest
attack but can be jabbed in rapid succession,
and is effective in critical hits such as
after a parry or when stabbing in the back.
With both slash and thrust attacks, this
dagger is useful in various situations.</text>
<text id="101000">Weapon type: Dagger
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

This dagger is useful after parrying and is
normally equipped in the left hand.

A favorite of the knights of Carim, who are
famous for fighting without a shield.</text>
<text id="102000">Weapon type: Dagger
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

The ghosts of New Londo clutch this wickedly
sharp dagger with their bony hands and make
mincemeat of the living.

One of the cursed weapons which can inflict
damage upon ghosts.</text>
<text id="103000">Weapon type: Dagger
Attack type: Slash

This wide single-edged shortsword is
the favorite of lowly thieves and bandits.

Primarily a slicing weapon, but highly
effective when used for critical hits,
such as after parrying or from behind.</text>
<text id="104000">Weapon type: Dagger
Attack type: Slash

This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons,
came from the tail of Priscilla, the Dragon
Crossbreed in the painted world of Ariamis.
Possessing the power of lifehunt, it dances
about when wielded, in a fashion reminiscent
of the white-robed painting guardians.</text>
<text id="200000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

This small straight sword is widely used,
to an extent only matched by the longsword.

An accessible sword which inflicts consistent
regular damage and high thrust damage, making
it applicable to a variety of situations.</text>
<text id="201000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Widely-used standard straight sword, only
matched in ubiquity by the shortsword.

An accessible sword which inflicts consistent
regular damage and high slash damage, making
it applicable to a variety of situations.</text>
<text id="202000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular

The wide blade of this straight sword
emphasizes slicing and has no thrust attack.

The horizontal sweeping motion makes this
sword effective against multiple enemies.</text>
<text id="203000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Half of the blade of this straight sword is
broken off.

Only the completely Hollowed would even
consider using this as a weapon.</text>
<text id="204000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

The knights of the ancient kingdom of Balder
wielded these rock-solid, long swords which
are excellent for thrust attacks.
Balder was the home of Knight King Rendal,
but the kingdom was reduced to ruins after
a widespread outbreak of Undead.</text>
<text id="205000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

A fully crystallized straight sword.
How such a weapon was created
is entirely unknown.
The crystallization boosts its attack, but
makes the blade brittle. The sword cannot be
used for long, as it cannot be repaired.</text>
<text id="206000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

This standard longsword, belonging to Solaire
of Astora, is of high quality, is well-
forged, and has been kept in good repair.

Easy-to-use and dependable, but unlikely to
live up to its grandiose name.</text>
<text id="207000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Thrust

The choice weapon of the infamous Darkwraith
Kirk, also known as the Knight of Thorns for
the gnarly spikes on his favorite weapon.

This frightful sword deals only thrust
attacks, and causes heavy bleeding.</text>
<text id="208000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular

The silver knights of Anor Londo guard the
city using this beautifully slender weapon.

Its chain attacks, in which the wielder takes
great advancing steps and makes use of his
bodyweight, are deadly even in single hits.</text>
<text id="209000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Straight sword of an unknown knight,
likely one of Astora's superiors.

High-quality weapon with a powerful blessing.</text>
<text id="210000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular

The sword of the knights of the Four Kings of
New Londo. Its blade is wide and thick, and
it is wielded in an unusual manner.
When the Four Kings were seduced by evil,
their knights became Darkwraiths, servants
of the Dark who wielded these darkswords.</text>
<text id="211000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular

This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons,
is formed by a drake's tail. Drakes are
seen as undeveloped imitators of the dragons,
but in they are likely their distant kin.
The sword is imbued with a mystical power,
to be released when held with both hands.</text>
<text id="212000">Weapon type: Straight Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

The hilt of this lost sword was found
discarded in the Undead Asylum.

Only slightly better than one's bare hands,
and not recommended for extensive use.
Be certain to find a replacement quickly.</text>
<text id="300000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

This standard greatsword is normally wielded
with two hands due to its great weight.

Usually swung in large arcs and effective
against multiple foes. Far from ideal when
fighting in tight quarters.</text>
<text id="301000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

This larger type of greatsword is normally
wielded with two hands due to its weight.

This highly flexible greatsword can be used
to attack in swings or thrusts.</text>
<text id="302000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

This single-bladed blood-stained greatsword
is the choice weapon of the slithering 
serpent men of Sen's Fortress.

An ordinary human will have great difficulty
swinging this heavy beast effectively.</text>
<text id="303000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Slash

This greatsword with an undulating blade is
the choice weapon of the slithering serpent
men of Sen's Fortress.

This weapon is designed to flay the skin and
causes heavy bleeding.</text>
<text id="304000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

A fully crystallized greatsword.
How such a weapon was created
is entirely unknown.
The crystallization boosts its attack, but
makes the blade brittle. The sword cannot be
used for long, as it cannot be repaired.</text>
<text id="306000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

The stone knights who guard the Darkroot
Garden wield this moss-covered greatsword.

The same magic which created the stone
knights is imbued in the sword. Unleash this
power by wielding the sword with two hands.</text>
<text id="307000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Sword born from the soul of the great grey
wolf Sif, guardian of the grave of the
Abysswalker Knight Artorias.

Sir Artorias hunted the Darkwraiths, and his
sword strikes harder against dark servants.</text>
<text id="308000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

Greatsword born from the soul of Gwyn,
Lord of Cinder. As bearer of the ultimate
soul, Gwyn wielded the bolts of the sun,
but before linking the fire, divided that
power amongst his children, and set off with
only this greatsword as his companion.</text>
<text id="309000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons,
came from the tail of Seath the Scaleless,
the pale white dragon who betrayed his own.
Seath is the grandfather of sorcery, and this
sword is imbued with his magic, which shall
be unleashed as a wave of moonlight.</text>
<text id="310000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Greatsword of the black knights who wander
Lordran. Used to face chaos demons.

The large motion that puts the weight of the
body into the attack reflects the great size
of their adversaries long ago.</text>
<text id="311000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Sword born from the soul of the great grey
wolf Sif, guardian of the grave of the
Abysswalker Knight Artorias.
The sword can damage ghosts, as it was
cursed when Artorias joined a covenant
with the creatures of the Abyss.</text>
<text id="350000">Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

One of the gigantic straight greatswords.

As the name suggests, the Zweihander is held
with two hands, but its wielder must still be
inhumanly strong. It is this great weight
that sends foes flying when hit solidly.</text>
<text id="351000">Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

One of the gigantic straight greatswords.

Very few have what it takes to wield this
incredibly heavy, damage-dealing monster.
A favorite of the Knights Berenike, known for
their heavy armor, and Black Iron Tarkus.</text>
<text id="352000">Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

The lesser Capra demons use these greatswords
in pairs. The blade is cast iron and hooked.

The sword is imbued with no particular magic,
but for those who have the strength, its
great weight will smash foes mercilessly.</text>
<text id="354000">Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons,
came from the tail of the stone dragon of
Ash Lake, descendant of the ancient dragons.

Its great mystical power will be unleashed
when wielded with two hands.</text>
<text id="355000">Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Greatsword of the black knights who wander
Lordran. Used to face chaos demons.

The large motion that puts the weight of the
body into the attack reflects the great size
of their adversaries long ago.</text>
<text id="400000">Weapon type: Curved Sword
Attack type: Slash

Small curved sword. Each hit inflicts little
damage, but fluid chain attacks are deadly.

The scimitar's sharp slashing attacks are
effective against cloth and flesh, but not
against metal armor or tough scales.</text>
<text id="401000">Weapon type: Curved Sword
Attack type: Slash

Small curved sword. Each hit inflicts little
damage, but fluid chain attacks are deadly.

The falchion's sharp slashing attacks are
effective against cloth and flesh, but not
against metal armor or tough scales.</text>
<text id="402000">Weapon type: Curved Sword
Attack type: Slash

Curved sword with sharply curved blade.

Created by Arstor, Earl of Carim.
Requires great skill to wield, but evades
shield defense to sneak in damage.</text>
<text id="403000">Weapon type: Curved Sword
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

Jagged blade wielded by New Londo ghosts.
Violent thrust attack.

One of the cursed weapons.
Inflicts damage to ghosts.</text>
<text id="405000">Weapon type: Curved Sword
Attack type: Slash

Curved sword of Anor Londo painting guards.
Unique shape with flat tip.
The guardians, who strike down those who
dare threaten the paintings, attack in a
continuous, circular dancing motion,
a technique passed down through generations.</text>
<text id="406000">Weapon type: Curved Sword
Attack type: Slash

A curved sword born from the soul of
Quelaag, daughter of the Witch of Izalith,
who was transformed into a chaos demon.
Like Quelaag's body, the sword features
shells, spikes, and a coating of chaos fire.
Power affected by wielder's humanity.</text>
<text id="450000">Weapon type: Curved Greatsword
Attack type: Slash

A curved greatsword used in a
mysterious ancient rite.

Imbued with a frightful occult energy
which restores HP with each hit.</text>
<text id="451000">Weapon type: Curved Greatsword
Attack type: Slash

Giant curved sword forged using special
methods in an Eastern land.
This unparalleled weapon cuts like a Katana
but is heavier than a Nata machete.
Requires extreme strength, dexterity,
and stamina to wield.</text>
<text id="453000">Weapon type: Curved Greatsword
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

Sword wielded only by servants of
Gravelord Nito, the first of the dead.
Crafted from the bones of the fallen.

The miasma of death exudes from the sword,
a veritable toxin to any living being.</text>
<text id="500000">Weapon type: Katana
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

Katana forged in an Eastern land.
Known for its brisk slashing motions.

The Uchigatana cuts beautifully and causes
bleeding, but its blade is easily nicked.</text>
<text id="501000">Weapon type: Katana
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

Katana forged in an Eastern land.
Very unusual specimen with a long blade.

The blade is extremely long,
but as a result, quite easily broken.</text>
<text id="502000">Weapon type: Katana
Attack type: Slash

Katana forged in an Eastern land.
The Katana is drawn from the scabbard at
lightning speed, using an Iaijutsu technique.

Iaijutsu allows the wielder to charge
forward to swiftly cut down distant foes.</text>
<text id="503000">Weapon type: Katana
Attack type: Slash

A curved sword born from the soul of
Quelaag, daughter of the Witch of Izalith,
who was transformed into a chaos demon.
This blade inherits only the chaotic nature
of Quelaag, and has a unique speckled design.
Blade wielder erodes along with opponents.</text>


<text id="600000">Weapon type: Thrusting Sword
Attack type: Thrust

Standard small thrusting sword.
Unsharpened but pointed solid
shaft can pierce tough armor.

Can be thrust using the weight of one's body,
and is very effective for critical attacks.</text>
<text id="601000">Weapon type: Thrusting Sword
Attack type: Thrust

Standard thrusting sword. Regular one-handed
attack can be delivered with shield held up.
Can parry with use of left hand.

Thrusting attacks pierce and are effective
against foes with hard exteriors, but the
wielder is left open to damage after a swing.</text>
<text id="602000">Weapon type: Thrusting Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

The largest of the thrusting swords.
Can pierce an armored knight in one thrust.

The blade is also sharp,
allowing slicing as well.</text>
<text id="603000">Weapon type: Thrusting Sword
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

A symbolic, powerful thrusting sword used
by the Pardoner serving Velka,
Goddess of Sin.
It is no mere symbol to be sure; the Pardoner
is an inhuman swordsman, and wields this
enchanted blade with special sword technique.</text>
<text id="604000">Weapon type: Thrusting Sword
Attack type: Thrust

A rapier with intricate decorations. Chosen
weapon of the infamous Undead Prince Ricard.
Ricard's exploits are told in a monomyth.
He was born into royalty, but wandered the
lands in a fateful ill-conceived journey.
He became Undead, and disappeared up North.</text>
<text id="700000">Weapon type: Axe
Attack type: Regular

Small hand axe. Appears identical to a
lumberjack's tool, but has an ideal weight
and strength, and is easy to handle.
One wrong swing leaves the wielder wide
open, so timing and proximity to the enemy
must be judged carefully.</text>
<text id="701000">Weapon type: Axe
Attack type: Regular

Standard battle axe. Inflicts regular damage,
making it effective in various situations.
Powerful attack due to its weight, but one
wrong swing leaves the wielder wide open,
so timing and proximity to the enemy must
be judged carefully.</text>
<text id="702000">Weapon type: Axe
Attack type: Regular

Well-used old bronze battle axe with a
long hilt and a crescent-shaped blade.

One of the blessed weapons of the Way of
White. The Crescent Axe is bequeathed to
cleric warriors who have proven their faith.</text>
<text id="703000">Weapon type: Axe
Attack type: Regular

Giant butcher knife wielded by the Undead
man-eating cook lurking in the Depths.
More a tool for subduing and preparing live
catches than an actual weapon. Those who
have faced this deadly blade have a deeper
sense of how helpless prey must feel.</text>
<text id="704000">Weapon type: Axe
Attack type: Regular

An axe born from the soul of the Iron Golem,
guardian of Sen's Fortress who repelled
countless heroes who sought Anor Londo.
Its powerful one-handed attack imitates the
golem's blade of wind, but the heavy iron
blade makes it quite unwieldy.</text>
<text id="705000">Weapon type: Axe
Attack type: Regular

Sliced tail of the gargoyle guarding the
Bell of Awakening in the Undead Church
or patrolling in Anor Londo.

Can be used as a bronze battle axe.
Bends dramatically during large attacks,
owing to its nature as a tail.</text>
<text id="750000">Weapon type: Greataxe
Attack type: Regular

This greataxe is a veritable mass of iron.
Its weight sends foes flying, but makes it
difficult to handle without inhuman strength.

Any miss makes one very vulnerable, as each
swing requires the full force of the body.</text>
<text id="751000">Weapon type: Greataxe
Attack type: Regular

Carved from the bones of fellow demons.
Wielded by the lesser Taurus demons.

This axe is imbued with no special power,
but can merrily beat foes to a pulp,
providing you have the strength to wield it.</text>
<text id="752000">Weapon type: Greataxe
Attack type: Regular

This axe, one of the rare dragon weapons,
is formed by the tail of the Gaping Dragon,
a distant, deformed descendant of the
everlasting dragons.
The axe is imbued with a mystical power,
to be released when held with both hands.</text>
<text id="753000">Weapon type: Greataxe
Attack type: Regular

Greataxe of the black knights who wander
Lordran. Used to face chaos demons.

The large motion that puts the weight of the
body into the attack reflects the great size
of their adversaries long ago.</text>
<text id="800000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Strike

A simple wooden club.
This simple bladeless strike weapon is
effective against most foes, is easily
handled, and can break the guard of a shield.
However, a single miss makes one wide open,
so timing and proximities are crucial.</text>
<text id="801000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Iron hammer with a protrusive pommel.
Standard weapon for clerics.
This simple bladeless strike weapon is
effective against most foes, and can
break the guard of a shield. However,
one miss leaves one wide open.</text>
<text id="802000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Thrust

Hammer with a sharp spike on its pommel.
One of the more barbaric cleric weapons.

Uniquely, this hammer inflicts thrust damage,
and causes bleeding.</text>
<text id="803000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Thrust

Hammer with a large beak-shaped pommel.
Originally a pickaxe; redesigned for battle.

This simple but deadly weapon hits heavily
with thrust damage, such that it easily
cracks metal armor.</text>
<text id="804000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Thrust

Traditionally a mining tool, but the hard
cone on the pommel is effective in battle.

A downward swing of the Pickaxe can crush
stone; a human head would be an afterthought.</text>
<text id="809000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Strike

A club with leather nailed to the pommel.
The burg Undead merchant proudly peddles
this club, but its reinforcement is shoddy.
Indeed, its attack is stronger, but the
club is no longer dependably sturdy.</text>
<text id="810000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Metal hammer of Andre of Astora,
blacksmith at the Old Church.

Can be used as a strike weapon, but better
left in the hands of its talented owner.</text>
<text id="811000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Wooden hammer of the giant blacksmith in
Anor Londo who handles lightning weapons.

The giant blacksmith forges with this wooden
hammer, as it would be hazardous to handle
lightning weapons with metals.</text>
<text id="812000">Weapon type: Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Metal hammer of Vamos, a skeleton blacksmith
deep within the Catacombs who rarely speaks.

Can be used as a strike weapon, but better
left in the hands of its talented owner.</text>
<text id="850000">Weapon type: Great Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Giant tree branch serves as a wooden club.
Smashes enemies from upside the head.

The leaping attack is a trademark of clubs,
and this giant club is no exception.</text>
<text id="851000">Weapon type: Great Hammer
Attack type: Strike

A legendary weapon of the Way of White,
granted to an Undead paladin long ago.

This mass of iron can only be lifted by those
with inhuman strength, but it is blessed,
and very effective against agents of Dark.</text>
<text id="852000">Weapon type: Great Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Demon weapon built from the stone archtrees.
Used by lesser demons at North Undead Asylum.

This hammer is imbued with no special power,
but can merrily beat foes to a pulp,
providing you have the strength to wield it.</text>
<text id="854000">Weapon type: Great Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Created from an everlasting dragon tooth.
Legendary great hammer of Havel the Rock.

The dragon tooth will never break as it is
harder than stone, and it grants its wielder
resistance to magic and flame.</text>
<text id="855000">Weapon type: Great Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Large wooden club.

The giant Undead of Blighttown wield these
clubs, which became poisonous from the
influence of their surroundings.</text>
<text id="856000">Weapon type: Great Hammer
Attack type: Strike

Great hammer from the soul of executioner
Smough, who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of Anor Londo.
Smough loved his work, and ground the bones
of his victims into his own feed, ruining his
hopes of being ranked with the Four Knights.</text>
<text id="901000">Weapon type: Fists
Attack type: Strike

The weapon augments one's bare hands
with thick, studded leather.

The Caestus has a short reach, but quick
cool down. Amount of damage inflicted is
dependent on its wearer's strength.</text>
<text id="902000">Weapon type: Fists
Attack type: Slash

A weapon formed by three sharp claws.

Attacks cause bleeding, and the wounds
inflicted are not easily mended. Preferred
weapon of the spooks of an Eastern land.</text>
<text id="903000">Weapon type: Fists
Attack type: Strike

A weapon from the soul of the Iron Golem,
guardian of Sen's Fortress who repelled
countless heroes who sought Anor Londo.
The Gods fused the power of the soul with
the great bones of the dragons, forming an
appropriate core for the giant golem.</text>
<text id="904000">Weapon type: Fists
Attack type: Strike

The Darkwraiths, incited by Kaathe, use the
power of the dark soul to absorb humanity, an
art shared by this weapon, which also acts as
a special shield. The ancients, particularly,
could sap the humanity of even a replete
saint in the blink of an eye.</text>
<text id="1000000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

Standard spear used commonly by soldiers.
Long reach, and can be used with shield up.
Effective against hard exteriors, and can hit
for high damage at the right moment of an
enemy's swing. But the hit radius is small,
and it is easily blocked by shields.</text>
<text id="1001000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

A long-hilted spear with a barbed point.
Long reach, and can be used with shield up.
Effective against hard exteriors, and hits
for high damage at the right moment of an
enemy's swing. But the hit radius is small,
and it is easily blocked by shields.</text>
<text id="1002000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Spear with blade attached to broad point.
Boasts long reach, and can slice.

The wide range of this spear makes it
adaptable to many situations. Its strength
lies in its length, but in cramped quarters,
this backfires, and slices ricochet off walls.</text>
<text id="1003000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

Carved from the bones of fellow demons.
Wielded by the slim lesser Batwing demons.

The weapon of these chaos demons wandering
Anor Londo are different from those of other
chaos demons, and are imbued with lightning.</text>
<text id="1004000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

Trident of the Six-eyed Channelers,
sorcerers who serve Seath the Scaleless
in collecting human specimens.
Thrusted in circular motions in a unique
martial arts dance that stirs nearby allies
into a bloodthirsty frenzy.</text>
<text id="1006000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

The silver knights of Anor Londo guard the
city using this beautifully slender weapon.

The spear can be wielded by both hands in a
focused thrust that uses one's body weight,
or swung in a large sweeping motion.</text>
<text id="1050000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

Long spear with a very long red hilt.
Traditionally used by groups of soldiers.
Specially designed for distance thrusting.
Has the longest range of the non-projectile
weapons, but its very length makes it
somewhat difficult to handle.</text>
<text id="1051000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

Cross spear born from the soul of Ornstein, a
Dragonslayer guarding Anor Londo cathedral.
Inflicts lightning damage; effective against
dragons. Two-handed thrust relies on cross
and buries spear deep within a dragon's hide,
and sends human foes flying.</text>
<text id="1052000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

Weapon born from the mystical creature of
the Darkroot Garden, the Moonlight Butterfly.

The horns of the butterfly, a being created
by Seath, are imbued with a pure magic power.</text>
<text id="1100000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Long-hilted weapon mixing spear and axe is
difficult to handle, requiring both strength
and dexterity. The Halberd has two elementary
attacks: spear-like thrusting and large
sweeping swings. However, one false swing
and the wielder is left wide open.</text>
<text id="1101000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Regular/Thrust

Large halberd made of old brass, used by
the giant sentinels of Anor Londo.

Brass contains traces of lightning,
but as the halberd is designed for the giant
sentinels, its weight is unbearable.</text>
<text id="1102000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Regular

Weapon of the titanite demon, a faceless
stone monster born from titanite slab.
One of the enchanted weapons, perhaps from
residual power of the titanite slab.
Known for its leaping attack which comes
smashing down on foes from above.</text>
<text id="1103000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Regular

Halberd of the gargoyle guarding the
Bell of Awakening in the Undead Church.

Perfectly standard bronze halberd
without any special power.</text>
<text id="1105000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Slash

Halberd of the black knights who wander
Lordran. Used to face chaos demons.

The large motion that puts the weight of the
body into the attack reflects the great size
of their adversaries long ago.</text>
<text id="1106000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Thrust

Halberd with a large, hard beak-like
protrusion. Inflicts thrust damage.
Instead of thrusting like a spear, the
wielder of the Lucerne aims to club
the head with its hard beak.</text>
<text id="1107000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Slash

Halberd with a large blade.
Scythe adjusted for battle.

Designed especially for slicing. However,
one false swing leaves one wide open.</text>
<text id="1150000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Slash

Weapon with a long curved blade. Converted
from a wheat-harvesting tool.

The magnificent sharp curved blade
instills fear in opponents. Perhaps it is
their survival instinct at work.</text>
<text id="1151000">Weapon type: Halberd
Attack type: Slash

Scythe born from the soul of Priscilla, the
stark white crossbreed trapped inside the
Painted World of Ariamis.
Even the Gods feared Priscilla's lifehunt
ability, and in the hands of a mortal, its
power will turn upon its wielder.</text>
<text id="1200000">Weapon type: Bow
Attack type: none

Small bow. Standard projectile weapon.
Equip arrows to use.

Hold bow to aim.
Aim for heads of humanoid foes.
May change type of arrows.</text>
<text id="1201000">Weapon type: Bow
Attack type: none

Large bow. Projectile weapon for experienced
hunters. Equip arrows to use.

Hold bow to aim.
Aim for heads of humanoid foes.
May change type of arrows.</text>
<text id="1202000">Weapon type: Bow
Attack type: none

The preferred black bow of the heroic
archer Pharis.

Has a longer range than standard bows,
but is more difficult to use. Without proper
abilities, results will be underwhelming.</text>
<text id="1203000">Weapon type: Greatbow
Attack type: none

Bow of the Dragonslayers, led by Hawkeye
Gough, one of Gwyn's Four Knights.

This bow's unusual size requires that it be
anchored to the ground when fired.
Only uses specialized great arrows.</text>
<text id="1204000">Weapon type: Bow
Attack type: none

Composite bow emphasizing power.
Requires more strength than standard bows.

However, its range is shorter, making it
unfit for sniping.</text>
<text id="1205000">Weapon type: Bow
Attack type: none

Bow born from the soul of the Dark Sun
Gwyndolin, Darkmoon deity who watches over
the abandoned city of Gods, Anor Londo.

This golden bow is imbued with powerful magic
and is most impressive with Moonlight Arrows.</text>
<text id="1250000">Weapon type: Crossbow
Attack type: none

Standard crossbow issued to soldiers.
While bows require both hands, a crossbow is
held in one, but arming each bolt takes time.

Equip bolts to use.
May change type of bolt.</text>
<text id="1251000">Weapon type: Crossbow
Attack type: none

Powerful large crossbow.
While bows require both hands, a crossbow is
held in one, but arming each bolt takes time.

Equip bolts to use.
May change type of bolt.</text>
<text id="1252000">Weapon type: Crossbow
Attack type: none

Repeating crossbow cherished by the weapon
craftsman Eidas. Its elaborate design makes
it closer to a work of art than a weapon.
Intricate mechanism makes heavy damage
possible through triple-shot firing of bolts,
but in fact each bolt inflicts less damage.</text>
<text id="1253000">Weapon type: Crossbow
Attack type: none

Large crossbow with long distance used by
Carim snipers. Often used with sniper bolts.

But while crossbows are normally easy to
use, the Sniper Crossbow requires dexterity.</text>
<text id="1300000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

Sorcery catalyst used by sorcerers of
Vinheim Dragon School.

Equip catalyst to use sorceries.
Attune sorceries from a scroll at a bonfire.
Most sorceries have limited no. of uses.</text>
<text id="1301000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

Catalyst belonging to Beatrice, the rogue
witch. Contrasts with Vinheim catalysts.

This ancient catalyst shows signs of being
used for age-old sorceries. It has passed
the hands of many generations to get here.</text>
<text id="1302000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Thrust

Catalyst of the banishment sorcerers who
flooded New Londo to seal off away the
Darkwraiths and the Kings who fell to Dark.
In contrast to other catalysts, the metal
catalyst qualifies as a weapon, as it
inflicts physical damage, however small.</text>
<text id="1303000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

Catalyst of Big Hat Logan, the great sorcerer
and seeker of knowledge.
Originally the same catalyst employed by the
Vinheim sorcerers, only terribly strengthened
over time due to Logan's use. Very powerful
when used by one of superior intelligence.</text>
<text id="1304000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

Catalyst born from the soul of the Dark Sun
Gwyndolin, Darkmoon deity who watches over
the abandoned city of Gods, Anor Londo.
Gwyndolin is Gwyn's lastborn and a legitimate
god, but he is also a Moon sorcerer, and this
wand is boosted by faith, not intelligence.</text>
<text id="1305000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

Sorcery catalyst of lost land of Oolacile.
Formed by enchanted whitebark branches.

The whitebark boosts sorcery adjustment,
but the sorceries of this lost land are
gentle and not affected by intelligence.</text>
<text id="1306000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Thrust

Catalyst imbued in terrifying crystal magic.
Used by Logan after his fixation on Seath.

Makes all sorceries incredibly powerful, but
demands extremely high intelligence from its
wielder, and halves sorcery usages.</text>
<text id="1307000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Thrust

Demon catalyst formed from Izalith molten
rock. Can be used as fire weapon.
The Demon Firesage was the first demon,
and the last master of the original fire
arts, before the Witch of Izalith was
engulfed by Chaos, creating pyromancy.</text>
<text id="1308000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

Catalyst of the Witch of Izalith of long ago,
when her daughters were still flame witches,
before they were engulfed by the Chaos Flame.
Before the birth of pyromancy, their wands
were mediums for sorcery, but knowledge of
this flame sorcery has long since vanished.</text>
<text id="1330000">Weapon type: Pyromancy Flame
Attack type: Strike

Flame medium used by Great Swamp pyromancers.
Pyromancers arouse this flame to produce
various fire arts.
Equip pyromancer flame to produce pyromancy.
Attune pyromancies from a scroll at bonfire.
Most pyromancies have limited no. of uses.</text>
<text id="1332000">Weapon type: Pyromancy Flame
Attack type: Strike

Pyromancy flame drawing upon the latent power
of Quelana of Izalith, mother of pyromancy.
For the pyromancer, a flame is a precious
thing indeed, to be nurtured, often for an
entire lifetime. When the flame is shared, it
creates an eternal bond between the parties.</text>
<text id="1360000">Weapon type: Talisman
Attack type: Strike

Medium for casting miracles of the Gods.
Standard talisman issued to common believers.

Equip talisman to cast miracles. 
Attune miracles from a scroll at a bonfire.
Most miracles have limited no. of uses.</text>
<text id="1361000">Weapon type: Talisman
Attack type: Strike

Medium for casting miracles of the Gods.
Canvas Talisman is for clerics on pilgrimage.

Equip talisman to cast miracles. 
Attune miracles from a scroll at a bonfire.
Most miracles have limited no. of uses.</text>
<text id="1362000">Weapon type: Talisman
Attack type: Strike

Medium for casting miracles of the Gods.
This talisman is only granted to high-
ranking Thorolund clerics. Has high
miracle adjustment which, thanks to divine
protection, is not dependent upon faith.</text>
<text id="1363000">Weapon type: Talisman
Attack type: Strike

Medium for casting miracles of the Gods.
Ivory Talismans are granted only to female
clerics, and their value is affected
dramatically by their owner's faith.</text>
<text id="1365000">Weapon type: Talisman
Attack type: Strike

Medium for casting miracles of the Gods.
The talisman of Solaire of Astora, the Knight
of Sunlight, is decorated with a holy symbol,
illustrated by Solaire himself.
This talisman is a projection of Solaire's
upstanding, unwavering faith.</text>
<text id="1366000">Weapon type: Talisman
Attack type: Strike

Medium for casting miracles of the Gods.
Granted to Darkmoon Blade knights, adherents
to the Covenant of the Dark Sun Gwyndolin.
This talisman demands dutiful faith from its
owner, but has very high miracle adjustment.</text>
<text id="1367000">Weapon type: Talisman
Attack type: Strike

Medium for casting miracles of the Gods.
This black tuft of hair that serves as a
talisman belongs to Velka, Goddess of Sin.
It casts miracles not by drawing upon
faith, but intelligence.</text>
<text id="1396000">Weapon type: Lantern
Attack type: Strike

Skull Lantern of the Catacombs necromancer.
Droops from his long beard locks.

This lantern alights the Tomb of the Giants,
Nito's light-devouring domain of death.
Also serves as a fire damage strike weapon.</text>
<text id="1400000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Wooden shield.
Decorated with the ancient symbol of
a double-headed eagle, painted yellow.

Wood shields are lighter than metal shields,
but with lower physical damage reduction,
and reduced shield stability.</text>
<text id="1401000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Vertically elongated wooden shield.
Decorated with a white dragon.

Wood shields are lighter than metal shields,
but with lower physical damage reduction,
and reduced shield stability.</text>
<text id="1402000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Large, leather-covered round shield.
Choice shield for hunters.

Wood shields are lighter than metal shields,
but with lower physical damage reduction,
and reduced shield stability.</text>
<text id="1403000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Small, leather-covered round shield,
reinforced in critical spots with metal.

Small shields are always less stable, but
landing critical hits after parry is easier.</text>
<text id="1404000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Small round metal shield.
Four protrusions used to parry attacks.

Small shields are always less stable, but
landing critical hits after parry is easier.
This shield is specialized for parrying.</text>
<text id="1405000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Very small round metal shield.
Parry attacks with large center protrusion.

Small shields are always less stable, but
landing critical hits after parry is easier.
This shield is specialized for parrying.</text>
<text id="1406000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Round wooden shield.
Cracked and nearly broken.

Wood shields are lighter than metal shields,
but this one has lower physical damage
reduction stability, partly due to cracking.</text>
<text id="1408000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Round leather-covered shield.
A standard, widely-used shield.

Small shields are always less stable, but
landing critical hits after parry is easier.</text>
<text id="1409000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Makeshift shield built from wood planks.
Provides minimal protection,
but at a cost of moderate humiliation.</text>
<text id="1410000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Round wooden shield crafted in Lordran.
Decorated by an ancient blue Caduceus.
The giant trees in Lordran are distant
offspring of the great stone archtrees.
This shield inherits their properties,
and the wood greatly reduces magic damage.</text>
<text id="1411000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Weapon born from the mystical creature of
the Darkroot Garden, the Moonlight Butterfly.
Imbued with a powerful crystal power, like
the butterfly created by Seath the Scaleless.
Can emit crystal light rings.</text>
<text id="1450000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Small metal shield.
A standard, widely-used shield.

This shield is easy to use, and is one of
the smallest shields that offers
100% physical damage reduction.</text>
<text id="1451000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

This medium metal shield is elegantly
carved and painted.
Although it is thought to have been used by
ancient knights of the nobility, its defense
capabilities are similar to other shields.</text>
<text id="1452000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Medium metal shield. Decorated with a tower,
the symbol of protection.
A standard, widely-used shield.</text>
<text id="1453000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Old medium metal shield of unknown origin.
The grass crest is lightly imbued with magic,
which slightly speeds stamina recovery.</text>
<text id="1454000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Metal shield wielded by Hollow soldiers.
Heavily rusted but sturdy, providing a
strong defense.</text>
<text id="1455000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of the knights of the ancient kingdom
of Balder. Tweaked for improved stability.
Balder was the home of Knight King Rendal,
but the kingdom was reduced to ruins after
a widespread outbreak of Undead.</text>
<text id="1456000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of a nameless knight, likely a
high-ranked knight of Astora.

One of the enchanted blue shields.
The Crest Shield greatly reduces
magic damage.</text>
<text id="1457000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of a nameless knight, likely a
high-ranked knight of Astora.

One of the enchanted blue shields.
The Dragon Crest Shield greatly reduces
fire damage.</text>
<text id="1460000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Round wooden shield crafted in Lordran.
Decorated with the ancient Labrys axe.
The giant trees in Lordran are distant
offspring of the great stone archtrees.
This shield inherits their properties, 
and the wood reduces magic damage.</text>
<text id="1461000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Thick iron shield of Shiva of the East.
Heaviest of the standard shields.
Deflects enemy attacks. A famous specimen
from Shiva's collection, but none who have
faced it have lived to tell the tale.</text>
<text id="1462000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of the savage mountain bandits.
Uniquely-shaped with a large black spider
etched upon it.
Has resistance to poison.</text>
<text id="1470000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of the infamous Darkwraith Kirk,
Knight of Thorns. Covered with spikes.

Can be used as a weapon.
Sharp spikes cause heavy bleeding.</text>
<text id="1471000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

A fully crystallized straight shield.
How such a weapon was created
is entirely unknown.
The crystallization boosts its defense, but
makes the shield brittle. The shield cannot
be used for long, as it cannot be repaired.</text>
<text id="1472000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of Solaire of Astora, Knight of
Sunlight. Decorated with a holy symbol,
but Solaire illustrated it himself, and it
has no divine powers of its own. As it turns
out, Solaire's incredible prowess is a product
of his own training, and nothing more.</text>
<text id="1473000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of the Silver Knights of Anor Londo.
A flowing canal is carved deep into its face.
The Silver Knights stayed behind in Anor
Londo to defend the illusory goddess,
and their shields are blessed with her
divine protection.</text>
<text id="1474000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Shield of the Black Knights that wander
Lordan. A flowing canal is chiseled deeply
into its face. 
Long ago, the black knights faced the chaos
demons, and were charred black, but their
shields became highly resistant to fire.</text>
<text id="1475000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Thrust

Shield of certain knights of Catarina, used
in attacks with a large protrusion in center.

Can be used as a thrust weapon.</text>
<text id="1476000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Round wooden shield crafted in Lordran
featuring an impressive red and white design.
The giant trees in Lordran are distant
offspring of the great stone archtrees.
This shield inherits their properties, and
the wood greatly reduces magic damage.</text>
<text id="1477000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Medium metal shield.
Decorated by an ancient blue Caduceus.
A standard, widely-used shield.</text>
<text id="1478000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

Bronze shield of the gargoyle guarding the
Bell of Awakening in the Undead Church.
The gargoyle's skin is tough by itself, and
perhaps its shield may have been a prop,
for it is a rare example of a metal shield
that does not reduce physical damage 100%.</text>
<text id="1500000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Greatshield with an eagle design. Lightest
and easiest greatshield to handle.

Greatshields are very stable, and deflect
attacks. But one cannot parry, and instead
bashes with the shield.</text>
<text id="1501000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Metal greatshield. Used by Knight Berenike,
known for his heavy armor. This thick plate
of iron is heavily defensive but ultra heavy.
Greatshields are very stable, and deflect
attacks. However, one cannot parry,
and instead bashes with the shield.</text>
<text id="1502000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Greatshield made of bronze and marcasite.
Used by giant sentinels of Anor Londo.
Marcasite, or white iron, is effective
against non-physical damage, but as the
shield is designed for the giant sentinels,
its weight is unbearable.</text>
<text id="1503000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Mossy round greatshield used by the guardian
of the Darkroot Garden, the Stone Knight.
The Stone Knight is a creation of ancient
magic, and this shield is imbued with the
same power, but is also extremely heavy.</text>
<text id="1505000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Greatshield of the legendary Havel the Rock.
Cut straight from a great slab of stone.
This greatshield is imbued with the magic
of Havel, provides strong defense, and is
incredibly heavy. A true divine heirloom
on par with the Dragon Tooth.</text>
<text id="1506000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Giant wooden wheel encircled by spikes.
Half-melded to a strange skeleton.

Can be used as a greatshield, only for the
great gaps. But at least the spikes turn into
weapons with a good spin. Strange indeed!</text>
<text id="1507000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Shield born from the soul of the great grey
wolf Sif, guardian of the grave of the
Abysswalker Knight Artorias.
Boasts consistent defense and divine
protection against various status effects.</text>
<text id="1600000">Weapon type: Whip
Attack type: Regular

Leather whip.
Not intended for battle.

Virtually ineffective against armor and tough
scales, but quite formidable against enemies
with exposed skin.</text>
<text id="1601000">Weapon type: Whip
Attack type: Regular

Whip with sharp spikes.

Only slightly effective against armor and
tough scales, but quite formidable against
enemies with exposed skin.
Also causes heavy bleeding.</text>
<text id="2000000">Weapon type: Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Standard arrow.
Arrows must be equipped to be fired.</text>
<text id="2001000">Weapon type: Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Large arrow.
Heavier arrows cause more damage,
but have a shorter range.</text>
<text id="2002000">Weapon type: Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Red feather arrows of the Lord's hunters.
Their long range makes them effective for
sniping.</text>
<text id="2003000">Weapon type: Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Arrows fired with flaming tips.
Inflicts fire damage.</text>
<text id="2004000">Weapon type: Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Arrow with point dipped in poison.
Ensures the demise of prey in a hunt,
or the target in an assassination.
Once an enemy is poisoned, one need
only wait.</text>
<text id="2005000">Weapon type: Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Arrow granted to those bound by
Covenant to the Dark Sun Gwyndolin,
Lord Gwyn's lastborn.
Moonlight Arrows glow silver,
and inflict magic damage.</text>
<text id="2006000">Weapon type: Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Standard arrow.
These arrows do not fly particularly far,
nor do they inflict a terrible amount of
damage, but their cheap cost makes them
useful when volume is required.</text>
<text id="2007000">Weapon type: Great Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Giant dragon-hunting arrows, resembling
iron spears. Used by Hawkeye Gough and
his Dragonslayers, they puncture human
flesh easily. Dragonslayer Arrows can only
be used with the Dragonslayer Greatbow,
and vice-versa. </text>
<text id="2008000">Weapon type: Great Arrow
Attack type: Thrust

Great arrow used by Hawkeye Gough,
one of Lord Gwyn's Four Knights,
for dragon slaying. Requires Greatbow.

Gough personally crafts each stone tip,
and wraps the shaft tightly with tree bark.</text>
<text id="2100000">Weapon type: Bolt
Attack type: Thrust

Standard crossbow bolt.
Used mainly with the Light Crossbow.

Equip crossbow with a bolt to fire.</text>
<text id="2101000">Weapon type: Bolt
Attack type: Thrust

Large bolt.
Used mainly with the Heavy Crossbow.

These weighty bolts inflict high damage,
but have reduced range.</text>
<text id="2102000">Weapon type: Bolt
Attack type: Thrust

Red feather bolts used with the Sniper
Crossbow. Their long range makes them
effective for sniping.</text>
<text id="2103000">Weapon type: Bolt
Attack type: Thrust

Basic wood bolt.

These bolts do not fly particularly far,
nor do they inflict a terrible amount of
damage, but their cheap cost makes them
useful when volume is required.</text>
<text id="2104000">Weapon type: Bolt
Attack type: Thrust

Special bolts imbued with lightning, crafted
by the giant blacksmith of Anor Londo.

The giant blacksmith has never seen a
crossbow, but remembers the specifications
of the bolts requested by ancient warriors.</text>
<text id="9000000">Weapon type: Small Shield
Attack type: Strike

Frightful occult shield. Defends against
divine weapons and lightning.

In an ill-fated plot to destroy the very
gods, the followers of the occult once
attempted to steal the power of
Gravelord Nito, the first of the dead.</text>
<text id="9001000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

A legendary weapon of the Way of White,
granted to an Undead paladin long ago.

Once blessed with the protection of a white
flame, but its power has all but faded, so
that it provides only slight HP recovery.</text>
<text id="9002000">Weapon type: Shield
Attack type: Strike

The bloodshield spoken of in the lost
legends. The red of blood is slightly
enchanted, and boosts various resistances.</text>
<text id="9003000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

Greatshield of the mighty knight Tarkus.

Built of special black iron and even heavier
than Knight Berenike's tower shield.
Especially resistant to fire attacks and
effective for shield bashing.</text>
<text id="9010000">Weapon type: Curved Sword
Attack type: Slash

Curved sword used by the Lord's Blade
Ciaran, one of Lord Gwyn's Four Knights.

Ciaran brandishes her sword in
a mesmerizing dance, etching the
darkness with dire streaks of gold.</text>
<text id="9011000">Weapon type: Dagger
Attack type: Slash/Thrust

A dark silver dagger used by the
Lord's Blade Ciaran, of Gwyn's Four Knights.

The victim is first distracted by dazzling
streaks of the Gold Tracer, then stung by
the vicious poison of this dagger.</text>
<text id="9012000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

This greatsword belonged to Lord Gwyn's
Knight Artorias, who fell to the Abyss.

Swallowed by the Dark with its master, this
sword is tainted by the Abyss, and now its
strength reflects its wielder's humanity.</text>
<text id="9014000">Weapon type: Greatshield
Attack type: Strike

The steel greatshield used by Knight Artorias,
who succumbed to the Abyss.
Artorias, deeply scarred by the Abyss, used
this to form a barrier to protect his
compatriot Sif. Although this drained the
shield, its magic defense remains high.</text>
<text id="9015000">Weapon type: Greataxe
Attack type: Regular

Greataxe borne by the stone knights
who guard the forest Sanctuary.

This greataxe, requiring inhuman strength to
wield and more fitted to manual labor than
battle, is nevertheless completely lethal.</text>
<text id="9016000">Weapon type: Spear
Attack type: Thrust

Four-pronged Plow wielded by the wooden
scarecrows, serfs of the forest Sanctuary.

The scarecrow serfs would not normally use
these four-pronged plows as weapons, but
their sharpness makes them very deadly.</text>
<text id="9017000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

A sorcery catalyst born from the soul of
Manus, Father of the Abyss.
A rough, old wooden catalyst large enough
to be used as a strike weapon.
Similar to the Tin Crystallization Catalyst,
it boosts the strength of sorceries,
but limits the number of castings.</text>
<text id="9018000">Weapon type: Catalyst
Attack type: Strike

Everyday Oolacile sorcery catalyst
formed by several enchanted branches.

Boosts sorcery adjustment, but lost land
sorceries are not offensive, and attacks
are not boosted by intelligence.</text>
<text id="9019000">Weapon type: Whip
Attack type: Regular

Sliced tail of the Sanctuary Guardian.

This flexible, spiked, and highly
poisonous tail would make a rather
obnoxious weapon.</text>
<text id="9020000">Weapon type: Greatsword
Attack type: Regular

This greatsword, one of the rare dragon
weapons, is formed by the tail of the
one-eyed black dragon Kalameet,
the last of the ancient dragons.
The mystical power of its obsidian blade
will be released when held with both hands.</text>
<text id="9021000">Weapon type: Greatbow
Attack type: none

Greatbow used by Hawkeye Gough, of Lord
Gwyn's Four Knights, for dragon slaying.

This bow is larger than even those used by
the famed Dragonslayers. Only their leader,
Gough, had the strength to handle it.</text>
</entries>