<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="37000000">Well, what do we have here? You must be a new arrival.</text>
<text id="37000001">Let me guess. Fate of the Undead, right?
Well, you're not the first.</text>
<text id="37000002">But there's no salvation here. You'd have done better to
rot in the Undead Asylum... But, too late now.</text>
<text id="37000003">Well, since you're here... Let me help you out.</text>
<text id="37000004">There are actually two Bells of Awakening.</text>
<text id="37000005">One's up above, in the Undead Church.
The other is far, far below, in the ruins at the base of Blighttown.</text>
<text id="37000006">Ring them both, and something happens...
Brilliant, right?</text>
<text id="37000007">Not much to go on,
but I have a feeling that won't stop you.</text>
<text id="37000008">So, off you go. It is why you came, isn't it?
To this accursed land of the Undead?</text>
<text id="37000009">Hah hah hah hah...</text>
<text id="37000100">Hm? What, you want to hear more?</text>
<text id="37000101">Oh, that's all we need. Another inquisitive soul.</text>
<text id="37000102">Well, listen carefully, then...</text>
<text id="37000103">One of the bells is up above in the Undead Church,
but the lift is broken.</text>
<text id="37000104">You'll have to climb the stairs up the ruins,
and access the Undead Burg through the waterway.</text>
<text id="37000105">The other bell is back down below the Undead Burg,</text>
<text id="37000106">within the plague-infested Blighttown.</text>
<text id="37000107">But I'd die again before I step foot in that cesspool!</text>
<text id="37000108">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37000200">Bloody hell, what is it now?</text>
<text id="37000201">You ask too many questions.</text>
<text id="37000300">What's wrong? Get a bit of a scare out there?</text>
<text id="37000301">No problem. Have a seat and get comfortable.</text>
<text id="37000302">We'll both be Hollow before you know it.</text>
<text id="37000303">Hah hah hah hah...</text>
<text id="37000400">Why, what a surprise. I didn't expect you to make it.</text>
<text id="37000401">...Oh, somebody rang the bell...Wait. Was it you?</text>
<text id="37000402">You never give up, do you? I don't know how you do it.</text>
<text id="37000403">Well, don't stop now. Only one more, but it's going to be suicide.</text>
<text id="37000404">Only one more now, if you have the heart for it.</text>
<text id="37000405">Hah hah hah hah...</text>
<text id="37000500">Did you see that hoity-toity cleric?
He went through the graveyard and down into the Catacombs.</text>
<text id="37000501">Clerics speak of some nonsense called Kindling,
used to feed bonfires.</text>
<text id="37000502">They're so bloody determined.
They practically queue to explore the Catacombs.</text>
<text id="37000503">Hah hah hah hah...</text>
<text id="37000600">Have you been to the ruins of New Londo below?</text>
<text id="37000601">Just head down the stairs, and take the lift.</text>
<text id="37000602">It's certainly worth a visit.</text>
<text id="37000603">It was once an Undead city. You may find a clue or two.</text>
<text id="37000604">Unless the ghosts find you first...</text>
<text id="37000605">Keh heh heh heh!</text>
<text id="37000700">How did that silly sorcerer's apprentice end up?</text>
<text id="37000701">You know,
the one always prattling on about Master Logan.</text>
<text id="37000702">He left for the Undead Burg, but never came back.</text>
<text id="37000703">Serves him right. If even Old Big Hat can't make it out there,
what chance does he have?</text>
<text id="37000704">I hope he enjoys his new life as a Hollow.</text>
<text id="37000800">How did that raggedy old chum end up?</text>
<text id="37000801">You know,
the one who idolized some godmother of pyromancy.</text>
<text id="37000802">He left for Blighttown, but never came back.</text>
<text id="37000803">Whereas most flee from sickness, he dives right in.</text>
<text id="37000804">Well, nothing will harm him once he goes Hollow.</text>
<text id="37000900">That cleric was spared?</text>
<text id="37000901">I never know what the Gods are thinking...</text>
<text id="37000902">Tsk!</text>
<text id="37001000">How did that nutty sorcerer make it back?</text>
<text id="37001001">Unexpected, but I suppose stranger things have happened.</text>
<text id="37001100">How did that old man make it back?</text>
<text id="37001101">Unexpected, but I suppose stranger things have happened.</text>
<text id="37001200">Don't you ever think to forge your weapons?</text>
<text id="37001201">Perhaps you haven't heard of Andre. Visit him
in the Old Church, in the forest behind the Undead Church.</text>
<text id="37001202">Perhaps you haven't heard of Andre.
You really need to find him.</text>
<text id="37001203">Unless you enjoy swinging about with blunt instruments!</text>
<text id="37001204">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37001300">Oh, have you seen that terribly morose lass?</text>
<text id="37001301">...The Fire Keeper.</text>
<text id="37001302">She's stuck keeping
that bonfire lit.</text>
<text id="37001303">Sad, really. She's mute and bound to this forsaken place.</text>
<text id="37001304">They probably cut her tongue out back in her village,
so that she'd never say any god's name in vain.</text>
<text id="37001305">How do these martyrs keep chugging along?
I'd peter out in an instant.</text>
<text id="37001306">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37001400">Oh, your face! You're practically Hollow.</text>
<text id="37001401">It won't be long, if you keep dying like this.
You'd best hurry and restore your humanity.</text>
<text id="37001402">But who knows, going Hollow could solve quite a bit!</text>
<text id="37001403">Hah hah hah hah...</text>
<text id="37001500">Hm, what? Restoring your humanity?</text>
<text id="37001501">Well, there are a few ways to go about it...</text>
<text id="37001502">##Collect it bit by bit from corpses,</text>
<text id="37001503">Collect it bit by bit from corpses,
or you can butter up a cleric, and get yourself summoned.</text>
<text id="37001504">And the quickest way, although I'd never do it,
is to kill a healthy Undead, and pillage its humanity. </text>
<text id="37001505">Coveting thy neighbour is only human, after all!</text>
<text id="37001506">Hah hah hah hah...</text>
<text id="37001600">What are you looking at?</text>
<text id="37001601">Don't try anything clever. You might regret it.</text>
<text id="37001700">Oi, hold on...Don't tell me, have you been cursed?</text>
<text id="37001701">Oh woe is the Undead who's cursed on top of it all!
Harsh times; harsh times, indeed!</text>
<text id="37001702">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37001703">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37001704">No, no, I'm sorry. Here, let me share a nice tip.</text>
<text id="37001705">Long ago,
I was told of a remedician who resides in New Londo.</text>
<text id="37001706">Does he really exist? Well, go and find out for yourself.</text>
<text id="37001707">But don't blame me if he's just an apparition!</text>
<text id="37001708">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37001709">Oi, did you see him?</text>
<text id="37001800">Big Hat Logan, the legendary sorcerer, in the flesh!</text>
<text id="37001801">...This place is simply mad...
Legendary heroes popping up left and right...</text>
<text id="37001802">They're making me feel quite inadequate, to be honest!</text>
<text id="37001803">Hah hah hah hah...</text>
<text id="37001900">Did you see her?</text>
<text id="37001901">That virtuous little maiden, complete with followers in tow.</text>
<text id="37001902">They're probably going straight to pillage graves.
I've heard enough about "M'Lady" for a lifetime.</text>
<text id="37001903">What absolute rubbish, eh?</text>
<text id="37001904">Tsk!</text>
<text id="37002000">Did you hear about the maiden?</text>
<text id="37002001">The virtuous lass came back alone,
and in absolute tatters...</text>
<text id="37002002">Did her followers die, or was she abandoned? Who knows.</text>
<text id="37002003">But I suppose we've heard the last from "M'lady".</text>
<text id="37002004">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37002100">That maiden?</text>
<text id="37002101">She's shuffled off somewhere. I believe to the Undead Church.</text>
<text id="37002102">These ruins were probably too awkward for her.</text>
<text id="37002200">Did you ring the second bell?</text>
<text id="37002201">That is incredible, I must say...But now we have a new problem.</text>
<text id="37002202">It's noisy, it snores, and its breath is lethal...</text>
<text id="37002203">This is no laughing matter, I tell you.</text>
<text id="37002300">Damn, that stench...And I was really beginning to like it here!</text>
<text id="37002301">Sigh...</text>
<text id="37002302">Maybe it's time I do something about it...</text>
<text id="37002400">You again?</text>
<text id="37002401">There's nothing to speak about, really.</text>
<text id="37002402">Oh, actually...Something strange did happen.</text>
<text id="37002403">That crow flew off with somebody in its clutches.
I think it was a man curled up in a ball.</text>
<text id="37002404">Stranger things have happened, right?</text>
<text id="37002405">No, maybe not...</text>
<text id="37002500">Hm? What now?</text>
<text id="37002501">I'm not up for chatting. Leave me alone.</text>
<text id="37002600">Well, what are you going to do?</text>
<text id="37002601">I've already decided.</text>
<text id="37002602">I don't really care; I'm simply crestfallen...</text>
<text id="37002700">Ooph!</text>
<text id="37002710">Oww!</text>
<text id="37002720">What in the...!</text>
<text id="37002730">Stop that! Oi!</text>
<text id="37002800">Lousy rat! You have some nerve!</text>
<text id="37002801">I may be crestfallen, but I'm not defenceless, you rascal!</text>
<text id="37002802">You will soon regret this!</text>
<text id="37002900">Heheh, not too shabby...</text>
<text id="37002901">I think you've done me a favour...</text>
<text id="37003000">Now, that's just embarrassing.</text>
<text id="37003001">How'd you let me do that to you?</text>
<text id="37003100">Don't you ever think to forge your weapons?</text>
<text id="37003101">You'd better find a smithbox soon,</text>
<text id="37003102">Unless you enjoy swinging about with blunt instruments!</text>
<text id="37003103">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text id="37003104">Don't you ever repair your weapons?</text>
<text id="37003105">You just need the right tools, or some powder.</text>
<text id="37003106">If you keep swinging those scraps around,
you'll be mistaken for a Hollow!</text>
<text id="37003107">Hah hah hah hah!</text>
</entries>