<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="28000000">Well, this is a surprise.
I don't get many visitors, except for ghosts.</text>
<text id="28000001">Do you have some business here?</text>
<text id="28000002">My name is Ingward.</text>
<text id="28000003">I'm an old man, bound to these parts.</text>
<text id="28000004">But I don't mind a chat. I may even be of some help.</text>
<text id="28000100">Well, this is a surprise.
I don't get many visitors, except ghosts.</text>
<text id="28000101">Oh, cursed, are you? Is that what brings you to me?</text>
<text id="28000102">It is a wise choice. Your troubles will soon be over.</text>
<text id="28000103">My name is Ingward.</text>
<text id="28000104">I'm an old man, bound to these parts.</text>
<text id="28000105">But cleansing your curses; that I can do.</text>
<text id="28000106">The breaking of curses is the territory of deities.
You must be prepared to give some of yourself.</text>
<text id="28000200">Hello again. How are you?</text>
<text id="28000201">Oh, hello there. How are you?</text>
<text id="28000202">I don't mind a chat. I may even be of some help.</text>
<text id="28000300">Hello, there. Where have you been? I'm glad to see you well.</text>
<text id="28000301">How can I be of assistance?</text>
<text id="28000400">Well, hello there. Have you been cursed?</text>
<text id="28000401">That can be quite onerous. But not to worry.</text>
<text id="28000402">Such cleansing, I am happy to administer.</text>
<text id="28000403">But the breaking of curses is the territory of deities.
You must be prepared for sacrifice.</text>
<text id="28000500">Hello, there. Cursed again?</text>
<text id="28000501">I do not know whether you are brave, or just foolish,
but you do seem to find your share of trouble.</text>
<text id="28000502">How do you manage to find so much trouble?</text>
<text id="28000900">Hello there. What is it?</text>
<text id="28000901">The key to the seal is now in your hands.
I will help you in any way possible.</text>
<text id="28001000">...You've broken the seal, have you?...</text>
<text id="28001001">...</text>
<text id="28001002">No, I have no regrets.
My trust lies with you, and Frampt.</text>
<text id="28001003">No, I have no regrets. For I trust in you.</text>
<text id="28001004">But you cannot proceed without being able to traverse the Abyss.</text>
<text id="28001100">According to legend,
the knight Artorias crossed the Abyss,</text>
<text id="28001101">and annihilatedthe atrocious Darkwraiths.</text>
<text id="28001102">If you can find him, and learn from him,
the Abyss may prove surmountable.</text>
<text id="28001200">...Magnificent. You defeated the Four Kings.</text>
<text id="28001201">Impressive, even for a bearer of the Lordvessel.</text>
<text id="28001202">And with this, my purpose is exhausted.</text>
<text id="28001203">I have not seen the sun for a long time.</text>
<text id="28001204">Perhaps I could do with a change...</text>
<text id="28001300">Oh, hello.</text>
<text id="28001301">The sunlight made me wince,
and now I've come back to this dark hole!</text>
<text id="28001302">So, what brings you here? I will help you in any way I can.</text>
<text id="28001400">Oh, hello.</text>
<text id="28001401">What is it? I will help you in any way that I can.</text>
<text id="28001500">Oh, hello. You've acquired the Lordvessel, have you?</text>
<text id="28001501">Very impressive.</text>
<text id="28001502">I know exactly what your intentions are.</text>
<text id="28001503">You seek the Four Kings whom I guard over.</text>
<text id="28001504">And yes, I do have the key to the seal.</text>
<text id="28001505">But before I give it up, there is something I must ask.</text>
<text id="28001506">Do you see the great hall that stands before you?</text>
<text id="28001507">Atop it, you will find a Darkwraith,
a servant of the Four Kings.</text>
<text id="28001508">Show me that you can defeat it.</text>
<text id="28001509">As guardian of the seal, it behoves me to test your strength.</text>
<text id="28001510">For if you cannot defeat the Darkwraith,
you will be no match for the Four Kings.</text>
<text id="28001511">Even if Frampt has chosen you.</text>
<text id="28001512">Even if you are the bearer of the Lordvessel.</text>
<text id="28001600">Well, this is a surprise.
I get few visitors, save for ghosts.</text>
<text id="28001601">You have...the Lordvessel.</text>
<text id="28001700">Oh, hello.</text>
<text id="28001701">What is it? I will help you in any way that I can.</text>
<text id="28001800">Hate to ask, really.</text>
<text id="28001801">But I am the Guardian of the Seal.
I have seen too many lives wasted over the eons.</text>
<text id="28001802">So, I had no choice but to test your mettle.</text>
<text id="28001900">You, you have defeated the Darkwraith!</text>
<text id="28001901">Very good, indeed. I can certainly trust you.</text>
<text id="28001902">This is the key to the seal.</text>
<text id="28001903">The Four Kings slumber in the deepest chamber of the ruins.</text>
<text id="28001904">Use this key to break the seal and open the floodgates.</text>
<text id="28001905">...Oh, and do not forget...</text>
<text id="28001906">The Darkwraiths reside in a dark void called the Abyss.</text>
<text id="28001907">But the Abyss is no place for ordinary mortals.</text>
<text id="28001908">Although long ago, the knight Artorias traversed the Abyss.</text>
<text id="28001909">If you can find him, and learn from him,
the Abyss may prove surmountable.</text>
<text id="28002000">I am the Guardian of the Seal.</text>
<text id="28002001">I watch over the Four Kings, the masters of the Darkwraiths.</text>
<text id="28002002">The Darkwraiths are the enemies of man,
and any living thing that has a soul.</text>
<text id="28002003">They were born in New Londo, and that is where they perished;
the entire city was sacrificed to contain them.</text>
<text id="28002004">...For that is how great a threat they were...</text>
<text id="28002100">New Londo was sacrificed to contain the Darkwraiths.</text>
<text id="28002101">Mark my words. The Darkwraiths are the enemies of man,
and any living thing that has a soul.</text>
<text id="28002102">They were never meant to roam again.</text>
<text id="28002200">Long ago, the Four Kings were powerful men.
Only, their hearts were weak.</text>
<text id="28002201">When an evil serpent dangled
the art of Lifedrain before them,</text>
<text id="28002202">they were unable to resist, and became pawns of evil.</text>
<text id="28002300">What! No!</text>
<text id="28002301">What are you doing!</text>
<text id="28002302">Cease!</text>
<text id="28002303">Stop that!</text>
<text id="28002304">Sigh...</text>
<text id="28002305">You are no different from the rest...</text>
<text id="28002306">So be it! I am Ingward, the guardian of the seal.</text>
<text id="28002307">Prepare to meet your doom!</text>
<text id="28002308">Ohh...ogghh...How could I allow this...</text>
<text id="28002309">Forgive me...my countrymen...</text>
</entries>