<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text>#0Talk-1st time</text>
<text id="74300000">Have you business with me?</text>
<text id="74300010">The way yonder's all blocked up you see. By this god-awful statue.</text>
<text id="74300020">Heavens above. Who thought it a good idea to put it there!</text>
<text id="74300030">Ohhhh, I'm in quite the pickle now. </text>
<text>#0Talk-2nd time</text>
<text id="74300100">See that statue? Gives me the willies.
Stare at it for long enough, it starts to look alive.</text>
<text id="74300110">Ach, It just does nae seem quite right.
There are no craftsmen round these parts.</text>
<text id="74300120">Hey, you don't think a real-life person was turned to stone, do you?</text>
<text>#0Talk-1st time, after using a Fragrant Branch of Yore to unpetrify Rosabeth</text>
<text id="74300200">What?! Clearing the way was your doing, was it?</text>
<text id="74300210">Haah, didn't think you had it in yer pal.</text>
<text id="74300220">No no no. That's not like it sounds, you know!
It was a pleasant surprise, that's all.</text>
<text id="74300230">Name's Benhart.
Thanks to you, I can resume my journey.</text>
<text id="74300240">If we share the same path, I'm sure that we are gonna meet again.</text>
<text id="74300250">I'll repay my debt to you in battle.
And I swear it by my sword.</text>
<text id="74300260">The road ahead's gonna be long, but I'm here to help.
Gah hah!</text>
<text>#0Talk-2nd time, after using a Fragrant Branch of Yore to unpetrify Rosabeth</text>
<text id="74300300">I am in yer debt.</text>
<text id="74300310">It's a true man who honours his debts. And I'll see mine paid.</text>
<text id="74300320">I swear it, by my ancient sword.</text>
<text>#0Talk-1st time</text>
<text id="74301000">Ho! Well met, friend.</text>
<text id="74301010">Good to see you well.
Yes, hehh hehh, very good indeed.</text>
<text>#0Talk-2nd time</text>
<text id="74301100">I journeyed from the distant east
to perfect my swordsmanship.</text>
<text id="74301110">Legend has it that powerful beings
slumber in this land.</text>
<text id="74301120">This sword, it's been in my family for generations.
And only a real man can wield it true.</text>
<text id="74301130">I may face any manner of man or beast,
but none shall be a match for my sword. Heh heh heh heh...</text>
<text>#0Talk-3rd time</text>
<text id="74301200">This land is a right mess, eh?</text>
<text id="74301210">King's gone, and the people have a mad glint in their eyes.</text>
<text id="74301220">The land itself is overrun by terrible beasts.</text>
<text id="74301230">No better place to test my sword, ey?
Heh heh heh heh...</text>
<text>#0Talk-1st time</text>
<text id="74302000">Well, we meet again! What you doing here?</text>
<text id="74302010">Who'dve thought we'd meet in a place like this.</text>
<text id="74302020">Fate just won't let us stay apart, will she?
Gah hah hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text>#0Talk-2nd time</text>
<text id="74302100">See the old sword's caught your attention?
Well, you've a good eye, then.</text>
<text id="74302110">Ah, it's been in my family for generations.</text>
<text id="74302120">They say it is crafted with moonlight,
and we all know what that means, it wards off evil.</text>
<text id="74302130">And I would nae trade her for all the riches in the world.</text>
<text id="74302140">They say that no man has ever
teased oot the sword's true power.</text>
<text id="74302150">But in the right hands...
Heh heh heh heh heh heh...</text>
<text>#0Talk-3rd time</text>
<text id="74302200">I see you've taken a liking to the sword.
Well, I applaud you, for you've a sharp eye.</text>
<text id="74302210">But this is one sword
pal that I will nae
be giving up.</text>
<text id="74302220">If you still insist on having it...</text>
<text id="74302230">Then you will have to pry it from my cold hands!
Gah hah hah hah hah hah!</text>
<text>#0Talk-4th time</text>
<text id="74302300">I've a great debt to you.
And I'll never forget it.</text>
<text id="74302310">I, Benhart,
swear by my honour,
to aid you in your darkest hour! So nae problem pal.</text>
<text>#0Talk-1st time</text>
<text id="74303000">Oh! Look at you! Old friend!</text>
<text id="74303010">I see yer travels weigh upon you yet.</text>
<text id="74303020">Just remember, I'm always ready to help.</text>
<text>#0Talk-2nd time</text>
<text id="74303100">My homeland is in the far east.
A kingdom of honourable fighting men.</text>
<text id="74303110">And this sword yet awaits a true man to wield it.</text>
<text id="74303120">I know how swords think, you see!
Gah hah hah hah!</text>
<text>#0Talk-Summoning him as White Phantom &amp; defeating 3 bosses without dying</text>
<text id="74307000">We have outwitted death a good many times.</text>
<text id="74307010">Huh huh, My dear friend, take these.</text>
<text>#0Upon being attacked-1st time</text>
<text id="74305030">Ooph!</text>
<text>#0Upon being attacked-2nd time</text>
<text id="74305040">Enough with that!</text>
<text>#0Upon being attacked-3rd time</text>
<text id="74305050">What in bloody...!</text>
<text>#0Upon being attacked &amp; made hostile</text>
<text id="74305000">Very well. I, Benhart,
will be honoured to chop you to pieces.</text>
<text>#0Upon approaching him, after he has previously killed the protagonist</text>
<text id="74305010">You're a sorry waste of life...</text>
<text>#0Upon killing the protagonist</text>
<text id="74305020">You knew this would happen...</text>
<text>#0After reducing his health to 50% or lower</text>
<text id="74305060">Hey! How dare you!</text>
<text>#0Upon dying</text>
<text id="74305070">What's done...urgh... Is done...</text>
<text id="74306000">##A man's journey...is never done...</text>
</entries>