<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="76000000">(Near Tower of Prayer) We knew you were coming...</text>
<text id="76000010">(Near Tower of Prayer) And stopped singing...</text>
<text id="76000100">(Near Tower of Prayer) We are Milfanito.</text>
<text id="76000110">(Near Tower of Prayer) We are here to sing to those bound
by death and Dark.</text>
<text id="76000200">(Near Tower of Prayer) We will sing here, forever,
as we always have, from long, long ago.</text>
<text id="76000210">(Near Tower of Prayer) We know nothing of the world outside.</text>
<text id="76000220">(Near Tower of Prayer) And why should we?
For we will never leave.</text>
<text id="76000300">(Near Tower of Prayer) Do you seek King Vendrick?</text>
<text id="76000310">(Near Tower of Prayer) But what is a king, after all?</text>
<text id="76000320">(Near Tower of Prayer) We know nothing of the world outside.</text>
<text id="76000330">(Near Tower of Prayer) For we will never leave here.</text>
<text id="76000400">(Near Tower of Prayer) When we sing, the little ones dance.</text>
<text id="76000410">(Near Tower of Prayer) The little ones
grant comfort to those
who bear death and Dark.</text>
<text id="76000420">(Near Tower of Prayer) This is what we were taught.</text>
<text id="76000500">(Near Tower of Prayer) Is there anything wrong?</text>
<text id="76000510">(Near Tower of Prayer) Perhaps this will help.</text>
<text id="76000520">(Near Tower of Prayer) This is all that we can do.</text>
<text id="76000600">(Near Tower of Prayer) We hear a song in the distance.</text>
<text id="76000610">(Near Tower of Prayer) You rescued a Milfanito
who was taken from us.</text>
<text id="76000620">(Near Tower of Prayer) Take this... We Milfanito thank you.</text>
<text id="76005000">(Near Tower of Prayer) What did we ever do...</text>
<text id="76005010">(Near Tower of Prayer) Are you never satisfied...
Aren't you ever satisfied...</text>
<text id="76005030">(Near Tower of Prayer) Oh!</text>
<text id="76005040">(Near Tower of Prayer) Ah!</text>
<text id="76005050">(Near Tower of Prayer) What...</text>
<text id="76006000">##(Near Tower of Prayer) All we can do...is sing...</text>
<text id="76007000">(Near Tower of Prayer) You quelled that cursed singing.</text>
<text id="76007010">(Near Tower of Prayer) They may be of no use outside,
but please take these.</text>
<text id="76010500">(Near Tower of Prayer) We hear a song in the distance.</text>
<text id="76010510">(Near Tower of Prayer) You rescued a Milfanito
who was taken from us.</text>
<text id="76010520">(Near Tower of Prayer) Take this... We Milfanito thank you.</text>
<text id="76010000">(Near Rise of the Dead) Who are you...</text>
<text id="76010010">(Near Rise of the Dead) And what do you want from us?</text>
<text id="76010100">(Near Rise of the Dead) Milfanito, that is what we are called.</text>
<text id="76010110">(Near Rise of the Dead) My name?</text>
<text id="76010120">(Near Rise of the Dead) Do you mean our name?</text>
<text id="76010130">(Near Rise of the Dead) We know nothing of the outside world...</text>
<text id="76010200">(Near Rise of the Dead) We sing eternally for those who
bear death and Dark within themselves.</text>
<text id="76010210">(Near Rise of the Dead) We have been here forever.</text>
<text id="76010220">(Near Rise of the Dead) We know nothing of the outside world,
and we do not need to.</text>
<text id="76010300">(Near Rise of the Dead) The little ones were born
from the Great Dead One.</text>
<text id="76010310">(Near Rise of the Dead) And the Great Dead One
taught us song.</text>
<text id="76010320">(Near Rise of the Dead) We have sung ever since.
To comfort those bound by death and Dark.</text>
<text id="76010330">(Near Rise of the Dead) This is what we were taught.</text>
<text id="76010400">(Near Rise of the Dead) Do you seek comfort, too?</text>
<text id="76010410">(Near Rise of the Dead) You poor thing...</text>
<text id="76010420">(Near Rise of the Dead) Take this, at the very least.</text>
<text id="76010430">(Near Rise of the Dead) This is all that we can do.</text>
<text id="76015000">(Near Rise of the Dead) What...will you do to us?</text>
<text id="76015010">(Near Rise of the Dead) Why are you here?</text>
<text id="76015030">(Near Rise of the Dead) Oh!</text>
<text id="76015040">(Near Rise of the Dead) Ah!</text>
<text id="76015050">(Near Rise of the Dead) We never...</text>
<text id="76016000">##(Near Rise of the Dead) We exist...to sing...</text>
<text id="76017000">(Near Rise of the Dead) You silenced that cursed singing.</text>
<text id="76017010">(Near Rise of the Dead) Please accept these as a thank-you.</text>
<text id="76020200">(Castle) Ah...Ahh...</text>
<text id="76020300">(Castle) Ahh...Ah...</text>
<text id="76025000">(Castle) Ahh...Ahhh...</text>
<text id="76025030">(Castle) Oh!</text>
<text id="76025040">(Castle) Ah...Ahh...</text>
<text id="76025050">(Castle) Ah...Ah...</text>
</entries>