<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="100">Online play item.
Create a co-op summon sign.

Be summoned to another world
as a phantom through your sign,
and defeat the area boss to
gain the strength of flame.

The nature of Lothric is murky, unclear.
The White Sign Soapstone allows
Unkindled to assist one another.</text>
<text id="101">Online play item.
Create a hostile red invasion sign.

Be summoned to another world
as a dark spirit,
and defeat the Host of Embers to
gain the strength of fire.

Not all dark spirits are unsporting,
or they wouldn't make use of this soapstone.</text>
<text id="102">Online play item.
Invade other worlds at will.

Defeat the Host of Embers of the world you have 
invaded to gain the strength of fire.

The Red Eye Orb is rooted in a tiny land
swallowed by darkness long ago.
Some choose to put the orb to other uses.
To embark on this path,
enter the service of Rosaria in the Cathedral of the Deep.</text>
<text id="103">A charm of farewell granted to banished Undead.
The crystal sends phantoms back to their homes,
or you back to yours.

Beware of fickle use of this item
if you intend to nurture relations.</text>
<text id="108">Online play item.
A roster of knights of the Darkmoon
who have served since the age of the old Royals.

Use to discover the names of Darkmoon Knights,
an order of elite knights shrouded in shadows.</text>
<text id="111">Online play item.
Allows a single invasion of another world.

Defeat the Host of Embers of the world you have
invaded to gain the strength of fire.

The Cracked Red Orb is far from perfect, it seems,
as Ringfinger Leonhard knows all too well.</text>
<text id="115">Arcane orb left on Rosaria's corpse.

Have faith her soul can be retrieved,
by invading the world of her killer,
and returning victorious.

The Black Eye is proof of vengeance,
but often appears serene as it
casts its gaze toward Irithyll.</text>
<text id="117">The Darksign is the sign of an accursed Undead.

The Darksign returns its bearer
to the last bonfire rested at,
or the bonfire at Firelink Shrine,
but at the cost of all souls held.

Carriers of the Darksign are reborn after death,
and eventually lose their minds, turning Hollow.
And so it is they are driven from their homelands.</text>
<text id="119">Online play item.
Restore the connection to other worlds.

Those who engage in unjust deeds when in contact
with other worlds will lose their connection to them.

Way of White Circlets assume such sin as their own,
but are found few and far between.
Acting without honor will never be without risk. </text>
<text id="150">The Undead treasure these dull green flasks.

Fill with Estus at bonfires, and drink to restore HP.

The journey of an Undead has always traced the bonfires,
and no journey of import has been made
without an Estus Flask.</text>
<text id="190">Undead treasure these dull ashen flasks.

Fill with Estus at bonfires, and drink to restore FP.

Quite befitting of an Unkindled,
an Ashen Estus Flask turns a bonfire's heat cold.</text>
<text id="240">Holy water blessed by the Queen of Lothric.

Fully restores HP and cures ailments.

The Queen of Lothric,
married to the former King Oceiros,
was initially revered as a goddess
of fertility and bounty.
After giving birth to Ocelotte, her youngest,
she quietly disappeared.</text>
<text id="241">Holy water blessed by the Queen of Lothric.

Fully restores FP.

There is a grave in Lothric that sees no visitors,
a dark place where rootless warriors rest.
The Queen of Lothric alone cared
to wish the poor souls good fortune.</text>
<text id="260">Green weed, shaped like a flower.
Temporary boost to stamina recovery speed.

The Undead Legion of Farron are remembered
for using this annual plant,
normally found near clear water,
to swing their mighty swords with abandon.</text>
<text id="261">Green flower-shaped weed with small white blooms.

Large temporary boost to stamina recovery speed.

Flowers of the Green Blossom are ethereal,
blossoming only on the surface of chilled,
but not frozen, water.</text>
<text id="262">Green flower-shaped weed with small white blooms.

Large temporary boost to stamina recovery speed.

The brief attached messages suggests that it was a gift:

"Good-bye, dear Grandmother.
I will visit Grandfather, in the Pit of Hollows."</text>
<text id="270">Red moss clump used as maggot repellent.

Reduces bleeding build-up.

Bleeding builds up when attacked
by sharp blades or spikes,
and once triggered causes severe damage.
Use this moss clump before it reaches that point.</text>
<text id="271">Medicinal purple moss clump.
Reduces poison build-up. Cures poison.

Poison builds up in the body,
and when it breaks out,
it causes gradual damage over a period of time.

Poison can be exasperating,
so be sure to carry sufficient moss clumps
when traveling to a blighted area.</text>
<text id="272">Potently medicinal moss clump with a flower.
Reduces poison and toxin. Cures ailments.

A toxin is a more vicious form of poison
which quickly leads to death.

Moss clumps without blooms
are useless against toxin,
and those who neglect to carry this flowered
variety are simply courting an early demise.</text>
<text id="274">Ash-colored stone encasing a skull.

Reduces undead curse build-up and cures hollowing.

Inhabitants of Londor, the land of Hollows,
use this secret treasure to feign normalcy.

Occasionally, a Hollow fools even himself,
and turns on his own kind.</text>
<text id="276">Moss clump radiating gentle heat and light.
Reduces frost build-up. Cures frostbite status.

Frost accumulates in the body causing frostbite,
which saps one's health, lowers absorption,
and slows stamina recovery.

Weapons imbued with frost are a rare thing indeed,
most of them originating in the Boreal Valley.</text>
<text id="280">Lightly enchanted golden powder.

Repairs equipped weapons and armor,
as long as they haven't already broken.

Use of a weapon depletes its durability,
eventually causing it to break.

As long as a weapon is not broken,
its durability can be restored at a bonfire,
but for distant journeys,
one may wish to prepare ahead.</text>
<text id="290">Small throwing machete.
Throw at enemies to cause bleeding damage.

A unique weapon originally
used by swordsmen of Carthus,
but now popular among bandits and thieves.</text>
<text id="292">Bisque urn filled with black powder.
Explodes, inflicting fire damage.

Fire damage, which differs from physical damage,
is highly effective against creatures of
flesh, beasts, and other foes that might
naturally have cause to fear the flame.</text>
<text id="293">Dried fecal waste material, moist on the inside.

Throw at enemy to inflict toxin build-up,
but also ups your own toxicity.

Though the stench makes it difficult to
carry on one's person,
inflicting toxins on an enemy yields
high damage over time.
Perhaps some Undead have fond memories of waste.
Or, perhaps not.</text>
<text id="294">A skull resplendent in the scent of souls.
Prepared by evangelists of the Cathedral of the Deep.

Throw to shatter, spreading souls which attract enemies.
Not effective for all foes.</text>
<text id="296">Tool used to hunt down the Undead.
Blocks Estus recovery within a limited area.

Used long ago by Lloyd's cleric knights
on their Undead hunts.
Although Allfather Lloyd is long forgotten
by the Way of White, his hunts have lived on,
and this charm allows one to challenge Undead
without fear of tenacious healing.</text>
<text id="297">More powerful bisque urn
filled with special black powder.
Explodes, inflicting great fire damage.

Fire damage, which differs from physical damage,
is highly effective against creatures of
flesh, beasts, and other foes that might naturally
have cause to fear the flame.</text>
<text id="299">Bisque urn attached to a string and
filled with black powder.
Thrown behind and explodes, inflicting fire damage.

No different to a firebomb,
save for the direction in which it is thrown.
Enables a different fighting style,
and flexibility in adjusting to one's circumstances.</text>
<text id="300">Dragon-hunting tool used by Lothric knights.
Explodes upon contact, inflicting lightning damage.

The knights of Lothric have since tamed dragons,
but were once hunters of dragons themselves.

This explains their special hunting gear,
and why they worshipped the sun.</text>
<text id="302">Black bisque urn attached to a string and
filled with black powder.
Thrown behind and explodes, inflicting fire damage.

No different to a black firebomb,
save for the direction in which it is thrown.
Enables a different fighting style,
and flexibility in adjusting to one's circumstances.</text>
<text id="303">Dried fecal waste material,
marked by a long plant stalk that was not properly digested.

Throw behind at enemies to inflict toxin build-up,
but also ups your own toxicity.

Strictly speaking,
this consists of different material than the dung pie,
but waste is waste, no sense in splitting hairs.</text>
<text id="304">Tool used in duels of judgment.
Nulls effects of special area effects for a short time.

Allfather Lloyd's knights lived
in fear of his duels of judgment,
in which verdicts were carried out by his Sword of Law.</text>
<text id="310">Small throwing knife. Throw at enemies to inflict damage.

Most items choose their wielder,
and only experience can improve their effectiveness.
True strength can be gained in no other way.</text>
<text id="311">A throwing knife dipped in poison.
Throw at enemies to inflict poison damage.

Used by assassins of Londor, land of Hollows.
The poison is jokingly known as Hollow's blood.</text>
<text id="330">Black charcoal-like pine resin.
Temporarily applies fire to right-hand weapon.

Used in the Undead Settlement to preserve 
Undead bodies after dissection, and to bury them.</text>
<text id="331">Rare pine resin which emits golden sparks.
Chunks of it are even rarer.

Temporarily applies lightning to right-hand weapon.

Its origins are unknown,
although some have speculated that
it may in fact be a type of fungal resin.</text>
<text id="334">Charcoal pine resin rotted with human body fluids.

Temporarily applies dark to right-hand weapon.

Normally used in the Undead Settlement
for preservation and burials,
but can mature into this state,
becoming a valuable substance,
used in a certain ceremony.
Often seen for trade at exorbitant prices.</text>
<text id="335">Highly viscous scarlet plant secretions.

Temporarily applies bleeding effect to right-hand weapon.

Associated with the warriors of Carthus,
whose blades take on the scarlet hues
of both this sanguine substance and
the spatters of their victims' blood.</text>
<text id="336">Pale pine resin that faintly glimmers.

Temporarily applies magic to right-hand weapon.

The blood red substance sometimes found
within suggests there is more to this
so-called resin than meets the eye.</text>
<text id="340">A small bundle of charcoal pine resin.

Quickly applies fire to right-hand weapon.

Does not last for long,
but can be used in inventive ways,
such as applying it in the middle of a series of blows.</text>
<text id="341">Rare pine resin which emits golden sparks.
Collected in a small bundle.

Quickly applies lightning to right-hand weapon.

Does not last for long,
but can be used in inventive ways,
such as applying it in the middle of a series of blows.</text>
<text id="343">Pine resin that has rotted and turned poisonous.
Likely rotten from the start.

Temporarily applies poison to right-hand weapon.

Farron Keep was swallowed by the rotted wood,
where the blunt-horned Ghrus concoct this resin.</text>
<text id="350">Bone fragment reduced to white ash.
Return to last bonfire used for resting,
or to the shrine bonfire.

Bonfires are sustained by bones of the Undead.
In rare cases,
their previous owner's strong urge to
seek bonfires enchants their bones
with a homeward instinct.</text>
<text id="351">Fragment of the coiled sword of a bonfire
which served its purpose long ago.

Returns caster to last bonfire used for resting,
or to the bonfire in Firelink Shrine.
Can be used repeatedly.

Bonfires are linked to one another irreversibly,
retaining their affinity long
after their purpose is exhausted.</text>
<text id="366">A leaf signifying a duty fulfilled
by the Watchdogs of Farron,
who stand beside the old wolf to ensure
the serenity of those at rest.
Depicts a swordgrass leaf stained with dried blood.

Long ago, the swordgrass leaf quietly identified
members of the Undead Legion.
In the rotted forest rest the spirits of warriors past,
their acceptance of and gratitude
toward their guardians is expressed eloquently
by the humble leaf.</text>
<text id="367">Proof of a duty fulfilled by the Aldrich Faithful,
who patiently await the Devourer of Gods' return.

Dregs are the heaviest things within the human body,
and will sink to the lowest depths imaginable,
where they become the shackles that bind this world.</text>
<text id="368">Proof that a red eye orb invader
successfully fended off a blue spirit.

Those who hunt dark spirits take the names
of gods in ancient accord with the Way of Blue,
a deception exemplified by their forked tongues.

Use to acquire two Pale Tongues.</text>
<text id="369">Distinguished proof that one has
hunted the enemies of the gods,
as per the ancient accord with the Way of Blue.

The layered ear of a dark spirit is the mark of
a particularly guilty offender,
one who has flagrantly violated one god or another.

Use to acquire two Proofs of a Concord Kept.</text>
<text id="370">Warm pebble emitting a beautiful
phasing aura of seven colors,
with a very rare eighth.

The prism stone does nothing special,
but can serve as a path marker,
or perhaps dropped off a cliff to judge height
by the sound of its descent.
If a loud noise is heard upon its landing,
then a fall from the ledge is surely lethal.</text>
<text id="371">Binoculars made of brass.
Use to peer at distant scenery.

Their utility is singular, but applications many.
The value of these specs depends greatly
on the imagination of their owner.</text>
<text id="372">Blood-drained, shrunken ear.
Souvenir taken for subduing the guilty.

The knights called the Blades of the Darkmoon
punish the guilt-soaked offenders of the Gods
and take this as proof of their conquest.
The earless corpses of the guilty will be
left behind as a warning to others,
inspiring both fear and respect for the Gods.
Such is the eternal mandate of the Dark Sun.</text>
<text id="373">Proof of a red orb invader's victory
over a Host of Embers.

Claiming tongues as trophies was originally
the practice of an infamous troupe of invaders,
who offered them to their speechless goddess.</text>
<text id="374">A special bone collected by members
of the covenant of Mound-makers,
discovered in the corpses of their victims.

Only one such bone is found in the vertebrae,
and the Mound-makers believe it to
be a shackle of the gods.
In their minds, each victim is another connection,
an addition to the family.</text>
<text id="375">A medal received by members of
the Warrior of Sunlight covenant for victory
over the final foe when summoned.
The summoner also gains the same medal.

The medal, engraved with the holy symbol of the sun,
is slightly warm, and reminds one of the great honor
of a shared victory.</text>
<text id="377">Stone imbued with the power of the everlasting dragons,
used in a secret rite by dragon worshippers.

Gain the head of a dragon and emit dragon breath,
a transformation that is irreversible until death.

Those who choose the path of the dragon
strive for perfect imitation,
and the dragon head rite is the first step
in this grand process.</text>
<text id="378">Stone imbued with the power of the everlasting dragons,
used in a secret rite by dragon worshippers.

Gain the torso of a dragon and a dragon's roar,
a transformation that is irreversible until death.

From ancient times,
the path of dragon worship was walked by warriors.
It is said they envision Archdragon Peak in the depths
of their meditation, and at times,
they even hear the distant sound
of the great bell at the peak.</text>
<text id="380">Rubbish with no value.

Who in their right mind would
bother carrying this around?
Perhaps you need help.</text>
<text id="385">Online play item.
Dried finger with multiple knuckles.

Use to strengthen connection to other worlds,
allowing the summoning of a third phantom,
but also a second dark spirit.

Also makes the summoning of a dark spirit occur earlier.
Use with caution.</text>
<text id="387">Stone imbued with the power of the everlasting dragons,
the second of its kind, offered to a towering dragon.

Gain the head of a dragon and emit breath
alongside an archdragon mirage.
The transformation is irreversible until death.

The illusion achieved was the first case of
a human imitating the form of an ancient dragon,
and it revealed the smallness of human existence.
The road to the old dragons is long and arduous,
and only one can complete the journey.</text>
<text id="388">Stone imbued with the power of the everlasting dragons,
offered to a towering dragon.
This stone shows signs of a nascent light.

Gain the torso of a dragon and roar
alongside an archdragon mirage.
The transformation is irreversible until death.

Yet true imitation will require a dragon head, as well.</text>
<text id="390">Soul of a Fire Keeper who is said to
have returned from the Abyss.

This Fire Keeper preserves the bonfire,
and serves its champion.
She is said to have soothed and accepted the dark sigil,
which has tainted her soul.

And yet, her soul will one day embed itself
in the bosom of another Fire Keeper.</text>
<text id="400">The fading soul of a corpse.

Use to gain a smattering of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="401">Soul found in a deserted corpse.

Use to acquire souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="402">Large soul found in a deserted corpse.

Use to acquire souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="403">Soul found in the corpse of an unknown traveler.

Use to acquire souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="404">A large soul found in the corpse of an unknown traveler.

Use to acquire souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="405">Soul found in the corpse of a nameless soldier.

Use to acquire souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="406">Large soul found in the corpse of a nameless soldier.

Use to acquire souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="407">Soul found in the corpse of a battle-weary warrior.

Use to acquire a large amount of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="408">Large soul found in the corpse of a battle-weary warrior.

Use to acquire a large amount of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="409">Soul found in the corpse of a crestfallen knight.

Use to acquire a large amount of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="410">Large soul found in the corpse of a crestfallen knight.

Use to acquire a large amount of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="411">Soul found in the corpse of a proud paladin.

Use to acquire many souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="412">Large soul found in the corpse of a proud paladin.

Use to acquire many souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="413">Soul found in the corpse of an intrepid hero.

Use to acquire a great helping of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="414">Large soul found in the corpse of an intrepid hero.

Use to acquire a great helping of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="415">Soul found in the corpse of a seasoned warrior.

Use to acquire a great helping of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="416">Large soul found in the corpse of a seasoned warrior.

Use to acquire a great helping of souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="417">Soul found in the corpse of an old hand at war.

Use to acquire innumerable souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="418">Large soul found in the corpse of an old hand at war.

Use to acquire innumerable souls.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="419">Soul found in the corpse of a champion of legend.

Use to acquire enough souls to sate a lord.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="420">Large soul found in the corpse of a champion of legend.

Use to acquire enough souls to sate a lord.

Let the Fire Keeper transform this sovereignless soul
into a source of strength,
for to be Unkindled is to be a vessel for souls.</text>
<text id="440">Makes enemies react to invaders.

The giant trees were also known as watcher trees,
and their seeds unmask invaders.

When used effectively,
these seeds will help counter dark spirits.</text>
<text id="452">A small clump of mossfruit.

Temporarily boosts bleed, poison, frost, and curse resistance.

All mossfruit is the same regardless of its color,
and has the effects of moss of all colors.</text>
<text id="454">A young white branch.

Use to transform into something
which blends into the surroundings.

Little Dusk's first sorcerer's staff
eventually became a seedling,
and then three white birch saplings.
The young branch is said to still contain echoes
of little Dusk's capriciousness.</text>
<text id="455">An old rusted copper coin.

Crushing the coin boosts item discovery.

Those who have lost their fortunes rely
upon this superstitious practice,
hoping to retrieve what was once theirs, and more.</text>
<text id="456">Special brew of Siegward of Catarina.
Perfect for travel in its jolly barrel mug.

Restores HP and temporarily boosts frost resistance.

Leave it to Siegward to discover a drink
that even an Undead can enjoy.
Perhaps his long years spent Undead have left him
wanting to drain a cup or two and revel as if
he were still among the living.</text>
<text id="457">A rusty old gold coin that surely has no currency.

Crushing the coin gives a large, if temporary,
boost to item discovery.

A rich man lost his fortune,
but it returned to him twofold.
He was swift to squander his retrieved fortune,
smugly confident that it was bound to double once again.</text>
<text id="458">Medicinal pellet made from crushed insects.
The blue type temporarily boosts magic damage absorption.

The Boreal Valley is infested with moon bugs,
meaning ingredients are never far from hand
for the Irithyllian slaves who concoct this medicine.</text>
<text id="459">Medicinal pellet made from crushed insects.
The red type temporarily boosts fire damage absorption.

Prepared in the Cathedral of the Deep by evangelists,
who dole them out to followers to
ease their suffering when they burn.</text>
<text id="460">Medicinal pellet made from crushed insects.
The yellow type temporarily boosts
lightning damage absorption.

The grave wardens of Carthus used these
to repel a great sand worm.

The worm tumbled into the catacombs,
and proceeded to dominate its new home
in the Smoldering Lake.</text>
<text id="461">Medicinal pellet made from crushed insects.
The black type temporarily boosts Dark damage absorption.

At all times, the Abyss Watchers of the Undead Legion
keep a supply of these concoctions,
prepared by the acolytes.
Rumor has it their Ghru descendants
still make these concoctions.</text>
<text id="462">Branch of a white birch received from a giant,
apparently as a token of friendship.

Become something that blends in to the surroundings.
Consumed with use.

"Good friend, no hit."</text>
<text id="463">Branch of a white birch received from somebody.
Apparently, this was once a token of friendship.

Use to become something that blends into the surroundings,
though the branch will unfortunately be consumed.

Perhaps treasuring the memory is more important.</text>
<text id="490">A black, gaping hole in the flesh that
resembles the brand of an Undead.

The darkness of humanity seeps from
this bottomless pitch-black hole,
the gap filled by the accumulation of the curse.

This Dark Sigil will never heal,
but there is a tale told of a Fire Keeper
who returned from the Abyss,
and brought great comfort to a bearer of the curse.</text>
<text id="500">No Unkindled can ever truly claim the embers
that burn within a champion's bosom,
which is precisely what makes their
yearning for warmth so keen.

Gain the strength of flame
and increased max HP until death.

With the strength of fire,
the summoning signs of Unkindled become visible,
and seekers of embers can be summoned
to join in co-operation.
But beware, the embers may also attract invaders.</text>
<text id="520">A strange head of unknown origin carved from archtree.
It speaks when thrown on the ground.

This head says "Hello". Have another look.
Do you sense the amicability in its eyes?</text>
<text id="521">A strange head of unknown origin carved from archtree.
It speaks when thrown on the ground.

This head says "Thank you". Have another
look. Is this not a face of gratitude?</text>
<text id="522">A strange head of unknown origin carved from archtree.
It speaks when thrown on the ground.

This head says "Very good!" Have another
look. Does it not appear rather jovial?</text>
<text id="523">A strange head of unknown origin carved from archtree.
It speaks when thrown on the ground.

This head says "I'm sorry". Have another look.
Isn't it quite the expression of atonement?</text>
<text id="524">A strange head of unknown origin carved from archtree.
It speaks when thrown on the ground.

This head says "Help me!" Look again.
Can you hear the desperation of its plea?</text>
<text id="712">Soul of the champion Gundyr.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Once, a champion came late to the festivities,
and was greeted by a shrine without fire,
and a bell that would not toll.</text>
<text id="714">Soul of the dancer.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The Pontiff Sulyvahn bestowed a double-slashing
sword upon a distant daughter of the formal royal family,
ordering her to serve first as a dancer,
and then as an outrider knight,
the equivalent to exile.</text>
<text id="715">Soul of a Crystal Sage.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The twin Crystal Sages once served as
spiritual guides to the scholars of the Grand Archives,
and one went on to ally with the Undead Legion.</text>
<text id="717">Soul of the Blood of the Wolf.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The blood was spread amongst the Abyss Watchers,
and their souls are one with
the soul of the wolf blood master.</text>
<text id="718">Soul of Oceiros, the Consumed King.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Oceiros went mad trying to harness his
royal blood for a greater purpose,
leading him to the heretics of the Grand Archives,
where he discovered the twisted worship
of Seath the paledrake.</text>
<text id="719">Soul of Vordt of the Boreal Valley.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Vordt served as an outrider knight,
never far from the fleeting dancer.</text>
<text id="720">Soul of the Old Demon King.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The shriveled Old Demon King
is now like a clump of burnt ash,
but he is the last living witness
of the Chaos of Izalith.</text>
<text id="721">Soul of the Dragonslayer Armour.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The Dragonslayer Armour,
controlled by the Pilgrim Butterfly,
lost its master long ago,
but still remembers their sporting hunts.</text>
<text id="722">Soul of the Nameless King.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The Nameless King was once
a dragon-slaying god of war,
before he sacrificed everything to
ally himself with the ancient dragons.</text>
<text id="724">Soul of Pontiff Sulyvahn.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Pontiff Sulyvahn of Irithyll imprisoned a god
of the old royalty in the abandoned cathedral,
to be fed to the devourer. </text>
<text id="725">Soul of Aldrich.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

When Aldrich ruminated on the fading of the fire,
it inspired visions of a coming age of the deep sea.
He knew the path would be arduous,
but he had no fear.
He would devour the gods himself.</text>
<text id="726">Soul of the High Lord Wolnir.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Lord Wolnir of Carthus sentenced
countless souls to gruesome deaths,
keen to outlive them all.</text>
<text id="727">Soul of the Curse-rotted Greatwood.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Ever since its establishment,
all manner of curses have managed to
seep into the Undead Settlement.
The worst of them were sealed away
inside a spirit tree,
but eventually the curses took their toll.</text>
<text id="728">The soul of Rosaria, Mother of Rebirth,
stolen by Ringfinger Leonhard.

Return this to her extant corpse,
and mother Rosaria will spring back to life.

As if nothing had ever happened.</text>
<text id="729">Soul of the Deacons of the Deep.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

After Aldrich left for the Boreal valley,
Archdeacon Royce remained in the cathedral
with the high priests,
to keep eternal watch over their master's coffin.</text>
<text id="731">Soul of the Twin Princes.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The two princes rejected their duty
to become Lords of Cinder,
and settled down far,
far away to watch the fire fade from a distance.
A curse makes their souls nearly inseparable.</text>
<text id="732">Soul of Yhorm the Giant.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Yhorm is the descendant of an ancient conqueror,
but was asked by the very people
once subjugated to lead them,
serving as both a weighty blade and a stone-hard shield.</text>
<text id="733">Soul of the Lords.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Since Lord Gwyn, the first Lord of Cinder,
many exalted lords have linked the First Flame,
and it is their very souls that have
manifested themselves as defender of the flame.</text>
<text id="739">Soul of a demon.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Demons were born of the Chaos Flame,
but the flame has not survived,
and the demons are a dying race.</text>
<text id="743">Soul of the Stray Demon.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The Stray Demon, now lacking even a trace of flame,
was once the gatekeeper of Lothric.</text>
<text id="1000">Titanite shard for weapon reinforcement.
Reinforces weapons to +3.

Titanite shards are fragments
of the Legendary Slabs.
Titanite is etched into weapons to reinforce.</text>
<text id="1001">Titanite shard for weapon reinforcement.
A larger shard that reinforces weapons to +6.

Titanite shards are fragments
of the Legendary Slabs.
Titanite is etched into weapons to reinforce.</text>
<text id="1002">Titanite chunk for weapon reinforcement.
Reinforces weapons to +9.

Few records of chunks exist,
and once one was discovered in Lothric,
the race to locate Legendary Slabs began,
but there have been no reports of success.</text>
<text id="1003">Titanite slab for weapon reinforcement,
said to once belong to the gods.
Reinforces weapons to their highest level.

Titanite slabs are smithing materials of the gods,
and weapons reinforced with slabs will be admired
no less than their precious legendary weapons.</text>
<text id="1020">Titanite altered by a soul.
Reinforces soul-transposed weapons to +4.

Weapons forged by soul transposition can only
be reinforced by titanite of the same kind.

In rare cases, crystal lizards devour souls,
growing to monstrous proportion and
leaving these great scales.</text>
<text id="1030">Twinkling titanite for weapon reinforcement.
Reinforce weapons steeped in strength to +4.
These unique weapons cannot be reinforced
with ordinary titanite,
nor can they be infused.

Unless one uses this twinkling titanite,
which reinforces these weapons without
unraveling their inherent strength.</text>
<text id="1100">A gem of infused titanite.
Famously used to forge Farron greatswords.

Used in infusion to create heavy weapons.

A warrior can appreciate a heavy weapon,
for they scale effectively with strength.</text>
<text id="1110">A gem of infused titanite.
Forged the unique curved swords of Carthus.

Used in infusion to create sharp weapons.

A swordsman can appreciate a sharp weapon,
for they scale effectively with dexterity.</text>
<text id="1120">A gem of infused titanite.
Forged the weapons of Lothric knights.

Used in infusion to create refined weapons.

Refined weapons are difficult to wield properly,
and scale effectively with strength and dexterity.</text>
<text id="1130">A gem of infused titanite.
Introduced to Lothric by the Crystal Sages.

Used in infusion to create crystal weapons.

Crystal weapons inflict magic damage,
and scale effectively with intelligence.</text>
<text id="1140">A gem of infused titanite,
said to be an object of infatuation for
victims of stunted development.

Used in infusion to create simple weapons.

Simple weapons inflict magic damage
and restore FP very gradually,
to help even a simpleton muster some mettle.</text>
<text id="1150">A gem of infused titanite.
Found in rare cases inside demons.

Used in infusion to create fire weapons.

Fire weapons inflict fire damage,
but lose scaling effects.</text>
<text id="1160">A gem of infused titanite.
Relics of lands scorched by the Chaos Flame.

Used in infusion to create chaos weapons.

Chaos weapons inflict fire damage,
and scale with intelligence and faith.</text>
<text id="1170">A gem of infused titanite.
Found in the aftermath of dragon hunts.

Used in infusion to create lightning weapons.

Lightning weapons inflict lightning damage,
and scale with faith.</text>
<text id="1180">A gem of infused titanite.
Found in the dregs of the Cathedral of the Deep.

Used in infusion to create deep weapons.

Deep weapons inflict dark damage,
but lose scaling effects.

There is a darkness that lies beyond human ken.</text>
<text id="1190">A gem of infused titanite.
Born of disembodied humanity.

Used in infusion to create dark weapons.

Dark weapons inflict dark damage,
and scale with intelligence and faith.</text>
<text id="1200">A gem of infused titanite.
Discovered in the rotted forest of Farron.

Used in infusion to create poison weapons.

Such weapons inflict poison-laced damage
that gradually eats away at foes.</text>
<text id="1210">A gem of infused titanite.
Slurped by Irithyll slaves.

Used in infusion to create lacerating weapons.

Such weapons inflict lacerating damage.
Most effective with sharp or spiked weapons.</text>
<text id="1220">A gem of infused titanite.
Forged the weapons of Lothric foot soldiers.

Used in infusion to create raw weapons.

Raw weapons are easily wielded and have higher attack,
but lose scaling effects.</text>
<text id="1230">A gem of infused titanite.
Commonly known as a charm kept by saints.

Used in infusion to create blessed weapons.

Special blessed weapons gradually restore HP
and heavily damage reanimated foes.</text>
<text id="1240">A gem of infused titanite.
A stone plentiful in Londor, land of Hollows.

Used in infusion to create Hollow weapons.

Hollow weapons are said to peer
into the essence of its wielder,
whose luck boosts attack.</text>
<text id="1250">A gem of infused titanite.
Also known as stark stone.

Reverses weapon infusion.

Has the benefit of undoing the effects of infusion
without reducing the reinforcement level.</text>
<text id="2001">Key to the room of the lift that descends
to the deepest dungeon in Lothric.

A surviving Darkwraith,
from the land swallowed by darkness,
is said to be held there.</text>
<text id="2005">Small silverwork doll depicting a young squire.

In the legendary old city of Irithyll
situated in the Boreal Valley,
the Pontiff Sulyvahn gave this doll to valued subjects,
so that they might use it to cross the barrier
when they return home.

Listen carefully, and you can hear it say,
"Wherever you go, the moon still sets in Irithyll.
Wherever you may be, Irithyll is your home."</text>
<text id="2007">Key to the barred window in the Irithyll dungeon.

But the window only leads to a bottomless black pit below,
and above, a paltry view of the ruined Profaned Capital.

The very architecture appears to be a cruel joke
the jailers played on would-be escapees.</text>
<text id="2008">Ring of keys to the Irithyll dungeon held by the jailer.

Opens most cell doors.

On what grounds do they remain imprisoned,
considering that by now they are mindless Hollows,
or unrealized, gibbering fools?</text>
<text id="2009">Key to the barred door leading from the sewer
below the Undead Settlement to a moist grave.

The grave, which no longer receives visitors,
was once the site of a statue of Velka,
Goddess of Sin, and was believed to pardon wrongdoing,
and lift curses.</text>
<text id="2010">Key to a cell holding thieves and the like.

There is no shortage of brash thieves in Lothric,
and these particular thieves likely scaled the wall
from the Undead Settlement.

But they are only willing to practice
their thievery on the High Wall,
for their fear of Lothric castle, rumored to devour men,
keeps them clear of its grounds.</text>
<text id="2012">Key to the oldest cell in the Irithyll dungeon.

The first prisoner of the dungeon was a lone giant.
Cells for men were built at his feet.</text>
<text id="2013">Key to the decrepit tower behind Firelink Shrine
which leads to the Bell Tower.

The Bell Tower is the grave of Fire Keepers past.
When a Fire Keeper has served her purpose,
she is led to true darkness,
where she enjoys a long-deserved sleep.</text>
<text id="2014">Key to the main entrance to
the Grand Archives of Lothric.

With the fire fading,
and the spreading pus of man tainting the castle,
the Grand Archives closed its doors for good.

Today, only a few of its keys remain.
This one likely belonged to Gotthard,
one of the king's Black Hands, who fled the castle.</text>
<text id="2102">Small banner held by Lothric messengers.

Hold up outside the main castle gate
to be greeted by an escort.

When the High Wall appeared,
the path to the Undead Settlement was blocked,
and messengers came bearing this banner.
They were sent out with a duty,
but had no way of returning.</text>
<text id="2103">Coal used for weapon infusion.

Long ago, used to forge the greatswords of
the Undead Legion of Farron.

Give to the blacksmith in the shrine to allow
the use of gems for heavy, sharp, and poison infusion.</text>
<text id="2104">Coal used for weapon infusion.

The white magic flame produced by this coal
was given to the Undead Legion long ago by
one of the Crystal Sage twins.

Give to the blacksmith in the shrine to allow
the use of gems for crystal, blessed, and dark infusion.</text>
<text id="2105">Coal used for weapon infusion.

It is said that the giant blacksmith of Anor Londo
was once the blacksmith of the gods.

Give to the blacksmith in the shrine to allow
the use of gems for lightning, simple, and chaos infusion.</text>
<text id="2106">Coal used for weapon infusion.

Remnants of the fire that burned down the Profaned Capital,
preserved in an icy skull.

Give to the blacksmith in the shrine to allow
the use of gems for dark, blood, and Hollow infusion.</text>
<text id="2107">Umbral ash of a resident of the Undead Settlement
who made a living burying corpses.

With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.</text>
<text id="2108">Umbral ash of one who dreamt of
joining the Undead Legion.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

In the end, the dream chasers who wandered aimlessly
in the rotted forest found a sense of fulfillment.</text>
<text id="2109">Umbral ash of a worn-out paladin
who sought the Cathedral of the Deep.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

This paladin paid quite a price for his headstrong justice.</text>
<text id="2110">Umbral ash of the grave warden
of the catacombs of Carthus.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

The old man began as a squire,
carrying his master's accoutrements.
He ended his days a grave warden,
and carried them still.</text>
<text id="2111">Umbral ash of Greirat of the Undead Settlement.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Greirat was a thief who fancied
himself a martyr for the poor,
which is what drove him to climb the wall.</text>
<text id="2112">Umbral ash of Orbeck of Vinheim.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Orbeck was fascinated with sorcery but without means,
so offered to serve as an assassin in exchange
for acceptance into the Dragon Academy,
believing that one day he could
reinvent himself as a sorcerer.</text>
<text id="2113">Umbral ash of Cornyx of the Great Swamp.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Cornyx was tired and defeated until
he discovered one final pupil,
like so many pyromancers before him.</text>
<text id="2114">Umbral ash of Karla. With this,
the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

The spurned child of the Abyss never dies,
but phases in and out of its fringes.
Only, there is no one to search for her any longer.</text>
<text id="2115">Umbral ash of Irina of Carim.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Irina was a frail woman.
This frailty led to her becoming a saint of Carim,
and to her grand treachery.</text>
<text id="2116">Umbral ash of Yuria of Londor.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Having three founders of the Black Church
ensured Yuria's legacy would survive.
Her two sisters could carry the torch,
making certain their lord claims the flame,
for the sake of all Hollows.</text>
<text id="2117">Chalice used in old ceremony in which
Lothric knights take their vows.

It is only a formality now,
but it remains as an empty practice.

Place this basin at a statue of a beheading knight.</text>
<text id="2118">Old, discolored human bone with several holes bored into it.

A woman's corpse in the Undead Settlement
was found clutching this bone.
Her name was Loretta.</text>
<text id="2119">A sacred braille tome from Carim,
filled with advanced miracles.

Give to a storyteller to learn advanced Carim miracles.

In the Way of White,
there is a tradition of placing great faith
in the words of the blind,
and braille tomes are not unusual.</text>
<text id="2120">A sacred braille tome from Lothric,
filled with miracles for use by knights.

Give to a storyteller to learn Lothric miracles.

It is said that no paladin
inside Lothric castle could fall,
owing to the divine protection they enjoyed.</text>
<text id="2123">Cinders of a lord left by the Abyss Watchers.

If the lords will not return
to their thrones themselves,
let them return as cinders.

The Watchers of the Abyss swore upon
their shared wolf's blood,
which also served as their
mandate as lords.</text>
<text id="2124">Cinders of a lord left by Aldrich, Devourer of Gods.

If the lords will not return
to their thrones themselves,
let them return as cinders.

Aldrich became a lord by devouring men,
but was disillusioned with his throne,
and so took to devouring gods instead.</text>
<text id="2125">Cinders of a lord left by Yhorm the Giant.

If the lords will not return
to their thrones themselves,
let them return as cinders.

Lonely Yhorm became a Lord of Cinder
to put the Profaned Flame to rest,
knowing full well that those who
spoke of him as lord were quite insincere.</text>
<text id="2126">Cinders of a lord left by Prince Lothric.

If the lords will not return
to their thrones themselves,
let them return as cinders.

The Lothric bloodline was obsessed
with creating a worthy heir,
and when this proved impossible,
resorted to unspeakable means.
Suffice it to say,
the path to linking the fire is a cursed one indeed.</text>
<text id="2127">Pyromancy tome from the Great Swamp
containing advanced pyromancies.

Give to the old master pyromancer to learn
advanced pyromancies of the Great Swamp.

Spells of the Great Swamp are
passed down from master to pupil.
Without a master, there is no pupil,
but without a pupil, there is also no master.</text>
<text id="2128">A pyromancy tome from Carthus
containing pyromancies crafted for battle.

Give to the old master pyromancer to learn
advanced pyromancies of the Carthus.

Carthus pyromancies developed
in isolation from other forms,
explaining their divergent evolution.</text>
<text id="2129">A pyromancy tome from Izalith
containing pyromancies of the witches.

Give to the old master pyromancer to learn
chaos pyromancies of Izalith.

Chaos pyromancies manipulate lava,
and birthed all later forms of pyromancy.</text>
<text id="2130">A pyromancy tome of Quelana
containing her unique spells.
These pyromancies can only be taught by a female master.

Give to a female pyromancy master to learn
Quelana's pyromancies.

Quelana, the sole surviving witch of Izalith,
once accepted a human pupil,
but after the pupil moved on,
she never took another.</text>
<text id="2131">A pyromancy tome of the grave warden,
from the Carthus catacombs.

Give to the pyromancer master to learn
black flame sorceries.

High Lord Wolnir of Carthus succumbed to the Abyss,
but the pyromancer later became a grave warden,
and discovered the black flame.</text>
<text id="2132">Scroll containing sorceries of the Crystal Sages.

Give to a sorcerer to learn sorceries of the Sages.

As any sorcerer knows, sorcery is a talent,
and these sorceries were refined to
nurture a very special talent.</text>
<text id="2133">Secret scroll of the Profaned Capital court sorcerers,
containing sorceries of Logan.

Give to a sorcerer to learn Logan's sorceries.

The court sorcerers used this scroll
to claim heirship to Logan's legacy,
though how that claim stands up to
closer scrutiny is another story.</text>
<text id="2134">Secret crystal scroll of the Grand Archives of Lothric.

Give to a sorcerer to learn crystal sorceries.

These sorceries are the work of the paledrake,
Seath the Scaleless,
whom Logan is said to have met,
a branch of sorcery that has been
carried on by the Crystal Sages.</text>
<text id="2135">An old transposing kiln from Courland,
crafted with stitched crystal lizard hide.

Give to Ludleth, Lord of Cinder,
to conduct soul transposition.

This kiln can transpose twisted souls to craft
special items with their concentrated essence.
Deemed forbidden by those unable to make proper use of it.</text>
<text id="2137">Sword missing from the shrine bonfire.
Cannot be equipped as a weapon.

Thrust into the shrine bonfire to restore
its power and enable travel between bonfires.

This sword is only bequeathed to chosen ash,
as judged by the Iudex,
who awaits the arrival of ash as a scabbard.</text>
<text id="2138">A pair of dark eyes.

Said to be the eyes of the first Fire Keeper,
and the light that was lost
by all Fire Keepers to come.

It reveals to the sightless Fire Keepers things
that they should never see.</text>
<text id="2139">Ceremonial sword of Londor.
Cannot be equipped as a weapon.

It is said that a rite of wedlock
will presage a true Hollow lord.

Your spouse's name is Anri,
who patiently awaits a rightful lord,
deep within the mausoleum.</text>
<text id="2140">A golden scroll chronicling the vast research
of the xanthous scholars.

Give to a sorcerer to learn the arts of Oolacile.

In the lost land of Oolacile,
the sorceries orchestrated light,
and were said to shine in golden hues.</text>
<text id="2141">A shard soaked in Estus.

Give to the blacksmith at the shrine
to increases usages of the Estus Flask.

In the old days,
it was rare to see an Estus Flask far from its owner,
but this shard offers hope, however shattered.</text>
<text id="2142">Blood-stained swordgrass of Hawkwood,
deserter of the Undead Legion.

Traditionally, the Undead Legion of Farron sends
the gravest of messages using swordgrass.

"Come to the mausoleum in Farron.
Only one can take the path of ancient dragons."</text>
<text id="2143">Undead bones that yet burn.

Cast it into the shrine bonfire
to boost the recovery provided by the Estus Flask.

The bonfire's cinders are the bones of Undead,
and a bone that still burns is a fresh cinder indeed.
Before feeding upon death, one must first pray to it.</text>
<text id="2144">A braille divine tome of the Deep,
belonging to the deacons of the cathedral.

Give this to a storyteller to learn
miracles of the Deep.

Intended to teach divine protection
to the deacons of the deep, but later,
dark tales were added to its pages,
such that it is now considered a thing profane.</text>
<text id="2145">A braille tome of Londor,
first spoken by Liliane of the Sable Church.

Give this to a storyteller to learn miracles of Londor.

This is a forbidden tome,
as it offers salvation to all Hollows,
and conversely curses all things living.</text>
<text id="2146">Unclean umbral ash coated with excrement.
Perhaps it's possible the handmaid of Firelink Shrine
could turn this into a few new things...

"Oh to savor the sweet pungency but once more..."</text>
<text id="2147">Umbral ash of the prisoner chief of the catacombs.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

The prisoner chief used his clout
to hoard all manner of things,
but died without putting them to use.</text>
<text id="2148">Umbral ash of a sorcerer who explored
the golden sorceries of a long-lost land.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

They were called xanthous scholars,
but some foolishly imitate them
by simply dressing in yellow.</text>
<text id="2149">Umbral ash of a Hollow who
faithfully served a woman,
only to become separated from her.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

It takes but a brief glance at this thing
to easily envision Londor,
the foreboding land of Hollows.</text>
<text id="2150">Umbral ash of Unbreakable Patches.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Patches never lost heart, and never looked back.
He marched in one direction,
and that direction was dead ahead.
Did you see him passing by?</text>
<text id="2151">Umbral ash of the fallen warrior
who chose the path of the ancient dragons.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Whatever it is, it is sure to grant strength
to the most unrelenting warriors.</text>
<text id="2152">Umbral ash of an armor merchant
from an eastern land.
Surely the handmaid of Firelink Shrine can
turn this into a few new things.

The merchant, the captain of a clan of hunters,
was fascinated with weaponry.</text>
<text id="744">Soul of Sister Friede.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire numerous souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Friede was the first Ash to enter the painting,
but together with the good Father,
they chose rot over fire.</text>
<text id="2153">The charred but warm bones of a champion.
Burn at the Firelink Shrine bonfire
to participate in Undead Matches.

Long ago, an Undead declared a fight.
A fight to celebrate their undeath,
and to preserve what remained of their souls.
So it was that the Undead Matches were born.

The merit of an Undead is measured in deaths.
Could there be a greater gift for such a creature,
than a fight that has no end?</text>
<text id="2154">Umbral ash of the Captain of the Millwood Knights.
With this, the shrine handmaiden will prepare new items.

Long ago, when the Millwood Knights lost
the forest they called home,
they began a journey so long that even thoughts
of their sworn enemy washed away,
replaced by a vision of a cold and brittle wood.</text>
<text id="2155">The key to the contraption leading to
the attic of the archive found on
the edge of the Corvian Settlement.

After Sir Vilhelm led a white-haired woman
to the attic of the library,
he kept this key as if it were his life.</text>
<text id="315">This special throwing blade has a flat tip,
and is wielded by guardians of the Church of Filianore.

Consume FP to project illusory blades
which seek their targets.

Guardians of the Church, of whom few remain,
watch over Princess Filianore's eternal slumber
along with the Spears of the Church.</text>
<text id="379">The Spears of the Church watch over the Princess' slumber,
and this serves as proof of their fulfillment of their duty. 
The embellished gold cloth is woven
with a crest of young grass.

The Princess' knights proudly displayed
these precious favors,
which were most often seen swaying
from their identical ceremonial spears.</text>
<text id="650">Online play item.
A fragment of the matching ritual spears
once held by the knights of Princess Filianore.

They are the namesake of the Spears of the Church.

When Spears of the Church
face unduly treacherous foes,
this allows them to draw upon former majesty,
and summon a row of upward-thrusting ritual spears.</text>
<text id="651">Online play item.
A fragment of the matching ritual spears
once held by the knights of Princess Filianore.

These Divine Spears of gold were placed
in the trusted hands of exalted Spears.

When Spears of the Church
face unduly treacherous foes,
this allows them to draw upon former majesty,
and summon a row of upward-thrusting ritual spears.</text>
<text id="745">Soul of Slave Knight Gael.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The red-hooded, wandering slave knight Gael
sought the blood of the dark soul
as pigment for the Painted World.
But Gael knew he was no Champion,
that the dark soul would likely ruin him,
and that he had little hope of a safe return.</text>
<text id="746">Soul of the demon prince.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

The demons, birthed from a common Chaos,
share almost everything between them,
even the pride of their prince,
and his near-faded flame.

So that the last demon standing may rekindle it.</text>
<text id="747">Soul of Darkeater Midir.
One of the twisted souls, steeped in strength.

Use to acquire many souls,
or transpose to extract its true strength.

Midir, descendant of Archdragons,
was raised by the gods,
and owing to his immortality,
was given a duty to eternally battle the dark,
a duty that he would never forget,
even after the gods perished.</text>
<text id="2156">The small banner used by envoys
of Great Lord Gwyn in the days of yore.

Face the ringed cliff and hold the banner high
to summon facilitators of transport.

For the pygmies, who took the dark soul,
the Great Lord gifted the Ringed City,
an isolated place at world's end,
and his beloved youngest daughter,
promising her that he would
come for her when the day came.</text>
<text id="2157">Umbral ash of the old stone-humped woman.
With this, the shrine handmaid will prepare new items.

Things that have dreadfully run their
course accrue at the great dreg-heap.
This old woman was once the wet nurse of royalty.</text>
<text id="2158">Blood of the dark soul that seeped
from the hole within Slave Knight Gael.

Used as pigment by his lady in Ariandel
to depict a painted world.

When Gael came upon the pygmy lords,
he discovered that their blood had long ago dried,
and so consumed the dark soul.</text>
<text id="2159">A small, transparent stone that once graced
the green young grass crest.

This semi-precious gem honors a Spear of Church
after a battle well-fought,
and is said to slightly enhance
their blessing of protection.
(while held, this effect is constant)</text>
<text id="10000">A silver pendant depicting the Darkmoon and a sword,
the crest of the Darkmoon Knights,
the original Blue Sentinels.
Equip to pledge oneself to
the Blade of the Darkmoon covenant.

When a member of the Way of Blue faces a dark spirit,
the Blades of the Darkmoon,
by an ancient accord,
help to root out the invader.
Summoning takes place automatically when equipped.</text>
<text id="10020">Ancient medallion depicting the crest of a wolf.
Symbolizes the pact with the Old Wolf of Farron.
Equip to pledge oneself to the Watchdogs of Farron.

The Watchdogs ensure that the warriors sleep in serenity,
by taking the form of loyal spirits and hunting down
those who would trespass the woods of Farron.

Summoning takes place automatically
while this is equipped.</text>
<text id="10030">The holy symbol of the Cathedral of the Deep,
and crest of those who see beyond fire
to the age of deep waters.
Equip to pledge oneself to the Aldrich Faithful covenant.

The Faithful ensure that Aldrich, Devourer of Gods,
remains undisturbed, by taking the form of loyal spirits
and hunting down those who
would trespass the ruined cathedral.

Summoning takes place automatically
while this is equipped.</text>
<text id="10040">An ancient talisman depicting a holy symbol
bestowed upon the Warriors of Sunlight.
Equip to pledge oneself to the Warrior of Sunlight covenant.

Warriors of Sunlight are brilliantly beaming co-operators
who place their golden signatures to help those in need,
for it is their duty to deliver
a great conquest to their summoner.</text>
<text id="10050">A malformed vertebra found by the mad,
with a queer symbol on its inside,
proof of the shackles of the Gods.
Equip to pledge oneself to the Mound-makers covenant.

The mound-makers wish only to add to their mounds,
becoming mad spirits whether summoned
as co-operators or invaders.

They are blithe to those around them, for in their minds,
any kill might lead to another shackle.</text>
<text id="10060">Pale blue sheepskin parchment featuring
an illustration of the moon,
symbol of an ancient accord.

Members of the Way of Blue are
the beneficiaries of an ancient accord.
When a dark spirit threatens them,
a blue spirit will grant them assistance,
and help to root out the invader.

Summoning takes place automatically
while this is equipped.</text>
<text id="10070">Faded sheepskin parchment depicting
the Darkmoon and a sword.
Equip to pledge oneself to the Blue Sentinels covenant.

When a member of the Way of Blue is
threatened by a dark spirit,
the Blue Sentinels, in compliance with an ancient accord,
assume the form of blue spirits,
and help to root out the invader.

Summoning takes place automatically
while this is equipped.</text>
<text id="10080">Sacred seal of Archdeacon Klimt,
who served Rosaria, Mother of Rebirth.
Equip to pledge oneself to the Rosaria's Fingers covenant.

Rosaria's Fingers collect tongues in her name.
Some do it to be reborn;
others do it to help comfort their voiceless goddess.</text>
<text id="10090">A green-rusted ornament of young grass,
the crest of Princess Filianore.
Equip to join the Spears of the Church covenant.

The Spears of the Church watch over the Princess' slumber,
and when the church is compromised by a trespasser,
the Judicator summons them
as loyal spirits to eliminate the threat
(summoned automatically while this is equipped).

Loyal spirits summoned as Spears of the Church
are granted a blessing of protection.</text>
<text id="242">Silver pendant engraved with the crest of Artorias.

One of the ancient treasures of Anor Londo.
Presented to Artorias for facing the Abyss.

Effectively deflects the Dark of the Abyss,
especially in its magic forms.</text>
<text id="277">A blessed charm. Cures poison and restores HP.

Many such charms were blessed in
reconstructed ancient ceremonies,
carried out in the monastery of Lindelt,
now known as the new home of miracles.

Though it may lack the power of an original,
in circumstances dire enough,
an imitation can be quite enough.</text>
<text id="301">An urn filled with crystal-clear water.
Originally intended as a soothing potion,
this water scalds the skin of Undead and Hollows.

In the old capital of Mirrah, an ancient,
well-protected spring produces holy water,
but the water has been difficult to acquire
ever since Mirrah became embroiled in war.</text>
<text id="376">This faintly warm medal,
engraved with the symbol of the Sun,
is the ultimate honor,
awarded to shoe who summon
the Warrior of Sunlight and complete a goal.

The symbol represents Lord Gwyn's firstborn,
who lost his deity status and
was expunged from the annals.
But the old God of War still
watches closely over his warriors.</text>
<text id="441">Online play item.
Purple crystal inhabited by spirits.

Spirits soar to seek enemies from other worlds,
conforming to the target's color.

Can be used three times,
then regenerated with rest at a bonfire.
What stuff is it that in the purple crystal resides?
Perhaps cinders of Undead, sacrificed to the bonfire.
Or perhaps the vengeful spirits of those
who fell to foes from distant worlds.</text>
<text id="450">A blue berry emitting a faint magic.
Temporarily boosts magic/fire defence.

When the magic contained in
the berry permeates the body,
it protects the user from magic and fire.</text>
<text id="451">A yellow berry emitting a faint magic.
Temporarily boosts dark/lightning defence.

When the magic contained in
the berry permeates the body, 
it protects the user from dark and lightning.</text>
<text id="453">A tiny bug that produces light.
Brightbugs are said to comfort the dead,
and are found in the marshlands
leading to the Undead Crypt.

By ingesting a brightbug just before death,
the moment at which they glow most brightly,
one attains great power for a short time.
Often utilized as a last-resort for
adventurers who have lost their way.

Has no effect in other worlds or for phantoms.</text>
<text id="501">Offering an ember to a body without flame
increases HP as well as abilities.

What remains of an ashen hero
once the fire has gone out?
Honor or ruin?</text>
<text id="1010">Dragon scale for reinforcing dragon weapons.
Peeled from an ancient dragon.

A dragon is inseparable from its scales,
and the transcendent apostles,
who seek the perpetuity of the ancient dragons,
have crossed the very end of the earth
to seek this invaluable treasure.</text>
<text id="2003">Key to the inner part of the bridge.

Beyond the great bridge that couldn't possibly
have been made by human hand,
hides a mystery that has yet to be discovered.
Some say that the realm of God awaits, but others…</text>
<text id="2004">Crest opening the way to Fort Faran,
home to the Undead Corps.

Passed down to cursed undead warriors,
the stench of death still lingers.

Perhaps Freise of Vinheim will have some use for it…</text>
<text id="2101">Sinister vessel made from the skull of a noble king.

Placed on the altar within the catacombs,
but its origins are unclear.

An ominous air emits from the chalice,
gripping the hearts of those who peer at it
as if determined to drag them to the world of the dead.</text>
<text id="2121">A sacred braille tome of sunlight,
written for warriors of the sun covenant.

Give it to a storyteller to learn sun miracles.

Knights of the sunlight covenant are brilliantly
beaming co-operators who volley lightning,
and hand out medals before
disappearing into the sunset.</text>
<text id="2136">Ruined finger of Dark Sun Gwyndolin.

The young crossbreed girl loved her brother,
of whom all that remains is this ruined finger.

Even so, her love for him will never falter…</text>
<text id="620">Proof of a pact, employed by the Judicator Giant.
Briefly summons the eccentric Silver Knight Ledo.

Most bound by the Judicator's pact are
not willing but rather impelled.
Yet a rare few are linked to the giant by mutual friendship.

This is a precious corroboration of such amiability,
and the only one that manifested in physical form.</text>
</entries>