<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="1200000">Variation of Soul Arrow developed
by sorcerers of the Undead Legion of Farron.

Fire a soul dart.

Well known among the Farron sorceries,
it is learned far and wide due to its ease of use.</text>
<text id="1210000">Sorcery which improves upon Farron Dart.
Fires a more powerful soul dart.

Entrusted to the leader of the Legion's acolytes,
and apparently a sorcery of his daughter, Heysel,
that was refined by a Crystal Sage.</text>
<text id="1300000">Elementary sorcery.
Fires a soul arrow.

To use sorceries, equip a staff
and attune a sorcery at a bonfire.</text>
<text id="1301000">Sorcery which improves upon Soul Arrow.
Fires a more powerful soul arrow.

Many sorceries inflict magic damage,
making them effective against iron armor,
tough scales, and other physically resilient materials.</text>
<text id="1302000">Elementary, yet practical sorcery from long ago.
Fires a heavy soul arrow.

Offers greater power but slower casting time,
entailing a vulnerability that makes
this sorcery trickier to handle.</text>
<text id="1303000">Sorcery which improves upon Heavy Soul Arrow.
Fires a more powerful heavy soul arrow.

Sorceries are a logical discipline;
their strength influenced by the caster's intelligence.</text>
<text id="1304000">Sorcery developed by Big Hat Logan,
the great sorcerer who left
the Dragon School in an age long past.

Releases a homing soulmass.

This sorcery may offer a clue as to what Logan sought,
but further investigation suggests its attraction to
living things mirrors the nature of the dark.</text>
<text id="1305000">Sharpens Homing Soulmass via crystallization.

Releases a homing crystal soulmass.
Crystal soulmass has piercing qualities.

According to the Crystal Sages,
old Big Hat achieved enlightenment
within the Regal Archives,
where he came to find the quintessence of
sorcery in the facets of a certain crystal.</text>
<text id="1306000">Sorcery developed by Big Hat Logan,
the great sorcerer who left the Dragon School
in an age long past.

Fires a soul spear.

The spear boasts superior penetrating power,
and is testament to Logan's strength in battle,</text>
<text id="1307000">Further sharpens Soul Spear via crystallization.

Fires a piercing crystal soul spear.


According to the Crystal Sages,
old Big Hat achieved enlightenment
within the Regal Archives,
where he came to find the quintessence of
sorcery in the facets of a certain crystal.</text>
<text id="1308000">Sorcery of Archdeacon Royce and his deacons,
said to have been imparted to them
by McDonnell of the Boreal Valley.

Fires dark soul dregs.

Souls which swell from the deep pursue their target,
drawn towards life.</text>
<text id="1309000">Sorcery which improves upon Deep Soul.
Fires powerful darkened soul dregs.

Archdeacon McDonnell, a sorcerer himself,
delighted in the cathedral's stagnating souls.
For him, they represented
the glorious bedrock of this world.</text>
<text id="1310000">Sorcery for casters who wield swords.
Reinforces right weapon with magic.

The power of the sorcerer-swordsmen of Vinheim
is predicated upon this and Magic Shield.
Many warriors learn sorcery just for this enchantment.</text>
<text id="1311000">Sorcery which improves upon Magic Weapon.
Greatly reinforces right weapon with magic.

Only sorcerer-swordsmen with special duties
are permitted the use of this spell.
The azure blade is said to cut down
heavily armored knights with ease.</text>
<text id="1312000">Further sharpens Magic Weapon via crystallization.
Reinforces right weapon with crystal.

After much experimentation,
Logan found the crystal medium facilitated
a stronger bond between weapon and soul.</text>
<text id="1330000">Sorcery for casters who wield swords.
Reinforces left shield with magic.

Shields augmented by magic have
higher stability and damage absorption.

Even the smallest of shields can be
toughened considerably with the use of this spell.</text>
<text id="1331000">Sorcery which improves upon Magic Shield.
Greatly reinforces left shield with magic.

Only sorcerer-swordsmen with special duties
are permitted the use of this spell,
which temporarily grants even the smallest of
shields fortitude more akin to that of a greatshield.</text>
<text id="1340000">Lost sorcery from Oolacile,
land of ancient golden sorceries.
Turns right weapon invisible.

The weapon itself undergoes no inherent changes.
Effective use of this, like any tool, perhaps,
is reliant upon the ingenuity of its caster.</text>
<text id="1341000">Lost sorcery from Oolacile,
land of ancient golden sorceries.
Turns body nigh on invisible.

Although perfect invisibility is
unachievable due to the risk of dissipation,
the caster need only stand still for a moment
to blend in to environs with astounding camouflage.</text>
<text id="1350000">Lost sorcery from Oolacile,
land of ancient golden sorceries.
Casts a light to illuminate surroundings.

This light-producing magic is
elementary but nonetheless demonstrates
the pure nature of golden sorceries;
the likes of which have not been
developed even at the Dragon School.</text>
<text id="1353000">Lost sorcery from Oolacile,
land of ancient golden sorceries.

Repairs equipped weapons and armor.
Includes weapons with exhausted durability.

While the effects of this spell are rather subtle,
its foundations are a well-guarded secret.
Light is time, and the reversal of
its effects is a forbidden art.</text>
<text id="1354000">Sorcery developed by a certain surreptitious sorcerer
at Vinheim Dragon School.

Masks noises of the caster and prevents fall damage.

Their mastery of this sorcery alone allows Vinheim
spooks to demand handsome payment for their services. </text>
<text id="1355000">Lost sorcery from Oolacile,
land of ancient golden sorceries.
Transforms into something inconspicuous.

Far from formally developed,
this magic was instead born from the mischief
of a young girl who sought relief from
the solitude of the woods at dusk.</text>
<text id="1356000">Sorcery developed by a certain surreptitious sorcerer
at Vinheim Dragon School.

Distracts foes with a distant sound.

The sound carries with it a strangely infectious resonance
that may cause one to stray from
their post and expose their back.</text>
<text id="1370000">Sorcery of the deluded Consumed King Oceiros.

Emits crystal breath of Seath the Scaleless.
Crystal breath has piercing qualities.

Seath's research seemed to strike
a chord with old Big Hat who,
in his mad, disrobed state,
made divine works such as this, his own.
Oceiros was no doubt edified by this.</text>
<text id="1372000">Sorcery which improves upon Farron Dart.
Fires a cascade of soul darts.

Entrusted to the leader of the Legion's acolytes,
and apparently a sorcery of his daughter, Heysel,
that was refined by a Crystal Sage.</text>
<text id="1373000">Unique sorcery developed by extraordinary
preacher twins known as the Crystal Sages.

Casts a cascade of small crystal soulmasses from above. Crystal soulmasses have piercing qualities.

In a pact said to have been formed long ago,
one of the Sages allied with the Undead Legion
in order to train the sorcerers of Farron.</text>
<text id="1374000">Sorcery developed primarily for sorcerer-swordsmen.
Attacks with a greatsword formed from souls.

The ephemeral blade only exists as
an extension of the caster,
but its power is said to rival
that of physical greatswords.
Even the most obstinate magic purists may
resort to this spell in times of crisis.</text>
<text id="1375000">Alteration of Soul Greatsword developed by sorcerers
of the Undead Legion of Farron.

The Legion has a tendency
to emphasize speed over power,
and this practical alteration of
an existing sorcery is no exception.</text>
<text id="1603000">A forbidden dark sorcery.
Casts a dark manifestation of humanity.

It appears to be an expression of envy,
or perhaps love towards another,
that will tenaciously pursue its target.
Even if, like so many human desires,
it amounts to nothing but misfortune.</text>
<text id="1613000">A forbidden dark sorcery.
Strikes with blade formed of humanity's darkness.

Passed from mother to daughter,
this blade was intended for both protection
and as a means of taking one's own life.
The young girl never swung it more than once.</text>
<text id="1620000">Sorcery imparted by the first of the Scholars,
when Lothric and the Grand Archives were but young.

Fires a torrential volley of souls.

The first of the Scholars doubted the linking of the fire,
and was alleged to be a private mentor to the Royal Prince.</text>
<text id="1651000">Lost sorcery from Oolacile,
land of ancient golden sorceries.
Distorts light in order to deflect magic.

A closely-guarded light manipulation spell
that contorts the very fabric of fundamental laws,
negating magic by denying its claim to physicality.</text>
<text id="1740000">Highly dangerous sorcery employed by
Dragon School spooks.
Only taught to trusted members.

Releases dense mist that eats away at HP.
Beware, as the caster is not immune to its effect.

A body caught in the silent mist cloud lies still,
while the face twists in a tortured scream.
The names of these learned sorcerers became feared
for this gruesome spectacle.</text>
<text id="2400000">Elementary pyromancy that is often the first learned.
Hurls a fireball.

To use pyromancies, equip a pyromancy flame
and attune a pyromancy at a bonfire.</text>
<text id="2402000">The signature flame-manipulating spell
common to pyromancers.
Hurls a giant fire orb.

The blazing fire orb explodes on impact,
dealing fire damage to the surrounding area.

They say that once a pyromancer learns this spell,
their understanding of the flame deepens,
together with a yearning for it.</text>
<text id="2403000">Primal pyromancy taught by Quelana,
a daughter of the Witch of Izalith.

Surrounds the caster with multiple pillars of flame.

The raging storm is indiscriminate;
such is the intrinsic horror of the flame.</text>
<text id="2405000">Pyromancy of Cornyx of the Great Swamp.
Emits a constant stream of fire.

Cornyx is a venerable pyromancer of an older mold,
said to have restored a number
of spells lost to the past,
amongst which this is the most well-known.</text>
<text id="2407000">Pyromancy discovered from the Abyss by High Lord Wolnir
that inspired the black arts of the grave wardens.

Releases undulating black flames that trace the ground.

Be it sorcery or pyromancy,
all techniques that infringe on
humanity lead to the same place.
That is to say, they all seek a will of their own.</text>
<text id="2411000">Pyromancy which improves upon Combustion.
Creates a powerful, giant flame in hand.

A very powerful, yet simple spell to use.

Pyromancy is to at once know fear and longing,
the resultant power of which depends on
both the caster's intelligence and faith.</text>
<text id="2420000">Unique pyromancy crafted by Eingyi,
a heretic inhabiting the Great Swamp long ago.
Creates a poison mist.

Eingyi was driven from the Great Swamp,
however his pyromancy continues to succeed him.

Perhaps dwellers of the Great Swamp
were reminded that their very existence
is one rooted in heresy.</text>
<text id="2421000">Unique pyromancy of Eingyi that
never gained currency in the Great Swamp.

Creates an intense poison mist.

Driven from the Great Swamp,
they say that at the end of his journey,
Eingyi happened upon a virulent poison and a young lady.</text>
<text id="2422000">Pyromancy of Carthus of the Sands.
Emits an acid which corrodes weapons and armor.

Carthus' swordsmen attached great value to victory,
and would not shun the use of such pyromancies.
For where is the honor in death and scoured bones?</text>
<text id="2430000">Pyromancy that internalizes flame.

Iron flesh boosts damage absorption and resistance,
but significantly increases weight.

Not advisable for walking in marshlands,
perhaps resulting in its obsolescence in the Great Swamp.</text>
<text id="2431000">Unique pyromancy of the Great Swamp associated
with Carmina.

Intense sweating increases fire damage absorption.

An influential pyromancy that internalizes flame,
likely forming the foundation for many subsequent spells.</text>
<text id="2435000">Pyromancy of Carthus of the Sands.
Reinforces right weapon with flame.

Warriors of Carthus favored
supplemental pyromancies such as this,
which was used to enhance
the curved blades of its swordsmen.</text>
<text id="2436000">Advanced pyromancy of Quelana,
a daughter of the Witch of Izalith.

Charms the enemy, making them a temporary ally.

The living are lured by flame,
and this tendency is elemental
to the art of pyromancy.</text>
<text id="2440000">Forbidden pyromancy amongst those who internalize flame.

Temporarily boosts attack, but gradually lose HP.

A pyromancer fears the flame.
However, this fear subsides once it is
accepted as a substitute for strength.</text>
<text id="2450000">Art of the Flame of Chaos, from Ancient Izalith.
Hurls a great chaos fire orb.

Chaotic flame melts even great boulders,
and creates a brief surge of molten lava on impact. 

The Witch of Izalith and her daughters
birthed the Flame of Chaos,
but it devoured them along with their home.</text>
<text id="2451000">Art of the Flame of Chaos, from Ancient Izalith.
Erects multiple chaos fire pillars in vicinity.

Chaotic flame melts even great boulders,
and creates a brief surge of molten lava on impact. 

The all-engulfing Chaos Flame eventually
formed a tumultuous seedbed,
which birthed the twisted things known as Demons.</text>
<text id="2452000">Primal pyromancy taught by Quelana,
daughter of the Witch of Izalith.
Sweeps foes with a fire whip.

The caster manipulates the flames at will,
making this an extremely difficult spell to use.

Pyromancy is at once the knowledge
of controlling flame,
and the knowledge that control is impossible.</text>
<text id="2453000">Pyromancy discovered by grave wardens
after High Lord Wolnir fell to the Abyss.

Creates a giant, black flame in hand

Black flames born from the Abyss bear no shadow.
They are said to be the impenetrable fires of humanity.</text>
<text id="2455000">Pyromancy deriving from the Profaned Flame.

Engulfs foes at range and burns them to ashes.

The Profaned Capital was consumed by fire
after Yhorm the Giant became a Lord of Cinder.
The fire, born of the sky,
is said to have incinerated naught but human flesh.</text>
<text id="2456000">Traces of the tumultuous seedbed that birthed
the beings known as Demons.

Hurls chaos flame that scorches vicinity.

Demons born from fire bore its smoldering essence
and perished soon after.
Man shares this rapport with the flames to this day.</text>
<text id="2470000">Peculiar pyromancy of the Mound-makers.
Creates a gentle flame that restores HP on touch.

They feared separation from the gods
and sought a familial bond,
perhaps leading to the creation of this flame of harmony.</text>
<text id="2562000">Advanced pyromancy that internalizes flame,
associated with Carmina.

Profuse sweating temporarily boosts resistance
to bleeding, poison, frost and curses.

The yellowish sweat cures all kinds of ailments.</text>
<text id="2610000">Pyromancy discovered by grave wardens
after High Lord Wolnir fell to the Abyss.

Hurls a black fireball.

The black flame inflicts dark damage,
striking targets with weighty force.</text>
<text id="2620000">Pyromancy of old restored by Cornyx.
One of the Great Swamp's more advanced spells.

Hurls an exploding fireball.

A rare technique that undergoes change
after leaving the caster's hand,
making this a spell renowned for its difficulty.</text>
<text id="2630000">Art of a stray demon of stifled flame.

Spews a boulder from one's mouth.

The boulder is heavy, but shatters easily.</text>
<text id="2640000">Pyromancy taught amongst savages.
Flame burrows inside foes and ignites.

Originally used in a ceremony
for cleansing sacrificial impurities,
thereby lending the spell its name.

As barbaric as it seems,
this may in fact be quite fitting
for the savage pyromancers who consider
themselves servants of the divine.</text>
<text id="2650000">The most obscure pyromancy developed
in Carthus of the Sands.

Damage increases with consecutive attacks.

Carthus's aggression has been
likened to an uncontrollable fire,
and since ancient times its beacon
has been used as a signal for war.</text>
<text id="3490000">Miracle imparted as charity to those of little faith.
A show of tolerance from the Way of White.

Slightly restores HP.

To use miracles, equip a talisman or sacred chime
and attune a miracle at a bonfire.</text>
<text id="3500000">Elementary miracle cast by clerics.
Restores HP for self and those in the vicinity.

To use miracles, equip a talisman or sacred chime
and attune a miracle at a bonfire.</text>
<text id="3501000">Miracle superior to Heal.
Restores moderate HP for self and those in the vicinity.

Miracles are fruit of the study of divine tales,
a blessing received from the gods through acts of prayer.
Miracle strength depends on the caster's faith.</text>
<text id="3502000">Glorious miracle used by high-ranking clerics.
Restores a large amount of HP for self
and those in the vicinity.

Only a select few have learned to
recite this epic tale in its entirety,
but those who do are amply rewarded. </text>
<text id="3503000">Special miracle granted to the maidens
of the Princess of Sunlight.

Restores a large amount of HP for self
and those in the general area.

The miracles of Gwynevere,
the princess cherished by all,
bestow their blessing on a great many warriors.</text>
<text id="3504000">Miracle once cherished by cleric knights.
Gradually restores HP.

Replenishment is a relic of the old Lloyd faith,
whose cleric knights were unfaltering in battle.</text>
<text id="3505000">Special miracle granted by the Princess of Sunlight.

Gradually restores a large amount of HP
for self and those in the vicinity.

The miracles of Gwynevere,
loved as both mother and wife bestow
their blessing on a great many warriors.</text>
<text id="3507000">Miracle taught to knights by Gertrude,
holy maiden to the Queen.

Gradually restores a large amount of HP.

The Heavenly Daughter is said to be
the Queen's child.</text>
<text id="3508000">Miracle taught by Morne, the Archbishop's apostle.

Cures bleeding, poison and frost for self
and those in the vicinity.

Caressing Tears is a tale of
the many deaths surrounding the goddess Caitha,
of whom Morne was a known follower.</text>
<text id="3520000">Miracle taught by Morne, the Archbishop's apostle.

Grants one chance to endure when HP reaches 0

Intended to grant the dying
a few moments for a final farewell.
Tears are shed for the sake of the living,
more so than the deceased.</text>
<text id="3521000">Miracle taught to traveling clerics.
Returns caster to the last bonfire used for resting, 
or to the bonfire in the shrine.

It would normally link to one's homeland,
only the curse of the Undead has twisted its power,
redirecting casters to a bonfire.
Perhaps for Undead, the bonfire serves as home.</text>
<text id="3530000">Elementary miracle among clerics.
Creates a shockwave.

While it inflicts no direct damage,
this miracle propels foes back, staggering them.
Can also defend against incoming arrows.</text>
<text id="3531000">Primal form of Force.
Creates a powerful shockwave.

Wrath of the Gods is an epic tale,
while Force is but a woefully
incomplete version of that yarn.

This primal account of profound fury
emits a shockwave that also inflicts damage.</text>
<text id="3532000">Traditional miracle of Catarina.
Releases a shockwave in front.

The people of lands known for festivity
and drink are typically outspoken.
One can be sure that they will not
bottle their emotions,
instead venting anger and the like with confidence.</text>
<text id="3540000">Miracle of stray souls.
Displays more help from other worlds and
reveals summon signs without using an ember.

Faith serves as a guide for clerics,
meaning they should have no need for secondhand wisdom.

Be that as it may,
this miracle has been passed down from soul to soul,
providing a tiny ray of hope for the lost.</text>
<text id="3550000">Miracle allegedly used by Warriors of Sunlight.

Hurls a lightning spear.

The spears inflict lightning damage,
providing an effective counter to magic or fire.
Especially powerful against metal armor and dragons.</text>
<text id="3551000">Primal account of Lightning Spear,
which tells of an ancestral dragonslayer.

Hurls a giant lightning spear.

Gwyn, the First Lord,
slew dragons with his sunlight spear,
a tradition upheld by his firstborn
and the greatspear he wielded.

Much of this resplendent tale of father and son,
while epic, remains tragically untold. </text>
<text id="3552000">Miracle of Gwyn, the First Lord.
Hurls a sunlight spear.

The tales of Gwyn's Archdragon hunts
describe the inception of the Age of Fire.</text>
<text id="3553000">Miracle of the Nameless King,
ally to the ancient dragons.

Calls forth furious bolts of lightning.

Once a slayer of dragons,
the former king and war god tamed a Stormdrake,
on which he led a lifetime of battle.
This miracle is likely a tale of their bond.</text>
<text id="3554000">Dark miracle taught in the Cathedral of the Deep.

Summons insect swarm to feast on foes.

These insects which lurk in the Deep
have tiny jaws lined with fangs to
tear open the skin and burrow into the flesh
in the blink of an eye, causing intense bleeding.</text>
<text id="3555000">Miracle of Dorhys the deranged evangelist.

Summons great insect swarm to feast on foes.

Those who linger too long on the brink
of the Deep will often slip.
Dorhys is sure to have wallowed in this darkness,
intoxicated by its peril.</text>
<text id="3560000">Miracle of clerics who wield weapons.

Increases magic damage absorption by 
covering the body in a white protective coating.

There was a short period in history where
clerics and sorcerers opposed one another.
Thus it became necessary for even simple clerics
to have some means of opposing magic.</text>
<text id="3561000">The tale which was later interpreted as Magic Barrier.

Greatly increases magic damage absorption
by covering the body in a strong white protective coating.

Said to be a tale of Havel the Rock,
arch enemy of Seath the Scaleless.
Havel despised magic,
and was never complacent in preparing means to counter it.</text>
<text id="3563000">Miracle of those chosen by the Sunlight covenant.

Temporarily boosts attack and damage absorption
for self and those in the vicinity.

This is the tale of the Sun's firstborn,
his faithful first knight,
and the brave dragonslayer who served them both.</text>
<text id="3581000">Miracle of the Sable Church of Londor.

Prevents spells in vicinity, including one's own.

Members of the Sable Church
are all trained swordsmen,
each sworn only to their weapons
as they bear the leaden silence of Londor.</text>
<text id="3590000">Miracle allegedly wielded by a certain dragonslayer knight
in the Age of Gods.

Reinforces right weapon with lightning.

Tales of dragonslayers are now a rare thing,
told only in fragments and whispers in remote regions.</text>
<text id="3591000">Miracle of those who devoted themselves
to the Darkmoon covenant.

Reinforces right weapon with Darkmoon light.

Miracles of the Darkmoon are tales of revenge,
but Captain Yorshka recites only for
the sake of remembering her brother,
without knowledge of its meaning.

Perhaps this is better,
as revenge is better left to the Blades.</text>
<text id="3640000">Miracle of the Sable Church of Londor.

Reinforces right weapon with dark.

The third daughter Liliane,
one of the founders of the Sable Church,
is said to recount tales that portray
the suffering and conflict of Hollows.</text>
<text id="3700000">Sacrilegious miracle of the Sable Church of Londor.

Bless corpses, transforming them into traps.

Londor, the Hollow Realm, is a society of undead,
comprised of the corpses and shades
of those who led unsavory lives.
Is such blessing really something one must ponder?</text>
<text id="3710000">A lost dragonslaying miracle.

Strikes with a stake of lightning.

This tale describes the lost practices
of ancient dragonslayers,
who found that in order to pierce dragonscale,
lightning should not be hurled as a bolt,
but rather be thrust as a stake directly into
the dragon's hide, to be truly effective.</text>
<text id="3720000">Miracle of Gertrude, the Heavenly Daughter.

Brings down multiple pillars of light in vicinity.

The Queen's holy maiden Gertrude was visited by an angel,
who revealed this tale to her.

Despite losing both her sight and her voice,
she was determined to record the tale.
Ordinary men cannot decipher her fragmentary scrawl,
nor comprehend how it became the foundation
of the Angelic faith of Lothric.</text>
<text id="3730000">Miracle of Aldrich, Devourer of Gods.

Steals HP of foes using an illusory scythe.

Aldrich dreamt as he slowly devoured
the God of the Darkmoon.
In this dream, he perceived the form of
a young, pale girl in hiding.</text>
<text id="3760000">Miracle taught to Lothric Knights.

Blesses right weapon, increasing attack power,
as well as gradually restoring HP.

The Knight is one of the Three Pillars of Lothric,
said to have strengthened ties with the High Priestess
after the Scholars acquired the Grand Archives.</text>
<text id="3770000">Miracle taught to inaugurated deacons
of the Cathedral of the Deep.

Slightly boosts attack, damage absorption and resistance,
while also increasing stamina recovery speed.

The Deep was originally a peaceful and sacred place,
but became the final rest
for many abhorrent things.
This tale of the Deep offers protection
for those who worship amidst those horrors.</text>
<text id="3780000">Miracle given to those cast out
from the Sable Church of Londor.

Attracts more attention from foes.

This is the only tale known by the exiles,
who believe it carries words of forgiveness.
Cursed journeys, too, must ultimately come to an end.</text>
<text id="1313000">One of the spells left behind by the young sorcerer Sulyvahn
before leaving the Painted World.
Imbues right-hand weapon with frost.

Sulyvahn was born and raised inside the painting,
yet had little use for his frigid homeland,
since he had not yet experienced loss.</text>
<text id="1741000">One of the spells left behind by the young sorcerer Sulyvahn
before leaving the Painted World.
Creates a cloud of near-freezing mist.

Sulyvahn was born and raised inside the painting,
yet had little use for his frigid homeland,
since he had not yet experienced loss.</text>
<text id="2457000">Pyromancer Dunnel was fascinated
by this ceremonial art employed
by the clerics of the Smouldering Lake.

Summons a fire-spitting chaos orb.

Chaos burns away in the blink of an eye,
but was the primordial life born in the Bed of Chaos,
and a grievous symbol of Izalith's sin.</text>
<text id="3556000">A lost Way of White miracle.
Launches a white discus which slices
into foes and returns to its conjurer.

Long ago, when the imprints left
by the gods were still deep,
miracles of the Way of White existed alongside aureoles.

Those who yearned for the long-lost aureoles
fully believed that they would return, one day.</text>
<text id="1376000">A memory of an old sword found deep within Midir.
This sorcery uses souls to grant form
to the thought, and attack with it.

Attacks are coupled with lightwaves,
and sustaining the stance before attacking
increases their speed and potency.

The sword is named after moonlight,
but it is slightly different than the one
fashioned of the paledrake Seath.
Perhaps it is rooted in an older memory,
from not long after the Beginning.</text>
<text id="1604000">A sorcery that fires great dark soul dregs
that have stewed for ages, far within the deep.

This sorcery is the highest form of Deep Soul.

Some of the murkmen who rise from the depths
are possessed by soul dregs,
which have a grave likeness to the human form.</text>
<text id="2458000">Pyromancy of Zoey, descendant of the desert pyromancers.

Use repeatedly to brush the fan of flame left and right.

Zoey possessed true beauty,
as did all the desert pyromancers,
but hers did not poison,
and so she became the unassuming queen of the feeble ones. </text>
<text id="2660000">The last flame lit by the demon prince.
This pyromancy hurls a clump of chaos.

Upon impact, this clump of chaos seethes wildly,
condenses briefly, then explodes violently.

To the demons, these clumps are shreds of life.</text>
<text id="3509000">The few female knights who served in
the age of the gods used this miracle for dragonslaying.

Draw lightning bow to fire a lightning arrow.

The lightning arrows offer a great improvement
to the range of spears,
and were said to have been used to
pierce the eyes of dragons from afar.
But remember, beautiful stories
are always marked by embellishment.</text>
<text id="3557000">A miracle discovered in the last days of Lothric.
Toss a light that heals those near the point of impact.

Even those who had forgotten the caress and bounty
of the Princess of Sunlight did their best
to recall her image. The stories spun about her
were most certainly childish, and yet gravely sincere.</text>
<text id="3513000">A micracle that causes distress
only to those that have turned hollow.

To hollows, there is no greater affliction
than the temptation of death.
To them, this agony transcends imagination.</text>
<text id="3750000">Dark miracle taught at the Cathedral of the Deep;
imparted by the mentor Dorris before she lost her mind.

Summon a swarm of insects that nestles within foes.

The insects bore completely through the body
before continuing to erode everything in the vicinity.</text>
</entries>