<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="20000">A generations-old ring set with a small red jewel.
Raises maximum HP.

Rings have unique powers,
and their discovery will do much
to ease a wearisome journey.</text>
<text id="20010">This old ring is named for its decorative green
blossom, but its luster is long since faded.

Raises stamina recovery speed.</text>
<text id="20020">A ring for warriors keen on heavy accoutrements.
Increases maximum equip load.

This ring was named after Havel the Rock,
the battlefield compatriot of Gwyn, the First Lord.

The art of war has been a constant since ages past,
and those who would follow in Havel's footsteps
are no fewer now than in his own day.</text>
<text id="20030">A ring symbolizing the favor of the Goddess Fina,
whose "fateful beauty" is mentioned in legend.

True to the fickle nature of Fina's favor,
her ring increases max HP, stamina,
and maximum equip load.</text>
<text id="20040">Ring of the Knight King of ancient legend.
Increases physical damage absorption.

The Knight King was said to be
lined with steel on the inside,
such that even the talons of
mighty dragons did him little harm.</text>
<text id="20050">Stoneplates are symbols of true knights,
and red stoneplates are granted to those
who valiantly face Chaos.

Increases fire damage absorption.</text>
<text id="20060">Stoneplates are symbols of true knights,
and yellow stoneplates are granted to
those who would become dragons.

Increases lightning damage absorption.</text>
<text id="20070">Stoneplates are symbols of true knights,
and blue stoneplates are granted to
the royal palace guards.

Increases magic damage absorption.</text>
<text id="20080">Stoneplates are symbols of true knights,
and dark purple stoneplates are granted to
Undead knights.

Increases dark damage absorption.</text>
<text id="20090">Stoneplates are symbols of true knights,
and speckled stoneplates are granted to
those who face an endless journey.

Slightly increases magic, lightning, fire
and dark damage absorption.</text>
<text id="20100">One of the bite rings native to Carim.
Increases bleed resistance.

The crafting of these rings is forbidden,
perhaps owing to a fear of malleable stone.
Clerics, however, dabble freely in the art.</text>
<text id="20110">One of the bite rings native to Carim.
Increases poison resistance.

The crafting of these rings is forbidden,
perhaps owing to a fear of malleable stone.
Clerics, however, dabble freely in the art.</text>
<text id="20120">One of the bite rings native to Carim.
Increases curse resistance.

The crafting of these rings is forbidden,
perhaps owing to a fear of malleable stone.
Clerics, however, dabble freely in the art.</text>
<text id="20130">One of the bite rings native to Carim.
Raises poison, bleed, frost and curse resist.

The crafting of these rings is forbidden,
perhaps owing to a fear of malleable stone.
Clerics, however, dabble freely in the art.</text>
<text id="20140">This special ring crafted in an Eastern land is made of metal,
but with a wood grain crest on its surface.
Slows equipment degradation.

Wielders of swords originating in the same region
follow a practice of inscribing special words
on the blades of their swords,
and are naturally drawn to this ring.</text>
<text id="20150">A ring engraved with a portrait of a scholar.
Increases intelligence.

In Lothric, the Scholar has long been considered
one of the Three Pillars of the king's rule,
and is therefore master of the Grand Archives.</text>
<text id="20160">A ring engraved with a portrait of the High Priestess.
Increases faith.

In Lothric, the High Priestess has long been
considered one of the Three Pillars of the king's rule.
The High Priestess also served as the prince's wet nurse.</text>
<text id="20170">A ring set with a large rare tearstone jewel.
Temporarily boosts attack when HP is low.

This stone is said to be a tear of mourning
of the goddess Caitha, and of course,
tears are always more beautiful near death.</text>
<text id="20180">A ring set with a large rare tearstone jewel.
Temporarily boosts damage absorption when HP is low.

This stone is said to be a tear of sorrow
of the goddess Caitha, and of course,
tears are always more beautiful near death.</text>
<text id="20190">Ring associated with Abysswalker Artorias,
one of the Four Knights of Gwyn, the First Lord.

Increases poise.

Artorias had an unbendable will of steel,
and was unmatched with a greatsword.</text>
<text id="20200">Ring associated with Dragon Slayer Ornstein,
one of the Four Knights of Gwyn, the First Lord.

Strengthens thrust weapon counter attacks.

Ornstein was the first knight of the sun's eldest born,
and his cross spear is said to
have pierced scales made of stone.</text>
<text id="20210">This mystical ring was created in a sacrificial rite of
Velka, the Goddess of Sin.

Its wearer will lose nothing upon death,
but the ring itself breaks.

A sacrifice is only worth as much as the life it spares.</text>
<text id="20230">Ring given in Vinheim, home of sorcery,
when newly ordained as a sorcerer.

Boosts sorceries.

Apropos to the Dragon School,
the seal depicts an everlasting dragon.
A young dragon presages the great length
of the journey to mastery.</text>
<text id="20231">A special ring given to those who are deemed fit
to undertake the journey of discovery in Vinheim,
home of sorcery.

Greatly boosts sorceries.

Apropos to the Dragon School,
the seal depicts an everlasting dragon.
A bellowing dragon symbolizes the true nature
of the consummate sorcerer.</text>
<text id="20240">Ring said to be chiseled from the bone of
a flame salamander by blighted Pyromancers
living in the Great Swamp.

Boosts pyromancies.

It is believed that salamanders
are the descendants of demons,
born of the Chaos Flame,
from which Pyromancy is also said to have originated.</text>
<text id="20241">The Witch of Izalith and her daughters,
scorched by the Flame of Chaos,
taught humans the art of pyromancy
and offered them this ring.

Greatly boosts pyromancies.

Every pyromancer is familiar with the parable that
tells of the witches espousing the need to fear the flame,
and teaching the art of pyromancy to men in hopes
that they might learn to control it.</text>
<text id="20250">A malformed ring given to knights of Carim.

Boosts miracles.

Morne served the goddess Caitha
and later became an apostle of the Archbishop.
They labored together to provide comfort to the suffering.</text>
<text id="20251">Ring of the Sun's first born,
who inherited the light of Gwyn, the First Lord.

Greatly boosts miracles.

The Sun's first born was once a god of war,
until he was stripped of his stature
as punishment for his foolishness.
No wonder his very name
has slipped from the annals of history.</text>
<text id="20270">A special ring given to those who are deemed fit
to undertake the journey of discovery in Vinheim,
home of sorcery.

Extends length of spell effect.

Apropos to the Dragon School,
the seal depicts an everlasting dragon.
A lingering dragon symbolizes the true nature
of the consummate sorcerer.</text>
<text id="20280">A ring given to Farron's Undead Legion
by one of the preacher twins,
known more commonly as the Crystal Sages.

Shortens spell casting time.

The sorcerers of Farron's Abyss Watchers
were known to be lonesome warriors
who would only rely upon more pragmatic spells.</text>
<text id="20290">Ring of a clandestine guild of sorcerers based in Vinheim,
home of sorcery.

Masks the sound of its wearer.

The Dragon School held effective sovereignty over Vinheim,
with a great many adept assassins at its disposal.</text>
<text id="20300">Leaf-colored crown ring bestowed
upon the princess of Oolacile,
ancient land of golden sorceries.

Reduces spell FP consumption, but also lowers HP.

Oolacile is synonymous for its lost sorceries,
of which the xanthous sorcerers are dedicated scholars.
This crown ring is a rare artifact of great magic heritage.</text>
<text id="20310">A ring bestowed upon a Carim saint.
Allows attunement of additional spells.

In Carim, the saints give voice to the ancient tales.
They memorize countless cumbersome sacred books
and read them in sonorous tones,
a function for which they are widely renowned.</text>
<text id="20320">A ring bestowed upon the Deacons of the Cathedral of the Deep.
Allows attunement of additional spells.

In the Cathedral slumber things most terrible,
and as such, the deacons require a grand narrative,
to ensure they do not falter in their duty.
A philosophy, to ward away the madness beckoned
by the grotesqueries at hand.</text>
<text id="20330">Ring of the moon deity Gwyndolin,
youngest son of Gwyn, the First Lord.

Adds many slots for attunement.

Gwyndolin, also known as the Dark Sun,
commands the Darkmoon Knights,
and bestows this ring upon the best of them.</text>
<text id="20370">Ring associated with Hawkeye Gough,
one of the Four Knights of Gwyn, the First Lord.

Extends the range of arrows.

In his later years, the giant Gough was blinded,
but this did not prevent him from striking down
a calamitous dragon with his Greatbow.</text>
<text id="20380">Ring associated with the Lord's Blade Ciaran,
one of the Four Knights of Gwyn, the First Lord.

Boosts critical attacks.

The masked Ciaran was the only woman
to serve in Gwyn's Four Knights,
and her curved sword granted a swift death
to any and all enemies of the throne.</text>
<text id="20390">A gold ring depicting a snake that could have been,
but never was, a dragon.
Fallen foes are more likely to drop items.

Snakes are known as creatures of great avarice,
devouring prey even larger than themselves
by swallowing them whole.

If one's shackles are cause for discontent,
perhaps it is time for some old-fashioned greed.</text>
<text id="20400">A silver ring depicting a snake that could have been,
but never was, a dragon.
Fallen foes yield more souls.

Snakes are known as creatures of great avarice,
devouring prey even larger than themselves
by swallowing them whole.

If one's shackles are cause for discontent,
perhaps it is time for some old-fashioned greed.</text>
<text id="20410">Ring associated with Gwynevere,
princess of sunlight and eldest daughter of
Gwyn, the First Lord.

The ring is vaguely warm, like a beam of sunlight,
and gradually restores HP.

Gwynevere left her home with a great many other deities,
and became a wife and mother,
raising several heavenly children.</text>
<text id="20420">Silver ring depicting a leaping feline.
Prevents damage from falling.

In the Age of Gods, or possibly just following it,
an old cat was said to speak a human tongue,
with the voice of an old woman,
and the form of a fanciful immortal.</text>
<text id="20430">One of Courland's transposed wonders.
Derived from the soul of a Soulfeeder.

Easier to be detected by enemies.

The Soulfeeder was a beast that
insatiably absorbed souls to feed its own power.
Even after its accursed corpse was burned,
it is said that the pungent stench of souls
left the air permanently stained.</text>
<text id="20440">One of the illusory rings worn by the Hollows of Londor.

Take the appearance of a phantom.

The Hollows of Londor are wretchedly aged,
fraught with deceit, and dubiously secretive.
It is no wonder that they are deeply detested.</text>
<text id="20450">Ring worn by warriors of the sand kingdom, Carthus.
Slightly boosts dexterity
and obscures the wearer while rolling.

The sword technique of Carthus allows for 
fluid movement with a curved sword.
Masters of the technique are said to
dazzle their opponents by moving
as weightlessly as a grain of sand.
They live for their High Lord Wolnir,
conqueror of most kingdoms known to their people.</text>
<text id="20460">Ring engraved with a portrait of a knight.
Increases strength.

In Lothric, the Knight has long been considered
one of the Three Pillars of the king's rule,
and were thus allowed to rear dragons.</text>
<text id="20470">Ring engraved with a portrait of a hunter.
Increases dexterity.

The hunters serve Lothric on the fringes and in the shadows.
For generations, rulers of Lothric have relied especially
upon the Black Hand hunters to punish enemies
in ways that the king's Three Pillars cannot.</text>
<text id="20480">Ring of the savage Tsorig,
more commonly known as the Knight Slayer.

Enemies lose more stamina when guarding attacks.

Long ago, Tsorig engaged the guardians
of an ancient city in a bloody confrontation,
and returned with their rings as his prize,
still frozen on their dismembered fingers.</text>
<text id="20490">Ring depicting a hand grasping a blue stone.
Increases magic attack,
but compromises damage absorption.

An old fable in Londor claims that the lure of
the clutch ring reaches out to the crestfallen,
who might otherwise be overcome by despair.</text>
<text id="20500">Ring depicting a hand grasping a yellow stone.
Increases lightning attack,
but compromises damage absorption.

An old fable in Londor claims that the lure of
the clutch ring reaches out to the crestfallen,
who might otherwise be overcome by despair.</text>
<text id="20510">Ring depicting a hand grasping a red stone.
Increases fire attack,
but compromises damage absorption.

An old fable in Londor claims that the lure of
the clutch ring reaches out to the crestfallen,
who might otherwise be overcome by despair.</text>
<text id="20520">Ring depicting a hand grasping a purple stone.
Increases dark attack,
but compromises damage absorption.

An old fable in Londor claims that the lure of
the clutch ring reaches out to the crestfallen,
who might otherwise be overcome by despair.</text>
<text id="20540">Ring of Flynn, the eulogized thief.
Lowering equip load increases attack power.

Flynn fought with the wind on his side,
and was a hero among the weak and poor,
yet even his admirers knew that
it was little more than an idyllic fable.</text>
<text id="20550">Portion of a steel chain used to restrain Gundyr.
Gain vigor, endurance, and vitality, but take extra damage.

A prisoner is one who has staked everything on a belief,
a proclivity most apparent in the greatest of champions.</text>
<text id="20560">One of the illusory rings worn by the Hollows of Londor.

Retain human appearance while Hollow.

The Hollows of Londor are wretchedly aged,
fraught with deceit, and dubiously secretive.
It is no wonder that they are deeply detested.</text>
<text id="20580">Ring bestowed upon the Fingers of Rosaria,
invaders who seek tongues for their goddess.

Hides the presence of the wearer when far away.

It is said that Rosaria, the mother of rebirth,
was robbed of her tongue by her firstborn,
and has been waiting for their return ever since.</text>
<text id="20590">This ring captured the foul spirit of an evil eye,
a creature that ravaged Astora.

Absorb HP from each defeated foe.

The horrid spirit nearly destroyed Astora,
but was eventually defeated by
"the sword of one most noble."</text>
<text id="20600">A ring made from the orange eye of a calamitous dragon.
Receive double damage.

This ring has no useful powers,
and is merely a symbol of dragon worship,
a thing quietly passed down
amongst its most fervent adherents,
some of whom become convinced the task
has been bestowed upon them as a sacred duty.</text>
<text id="20610">A ring given to Undead Legion of Farron.
Reduces Skill FP consumption.

The Abyss Watchers, for their hunting,
required a sword technique that
went beyond any existing art.
Wolf's blood provided just that,
and this ring further extends the effect.</text>
<text id="20620">A malformed ring left by Aldrich, Saint of the Deep.
Recovers HP from critical attacks.

Aldrich, infamous for his appetite for flesh,
apparently had the desire to share with others
his joy of imbibing the final shudders of life
while luxuriating in his victim's screams.</text>
<text id="20630">A malformed ring left by Aldrich, Saint of the Deep.
Recovers FP from critical attacks.

Aldrich, infamous for his appetite for flesh,
apparently had the desire to share with others
his joy of imbibing the final shudders of life
while luxuriating in his victim's screams.</text>
<text id="20660">Ring given to knights of the Way of White.
Depicts Allfather Lloyd's Sword of Law.

Boosts attack power when HP is full.

Much time has passed since the worship of Lloyd
was common in the Way of White.
The clerics of Carim had always strongly asserted that
Lloyd was a derivative fraud,
and that the Allfather title was self-proclaimed.</text>
<text id="20670">Ring given to knights of the Way of White.
Depicts Allfather Lloyd's Shield of Caste.

Boosts damage absorption when HP is full.

Much time has passed since the worship of Lloyd
was common in the Way of White.
The clerics of Carim had always strongly asserted that
Lloyd was a derivative fraud,
and that the Allfather title was self-proclaimed.</text>
<text id="20700">A green ring crafted from shards.
Increases HP restored by Estus Flask.

This ring was entrusted to a certain Fire Keeper,
but in the end she never met her champion,
and the ensuing tragic farce became
a favorite tale of the masses.</text>
<text id="20710">Gray crystalline ring crafted from shards.
Increases FP restored by Ashen Estus Flask.

Once a treasure brought before Lothric's Queen,
she had it enshrined in the Cemetery of Untended Graves,
so that one day an Unkindled might profit from its use.</text>
<text id="20720">An old ring with a seal depicting a horse's hoof.
Boosts kick effect.

Unbreakable Patches adored this ring and the feeling that
it gave it him when he kicked his marks
into the depths of treacherous traps,
but suffered no shortage of ridicule from his associates
for relying so heavily on the tired old trick.

But who is the sorrier? The horse who knows only to kick,
or the fool who approaches the old beast without thought?</text>
<text id="20730">Ring worn by warriors of the sand kingdom, Carthus.
Boosts rolling invincibility, at the cost of defense.

The sword technique of Carthus allows for
fluid movement with a curved sword.
Masters of the technique are said to dazzle their opponents
by moving as weightlessly as a grain of sand.
They live for their High Lord Wolnir,
conqueror of most kingdoms known to their people.</text>
<text id="20740">A divine ring granted to
the Darkmoon Gwyndolin in his youth.

Causes males to perform female actions,
and vice-versa.

Gwyndolin was raised like a daughter
through the aura of the moon,
and was said to behave like a sullen brooding goddess.</text>
<text id="20750">Bewitched ring that Pontiff Sulyvahn
bestowed upon his knights.

Boosts attacks, as long as attacking persists.

Knights who peer into the black orb
are lured into battles of death,
transformed into frenzied beasts.
No wonder the Pontiff only provides these rings
to those dispatched to foreign lands.</text>
<text id="20790">Bewitched ring that Pontiff Sulyvahn
bestowed upon his knights.

Recovers HP with successive attacks.

Knights who peer into the black orb
are lured into battles of death,
transformed into frenzied beasts.
No wonder the Pontiff only provides these rings
to those dispatched to foreign lands.</text>
<text id="20830">Ring of Oceiros, former king of Lothric.
Reduces damage from backstabs.

In his later years,
Oceiros became fascinated with dragons.
After going mad,
he was more commonly known as the Consumed King.
Many assassins were dispatched to his domain,
but none returned.

The Consumed King ascribed his resilience
to the divine protection of the dragon scale.</text>
<text id="21000">One of the bite rings native to Carim.
Increases frost resistance.

This ring would never grace Friede's hand,
for the painting and its frost became her home.</text>
<text id="20220">This mystical ring was created in a sacrificial rite of
Velka, the Goddess of Sin.
This magenta-shaded ring is especially rare.

Its wearer will lose nothing upon death,
and will be freed from any curse whatsoever,
but the ring itself breaks.

A sacrifice is only worth as much as the life it spares.</text>
<text id="20570">Ring of Sir Yorgh, who sought the blood
of a dragon and invaded Shulva.
Can deflect spells.

When Sir Yorgh faced Sinh, the slumbering dragon,
he drew blood with a flash of his steel,
but Sinh responded by spewing forth
the poison that had long brewed within him,
blanketing the city in a miasmic cloud.</text>
<text id="20690">Masks one's presence from adversaries.
Hides the wearer from Dark Spirits at a distance.

The wearer's presence is obscured,
concealing their very existence from invaders of that world.
However, if permitted to get close, the effect will fade.</text>
<text id="20760">Wearer's will to fight is converted into strength.
Boosts defense,
as long as attacking persists.

The unnatural ability of a late hero
dwells within this ring,
the use of which was permitted
to only a select and valiant few.</text>
<text id="20770">Wearer's will to fight is converted into strength.
Boosts stamina recovery speed,
as long as attacking persists.

The unnatural ability of a late hero
dwells within this ring,
the use of which was permitted
to only a select and valiant few.</text>
<text id="20780">Wearer's will to fight is converted into strength.
Boosts spells,
as long as attacking persists.

The unnatural ability of a late hero
dwells within this ring,
the use of which was permitted
to only a select and valiant few.</text>
<text id="20800">Wearer's will to fight is converted into strength.
Recovers FP with successive attacks.

The unnatural ability of a late hero
dwells within this ring,
the use of which was permitted
to only a select and valiant few.</text>
<text id="20810">Wearer's will to fight is converted into strength.
Adds extra damage with successive attacks.

The unnatural ability of a late hero
dwells within this ring,
the use of which was permitted
to only a select and valiant few.</text>
<text id="20820">Wearer's will to fight is converted into strength.
Increases drop rate with successive attacks.

The unnatural ability of a late hero
dwells within this ring,
the use of which was permitted
to only a select and valiant few.</text>
</entries>