<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="50600000">Key to the soldier's door in the Forest of
Fallen Giants.

A fort was erected in the forest to face the Giants,
but now the soldiers are lost and Hollowed.

They are enfeebled, but not without honor,
and continue to steadfastly defend their country.</text>
<text id="50610000">Key to the King's Passage,
inside Drangleic Castle.

King Vendrick tried all manner of things to
purge the curse that threatened his kingdom.

But when every last attempt failed,
the King fled through the King's Passage.</text>
<text id="50800000">Key to the cells of the Lost Bastille.

Long ago, a bastille lord, driven to desperation
by the rapid spread of curse across the land,
began to see each subject as a carrier of the
blight, and locked them away in droves.

This entire bastille was turned into a prison,
and left abandoned to rot with its prisoners.</text>
<text id="50810000">Key to the iron door of the Iron Keep.

The Old Iron King's castle sunk into a lake
of fire, weighed down by the castle's iron,
and the burden of the king's conceit.

Over the ages, the iron was stripped from
the castle by opportunistic passers-by.
The iron door, too, must be somewhere, far away.</text>
<text id="50820000">Key found in the Gutter.
Intricately designed, but of unknown origin.

All manner of terrible things have been
cast into the Gutter in Majula, forming a
settlement of filth and chaos.</text>
<text id="50830000">Key to Brightstone Cove Tseldora.

The eccentric Lord Tseldora, known for his
fascination with spiders, built a town and
a personal fortune by mining brightstone.

One day, the town was overrun by spiders,
but Lord Tseldora only stood by and watched,
eerily contented.</text>
<text id="50840000">This key is very old, but in very good
condition, such that it should still function.

Only, what lock does this key fit?</text>
<text id="50850000">A strange key shaped like a wild beast's fang.

What manner of dilettante would create such a
key, and what might it unlock?</text>
<text id="50860000">Key to the abandoned house in Majula.
Received from Cale the Cartographer.

In the past, Majula served as a dumping ground
for horrible things, but is now a gathering place
for those with no better place to go.

It seems this house in Majula was the final
home for a few such souls.</text>
<text id="50870000">Key of Blacksmith Lenigrast of Majula.

Majula, the land of exiles, is comprised of
abandoned old houses, one of which
Lenigrast has fashioned into a workshop.</text>
<text id="50880000">A perfectly smooth and silky stone.
Use to restore HP.

The shine of this stone is no ordinary polish,
and can only be achieved over a long period.
Some in this land are in search of such
mystical stones.</text>
<text id="50885000">A smooth and silky stone.
Use to slightly restore HP.

The shine of this stone is no ordinary polish,
and can only be achieved over a long period.
Some in this land are in search of such stones.</text>
<text id="50890000">A stone which rotates the Majula Rotunda.
Insert into the central pillar to align
the rotunda with a different passageway.

Nothing magical about it,
but a fine feat of engineering.</text>
<text id="50900000">Each king has his rightful throne.
And when he sits upon it,
he sees what he chooses to see.

Or perhaps, it is the throne,
which shows the king only what he wants.

The flames roar, but will soon begin to fade,
and only a worthy heir might burnish their light.
What is it, truly, a claimant of the throne
could desire?</text>
<text id="50910000">Manifestation of ashen mist
received from the ancient dragon.

The magic of the ancient dragon allows one
to delve into the memories of the withered.</text>
<text id="50920000">The soul of a Giant who came to conquer Drangleic.

Will the Giants' resentment for the King
be pacified in death, or only emboldened?

Can be used to acquire souls, only...</text>
<text id="50930000">Key to the den in Brightstone Cove Tseldora.

The fools that venture into Tseldora, unaware
of the ancient deeds that still haunt the cove,
are transfigured into unspeakable malformations.</text>
<text id="50940000">Online play item.
Shows the names of the greatest victors
of the Company of Champions covenant.

This tablet, chiseled from the Victor's Stone,
is engraved with the names of the brave warriors
who have offered the most awestones,
as if they were epitaphs, honoring their lives.</text>
<text id="50950000">A small ornamental ladder.
A quaint little thing, but only for show.

This ornament does not seem to have any
particular function, and should not be worth
much, but is sold at an exorbitant price.</text>
<text id="50960000">A vessel that will accept your souls.

It can allow reallocation of levels,
but without proper assistance,
it may simply drain you of souls.

If you truly wish to start again,
go to the place where your journey began.</text>
<text id="50970000">Key to the prison in the Huntsman's Copse.

The Undead hunts during the reign of
the Old Iron King took place in this forest,
and the cells in which the Undead were
held still stand there to this day.
However, the march of time has eroded
away any difference between the captors
and the captives.</text>
<text id="50990000">An ember radiating a dull light.

This flame seems nearly exhausted,
but exhibits an eerie resilience.
Perhaps this is its ordinary state?</text>
<text id="51000000">A crushed eye orb with an unfocused gaze.

The crushed eye writhes unsteadily,
in search of dishonorable miscreants.

Where are the fiends, where are they...</text>
<text id="51010000">A spice exuding a peculiar aroma.

A spell demands devotion from its caster,
but using this spice makes a chosen spell
attainable with 1 less intelligence. Will only
work with assistance from a certain person.

The spice does not raise one's intelligence,
but only obfuscates the requirement.</text>
<text id="51020000">A spice exuding a peculiar aroma.

A spell demands devotion from its caster,
but using this spice makes a chosen spell
attainable with 1 less faith. Will only
work with assistance from a certain person.

The spice does not raise one's faith,
but only obfuscates the requirement.</text>
<text id="51030000">Key used in the mansion of Aldia.

King Vendrick condemned his own
elder brother to the mansion.

They both sought the truth, but through
different means, and their fervor meant the
eventual withering of their familial ties.</text>
<text id="52000000">A terribly worn dragon talon.

Legend has it that in the deepest reaches
of the Black Gulch, behind a door locked
from the inside, is a magnificent city
built for a great slumbering dragon.

This talon clearly dates to ancient times,
but great vitality emanates from it still.</text>
<text id="52100000">A piece of iron shaped like a key.

Past the altar deep within the Iron Keep
and through a door is the tower that the
Old Iron King used to produce iron.

The unearthly weight of this chunk of
iron is a reminder of the Iron King's
own immeasurable strength.</text>
<text id="52200000">A stone ornament shaped like a flower.
Cold enough to dampen the greatest heat.

Opens the door to a new path from
the Shrine of Winter, found on the road
to the great castle.</text>
<text id="52300000">Key to the inner chamber of the Eternal Sanctum.

The Sunken King erected the
Eternal Sanctum to shelter Sinh the Dragon.

The Sanctum appears to be a solemn temple,
but it is filled with devilish creatures that
ensure no trespasser shall cause offense.</text>
<text id="52400000">Key that opens the door to Brume Tower.

Long ago, the tower used to produce
a seemingly endless supply of iron.
The King used it to create iron soldiers
and an iron castle. Legend has it he even
tried his hand at forging a dragon out of iron.</text>
<text id="52500000">Opens the Garrison Ward of Eleum Loyce.

The Garrison Ward was built to confine Chaos,
and Eleum Knights remain there today,
waiting for someone to lead
the advance on the swollen flame,
faithful to the King's final orders.</text>
<text id="52650000">An extremely solid stone.
Used to operate the Eternal Sanctum contraption.

The heirloom of a race that discovered
a dragon, worshipped its magnificence,
and perished by its side.</text>
<text id="53100000">A scorching-hot iron scepter.
Used to activate contraptions by
transferring heat to Brume Tower.

When the Old Iron King wrested this
dilapidated region from the kingdom
of Venn, the act required all the resources
the enfeebled lord could muster. But with the
discovery of this iron-producing miracle,
he was reborn as a powerful leader.</text>
<text id="53200000">An iron wedge forged in this land.
Destroys the ashen idol.

The ashen idol is of great consequence
to Nadalia, who, having renounced her flesh,
entrusts her very being to it.</text>
<text id="53300000">Soul of Nadalia, Bride of Ash, who renounced
her flesh and wandered Brume Tower.

When Nadalia came to this land,
the king she sought was no longer there.
Dispirited, she forsook her own soul
and clung to the heirlooms of the old king.

This is only a fragment of a soul,
and cannot be used in this state.</text>
<text id="53600000">The eye of the first priestess
who watched over Eleum Loyce.
Allows one to see the unseen.

All the great priestesses replaced
one of their birth eyes with this,
returning it after their term was complete.</text>
<text id="60010000">Small stone made up of crystallized souls.
Gradually restores a small amount of HP.

Often found near abandoned corpses,
as if it were what remains of the soul.</text>
<text id="60020000">Stone made up of crystallized souls.
Gradually restores HP.

The dull glimmer of these mysterious stones
brightens with the passage of time.</text>
<text id="60030000">Stone made up of crystallized souls.
Gradually restores a large amount of HP.

A rare stone with so brilliant a shine
would fetch a handsome price.
But what value could it really have,
without knowing who died to leave it behind?</text>
<text id="60035000">Specially treated dried mushroom.
Creates a euphoric sensation when ingested,
and restores a large amount of HP over time.

Saint Elizabeth devoted her life to helping the
needy by concocting medicine and potions.

It's thought her great virtue was matched only by
her sublime beauty, but who can say now?</text>
<text id="60036000">Root of a perennial herb native to the south.
Restores HP for an extended duration.

Wild animals abhor the pungent odor of this root,
but clerics on pilgrimage are keenly aware
of the value of its powerful medicinal effects.</text>
<text id="60040000">An annual herb with an amber color so deep,
it gives the impression of luminescence.
Restores a small number of spell uses.

It is the mistaken belief of many that the
flowers of this herb do not blossom. However,
small, white flowers do blossom during
dusk when the moon is visible.</text>
<text id="60050000">A gray herb that grows hidden among
the rocky surfaces of tall mountains.
Restores a number of spell uses.

There is no end to the scores of people who
risk life and limb to forage for this valuable
herb, which led to a banning of its harvest in
some regions.</text>
<text id="60060000">A wilted and faded stalk of dusk herb.
Restores a great deal of spell uses.

A dusk herb in bloom works wonders,
but will wilt in the blink of an eye.
Needless to say, finding such an herb
is of the utmost difficulty.</text>
<text id="60070000">A faintly poisonous clump of moss.
When ingested, it counteracts poison
and cleanses one's insides.

If enough poison builds up in the body to
break out and cause poisoning, your HP
will start to decrease.

If you wish to stay alive, you would do well
to keep a supply close to hand. </text>
<text id="60090000">A blessed charm.
Cures poison and restores HP.

Many such charms were blessed in
reconstructed ancient ceremonies, carried out
in the monastery of Lindelt, now known as
the new home of miracles.

Though it may lack the power of an original,
in circumstances dire enough,
an imitation can be quite enough.</text>
<text id="60100000">A blessed charm.
Cures poison and greatly restores HP.

A rare, ancient charm that is said
to be endowed with the power of dragons.
It is not clear whether it is a man-made
creation, or of some other nature.</text>
<text id="60105000">Holy water endowed with a divine blessing.
Cures status effects and fully restores HP.

Water blessed by an ancient goddess.
Her name is long forgotten, and the Magic
Academy of Melfia denies even her existence.

In any age, there are those who refuse
to see reason. It is their meddling that
distorts the truth.</text>
<text id="60110000">Crimson water of unknown origin.
Restores HP and spell uses.

Though known to some as red holy water,
not everyone acknowledges its holy status.</text>
<text id="60120000">Crimson water of unknown origin.
Greatly restores HP and spell uses.

Those who have experienced the powerful
effect of this dimly lucent red water care not
that its very origins are completely unknown.</text>
<text id="60151000">A warm, soft, shadow-like effigy.

Use this item to reverse Hollowing.
It also weakens the links to other worlds,
preventing invasions and most cooperation.

Peer closely at an effigy, and one begins
to perceive a human form, but whose form
it takes depends on the person looking.</text>
<text id="60155000">A green glass bottle of unknown make.
Fill it with Estus at a bonfire, and drink
from it to restore HP.

The nature of the link between the
Estus Flasks and the bonfires that illuminate
the world of the Undead is entirely unknown.

But that is of little concern, for any Undead
knows the value of these precious flasks.</text>
<text id="60160000">A small blue burr.
Temporarily boosts magic defense.

These burrs bloom magnificently on a shrub
every few years, their color and effect determined
by soil quality and recent weather.
Known to have been used in rituals long ago.</text>
<text id="60170000">A small yellow burr.
Temporarily boosts lightning defense.

These burrs bloom magnificently on a shrub
every few years, their color and effect determined
by soil quality and recent weather.
Known to have been used in rituals long ago.</text>
<text id="60180000">A small orange burr.
Temporarily boosts fire defense.

These burrs bloom magnificently on a shrub
every few years, their color and effect determined
by soil quality and recent weather.
Known to have been used in rituals long ago.</text>
<text id="60190000">Troches with an inexplicably pungent odor.
Temporarily boosts dark defense.

Verbal histories often mention Saint Elizabeth;
her uniquely concocted medicines and potions
are still widely used today.</text>
<text id="60200000">A spotted fruit.
Temporarily boosts poison resist.

This common fruit has no taste,
but when facing a true test of mettle,
its benefits could make the difference
between life and death. </text>
<text id="60210000">Troches with an oddly charred odor.
Temporarily boosts bleeding resist.

Verbal histories often mention Saint Elizabeth;
her uniquely concocted medicines and potions
are still widely used today.</text>
<text id="60230000">Troches that exude the scent of rust.
Temporarily boosts petrify resist.

Verbal histories often mention Saint Elizabeth;
her uniquely concocted medicines and potions
are still widely used today.</text>
<text id="60235000">A balm extracted from a rare plant.
Temporarily increases strength.

This special fragrant oil affects the mind,
granting a fleeting sense of empowerment.</text>
<text id="60236000">A balm extracted from a rare plant.
Temporarily increases dexterity.

This special fragrant oil affects the mind,
granting a fleeting sense of empowerment.</text>
<text id="60237000">A balm extracted from a rare plant.
Temporarily increases intelligence.

This special fragrant oil affects the mind,
granting a fleeting sense of empowerment.</text>
<text id="60238000">A balm extracted from a rare plant.
Temporarily increases faith.

This special fragrant oil affects the mind,
granting a fleeting sense of empowerment.</text>
<text id="60239000">A tiny bug that produces light.
Brightbugs are said to comfort the dead,
and are found in the marshlands leading
to the Undead Crypt.

By ingesting a brightbug just before death,
the moment at which they glow most brightly,
one attains great power for a short time.
Often utilized as a last-resort for adventurers
who have lost their way.

Has no effect in other worlds or for phantoms.</text>
<text id="60240000">A mysterious sticky substance that
radiates a pale white light.
Applies magic to right-hand weapon.

The affected weapon inflicts magic damage
for a short time. Particularly effective against
heavily armored foes or creatures with
thick scales.</text>
<text id="60250000">A rare pine resin with a golden glint.
Applies lightning to right-hand weapon.

The affected weapon inflicts lightning damage
for a short time. Particularly effective against
foes who are resistant to magic and fire.</text>
<text id="60260000">Black charcoal-like pine resin.
Applies fire to right-hand weapon.

The affected weapon inflicts fire damage
for a short time. Particularly effective
against enemies vulnerable to fire,
such as Undead or beasts.</text>
<text id="60270000">Hexed pine resin.
Applies dark flame to right-hand weapon.

The affected weapon inflicts dark damage
for a short time. Particularly effective
against enemies that fear dark,
such as clerics and magical creatures.</text>
<text id="60280000">This Rotten Pine Resin has gone poisonous.
Applies poison to right-hand weapon.

Poisoned foes slowly lose HP over time.</text>
<text id="60290000">A jar of carnivorous plant secretions.
Applies bleeding effect to right-hand weapon.

Bleeding foes' max HP is lowered.</text>
<text id="60310000">Green weed shaped like a leafy flower.
Temporarily boosts stamina recovery speed.

At one point, this herb was avoided due to
its unusually bitter taste, but once its effects
became known, it was harvested to near
extinction by merchants. Now, only
exceptionally rare, wild specimens of this
plant are left.</text>
<text id="60320000">An old rusted coin.
Crushing the coin temporarily boosts luck.

This rusted coin gives you that little extra
bit of luck, making items and the like
easier to find.

The coin is engraved with the image of a god
that was worshipped in ancient times,
but no one knows its true origins.</text>
<text id="60350000">A white-ashen bone.
Return to last bonfire rested at.

Bonfires burn on the bones of Undead.
And this bone, belonging to one whose
journey was cut short, has the power
to travel to bonfires. As if it yearns to
resume its futile quest...</text>
<text id="60355000">An aged bird feather.
Return to last bonfire rested at.
Can be used repeatedly.

The child of the dragon, sequestered away
from the world, imagined a world of boundless
possibilities from the mere sight of a feather.</text>
<text id="60360000">An accursed mark.
The Darksign induces death, returning
the player to the last bonfire rested at,
at the cost of all souls held.

Do what you must to gather the pieces,
scraping them into some semblance of
a whole, before the will to do so fades.</text>
<text id="60370000">A tiny charm embedded with imitative magic.
Use to transform into something to blend in.

Use this talisman to hide from invaders.
Only provides the most superficial camouflage,
but sometimes that is enough to do the trick.</text>
<text id="60405000">A stone containing the strength of dragons.
Transforms the head into that of a
fire-breathing dragon, an effect that will
remain until death.

The zealots who sought everlasting life are said
to have conducted rites to imbue stones with the
strength of dragons, but their are no records
confirming their success.</text>
<text id="60406000">A stone containing the strength of dragons.
Transforms the body into a roaring dragon,
an effect that will remain until death.

The zealots who sought everlasting life are said
to have conducted rites to imbue stones with the
strength of dragons, but the truth of such claims
is questionable.</text>
<text id="60410000">Enchanted metal rendered into powder.
Repairs equipment.

Weapons and armor wear down with use.
Allow too much wear, and you won't be
able to use them.

You have only yourself to blame if you find
yourself in crisis with no powder to spare.</text>
<text id="60430000">Bottle filled with dried red butterflies.
Stimulation of these rare butterflies creates a
small flame, allowing torches to be lit on the go.

These butterflies exude secretions which ignite
upon exposure to air, protecting them from
natural predators. Known and loved as handy
fire-lighters, but feared as the catalysts of
disastrous fires when found in swarms.</text>
<text id="60450000">A slightly warm rock.
Emits a beautiful, phasing aura of seven
colors, with a very rare eighth.

The prism stone does nothing special,
but if you feel you may lose your way,
it can serve as a path marker.</text>
<text id="60470000">Faces carved from the wood of aged trees.
They speak when thrown upon the ground.

The fine craftsmanship of these faces is
evident even after much aging, but no one
knows even the name of the artist.

This face says "Hello!"
Doesn't it look friendly?</text>
<text id="60480000">Faces carved from the wood of aged trees.
They speak when thrown upon the ground.

The fine craftsmanship of these faces is
evident even after much aging, but no one
knows even the name of the artist.

This face says "Thank You"
Doesn't it look appreciative?</text>
<text id="60490000">Faces carved from the wood of aged trees.
They speak when thrown upon the ground.

The fine craftsmanship of these faces is
evident even after much aging, but no one
knows even the name of the artist.

This face says "I'm Sorry"
Doesn't it look apologetic?</text>
<text id="60500000">Faces carved from the wood of aged trees.
They speak when thrown upon the ground.

The fine craftsmanship of these faces is
evident even after much aging, but no one
knows even the name of the artist.

This face says "Very Good!"
Doesn't it look cheerful?</text>
<text id="60510000">A piece of rubbish that is good for nothing.

One man's rubbish is another man's riches,
for value, is in the eye of the beholder.

But utility is another matter, and this has none.</text>
<text id="60511000">An unidentified petrified object.
Pleasant to the touch, despite its looks.

A rare and peculiar thing, to be certain,
but one without a known purpose.</text>
<text id="60525000">The shard of an Estus Flask.
Shards are deeply soaked in Estus.
Graft the shard to an Estus Flask
to increase flask uses.

Over the ages, countless souls rested their
bones as they drank from the original flask.
And now this shard remains, serving as
a vestige of their hopes and dreams.</text>
<text id="60526000">Charred, ashen bones.
Cast them into the Far Fire in Majula
to increase the HP restored
with each use of your flask.

They say these are the remains of a saint
who cast himself into the bonfire.
But we will never know for sure,
for soot and ashes tell no story.</text>
<text id="60527000">Tossing this into a bonfire strengthens nearby foes.

Once the Bonfire Ascetic is devoured by
the flames, its effects can never be reversed.
Be prepared before using this perilous ember.

Fire exhibits a connection to the curse,
and when the flames grow stronger,
so does the curse.</text>
<text id="60530000">A skull of unknown ownership.
Smashing it releases traces of souls,
which attract nearby foes.

Does not work on all enemies, but
can prove useful in unexpected ways.</text>
<text id="60531000">Talisman used by cleric knights.
Blocks Estus recovery within a limited area.

It is said that the cleric knights used these
talismans to hunt down accursed Undead.

Cleric knights fight with pride,
and by blocking the recovery of the Undead,
they can also fight with impunity.</text>
<text id="60536000">Stone activating a creation of
Pharros the Vagabond.

Pharros the Vagabond was a legend who
wandered the lands, creating contraptions
to help those in sincere and dire need.

The scope of his travels was so wide that
Pharros has been mistakenly credited with
many inventions that were crafted by others.</text>
<text id="60537000">A fragrant tree branch with a faint sweet smell.
Restores the life of things turned to stone.

Extended inhalation of the branch's scent can
lead to coughing and nausea.</text>
<text id="60538000">A tiny waning flame.
Used to strengthen a pyromancy flame.

A pyromancy flame serves as the catalyst
for pyromancies, and scales the strength of
each spell according to its level.

Fire is a common object of worship.
It can never be grasped, and its mystery
stokes the human imagination.</text>
<text id="60540000">Throwing knife.
Used as a projectile.

This simple weapon is easily utilized.
Its range is limited, and it deals very little
damage, but even still, it is a valuable tool
in the absence of other ranged weapons.</text>
<text id="60550000">A small clay urn enwreathed in magic.
Explodes, inflicting magic damage.

Created in Melfia, a land that flourishes
with magic and pyromancy.
Though the magic contained in the urn
lacks potency, it is a boon to any
inexperienced traveler.</text>
<text id="60560000">A small clay urn enwreathed in lightning.
Explodes, inflicting lightning damage.

Created in Melfia, a land that flourishes
with magic and pyromancy.
Though the lightning contained in the urn
lacks potency, it is a boon to any
inexperienced traveler.</text>
<text id="60570000">Bisque urn filled with black powder.
Explodes, inflicting fire damage.

Though this urn is a crude and commonplace
weapon, it owes its continued usage to its
simplicity and effectiveness in a variety
of situations.</text>
<text id="60575000">Bisque urn filled with black powder.
Explodes, inflicting great fire damage.

Utilizes a powerful explosive developed
in the fallen kingdom of Forossa.
Black firebombs can cause harm to their
owners when misused, and Forossa law
defined stringent standards for their
safe storage.</text>
<text id="60580000">Hexed black lacquer urn.
Explodes, inflicting dark damage.

With the dark art of hexing strictly forbidden,
who would dare fill an urn with such power?
The very origins of the art are unclear,
yet another reason hexing is feared.</text>
<text id="60590000">A throwing knife.
Intended to poison the target more
than inflict direct damage.

This simple weapon is easily utilized,
but has limited range and deals little damage.

However, if the knife can cause poison,
the target will take damage for some time.</text>
<text id="60595000">A large excrement. Still rather warm.
Throw at enemy to cause rapid onset of poison,
but you too will be subjected to the same bane.

Most warriors are loath to come near
a thing like this, much less carry it around,
but therein lies the advantage.</text>
<text id="60600000">A throwing knife.
Its sharp blade is intended to cause bleeding
rather than simply inflict damage.

This simple weapon is easily utilized,
but has limited range and deals little damage.

However, if the knife can cause bleeding,
the target's max HP will be lowered.</text>
<text id="60610000">Urn filled with secretions of giant corrosive ants.
Powerful acid inflicts damage on equipment.

Giant anthills created by the corrosive ants
line the horizon of the desert land of Jugo.
Ant larvae are considered a delicacy,
but he who enters an anthill uninvited
will have their flesh melted to the bone.</text>
<text id="60620000">An urn filled with crystal-clear water.
Originally intended as a soothing potion,
this water scalds the skin of Undead and Hollows.

In the old capital of Mirrah, an ancient,
well-protected spring produces holy water,
but the water has been difficult to acquire
ever since Mirrah became embroiled in war.</text>
<text id="60625000">The fading soul of a lost Undead
who has gone Hollow and still.

Use to acquire souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60630000">Soul of a lost Undead who has
long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60640000">Large soul of a lost Undead who has
long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60650000">Soul of a nameless Undead soldier
who has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60660000">Large soul of a nameless Undead
soldier who has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire many souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60670000">Soul of a proud Undead knight who
has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire many souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60680000">Large soul of a proud Undead knight who
has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire many souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60690000">Soul of a brave Undead warrior
who has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire a large amount of souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60700000">Large soul of a brave Undead warrior
who has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire a large amount of souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60710000">Soul of a hero of legend
who has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire a large amount of souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60720000">Great soul of a hero of legend
who has long ago gone Hollow.

Use to acquire an incredible amount of souls.

The soul is the source of all life,
and even in undeath, or hollowing,
the mind seeks souls.</text>
<text id="60970000">Titanite shard used to reinforce equipment.
Reinforces equipment up to +3.

Titanite was discovered in an ancient layer
of earth, and is said to be a gift of the gods.
Titanite of this size has very little power,
but it is still a rare find.</text>
<text id="60975000">Large titanite shard used to reinforce equipment.
Reinforces equipment up to +6.

Titanite was discovered in an ancient layer
of earth, and is said to be a gift of the gods.
Titanite of this size has tremendous power,
and is a very rare find.</text>
<text id="60980000">Titanite chunk used to reinforce equipment.
Reinforces equipment up to +9.

Titanite was discovered in an ancient layer
of earth, and is said to be a gift of the gods.
There are said to be only a scarce few
titanite chunks in the world.</text>
<text id="60990000">Titanite slab used to reinforce equipment.
Reinforces equipment up to +10.

Titanite was discovered in an ancient layer
of earth, and is said to be a gift of the gods.
One of the original slabs that provided
the world with all forms of titanite.

Titanite slabs were created to smith
the weapons of the gods, or so the legends say.</text>
<text id="61000000">A form of titanite with special power.
Reinforce equipment that cannot normally
be reinforced up to +5.

What cosmic event could have created
such a powerful class of titanite?</text>
<text id="61030000">A large petrified bone.
Reinforces equipment made from special souls.

Commonly called dragon bone, but the
veracity of the name is questionable.
In any case, this petrified bone houses
great power.</text>
<text id="61060000">An altered state of titanite.
Use to imbue weapons with magic,
or to provide magic reduction to shields.

Sorcerers at the Melfian Magic Academy
once attempted to imbue titanite with
various elements, but are said to have failed.

Someone must have succeeded though;
what else would explain this stone?</text>
<text id="61070000">An altered state of titanite.
Use to imbue weapons with lightning,
or to provide lightning reduction to shields.

Sorcerers at the Melfian Magic Academy
once attempted to imbue titanite with
various elements, but are said to have failed.

Someone must have succeeded though;
what else would explain this stone?</text>
<text id="61080000">An altered state of titanite.
Use to imbue weapons with fire,
or to provide fire reduction to shields.

Sorcerers at the Melfian Magic Academy
once attempted to imbue titanite with
various elements, but are said to have failed.

Someone must have succeeded, though;
what else would explain this stone?</text>
<text id="61090000">An altered state of titanite.
Use to imbue weapons with dark,
or to provide dark reduction to shields.

Sorcerers at the Melfian Magic Academy
once attempted to imbue titanite with
various elements, but are said to have failed.

Someone must have succeeded, though;
what else would explain this stone?</text>
<text id="61100000">An altered state of titanite.
Use to imbue weapons with poison,
or to provide poison reduction to shields.

Sorcerers at the Melfian Magic Academy
once attempted to imbue titanite with
various elements, but are said to have failed.

Someone must have succeeded, though;
what else would explain this stone?</text>
<text id="61110000">An altered state of titanite.
Use to make weapons lacerating,
or to provide bleeding reduction to shields.

Sorcerers at the Melfian Magic Academy
once attempted to imbue titanite with
various elements, but are said to have failed.

Someone must have succeeded, though;
what else would explain this stone?</text>
<text id="61130000">An altered state of titanite.
Changes weapon class to Raw.
Cannot be used on shields.

This unusually hard titanite raises a
weapon's physical attack power,
but lowers strength and dexterity bonuses.</text>
<text id="61140000">An altered state of titanite.
Use on weapon to convert wielder's intelligence
into attack. Cannot be used on shields.

Sorcerers at the Melfian Magic Academy
once attempted to imbue titanite with
various elements, but are said to have failed.

Someone must have succeeded, though;
what else would explain this stone?</text>
<text id="61150000">An altered state of titanite.
Use to imbue weapons with power of the mundane.
Cannot be used on shields.

People do not look favorably on the banal,
but sometimes even the most mundane of objects
can cast things in a most pleasant light.</text>
<text id="61160000">An altered state of titanite.
Use on a weapon or shield
to undo all imbued powers.

This does not revert reinforcement,
but undoes imbued powers such as
magic, fire, poison, etc.</text>
<text id="62000000">Dried fingers with multiple knuckles.

Shriveled, but radiating a peculiar warmth.

By the number of knuckles, it couldn't
have been human, but perhaps
some questions are best left unasked.</text>
<text id="62020000">Online play item.
You will be punished for fleeing from other
worlds by disconnecting unjustly. However,
this charm will disperse the ire directed at you.

But sins are not easily buried, and there's no
telling if you will be let off so easily next time.
Each encounter in life is a precious turn of fate,
and fate will not be cheated.</text>
<text id="62030000">Online play item.
Leave summon sign.

Be summoned as a phantom to another world
in order to help that world's master for
a certain time. You will be rewarded with
a Token of Fidelity for successfully
assisting the other player.

The flow of time is distorted in these lands,
and the White Sign Soapstone allows
Undead to assist one another.</text>
<text id="62040000">Online play item.
Leave summon sign.

Be summoned as a shade to another world
in order to help that world's master for
a certain time. You will be rewarded for
successfully assisting the other player.

The effect is not as long-lived as that of
the White Sign Soapstone, and it is used
only in particular places.</text>
<text id="62045000">Online play item.
Leave invasion sign.

Be summoned to another world as a dark
spirit, and defeat the summoner to acquire
a Token of Spite.

Some Undead persevere along the honorable
path even after crossing into the dark.
The Red Sign Soapstone is for them.</text>
<text id="62050000">Online play item.
Invade the world of the guilty.

Can only be used by members
of the Blue Sentinels covenant.
Punish the guilty to strengthen
the bond with your covenant.</text>
<text id="62060000">Online play item.
Invade other worlds.

Defeat the master of the world you have
invaded to acquire a Token of Spite.

The residual sins of those who have
succumbed to dark temptations are
contained in the form of the Cracked
Red Eye Orb.</text>
<text id="62070000">Online play item.
Invade a world with a Dragon Scale
to claim the scale from its master.

If our human flesh is our greatest weakness,
then those who seek a form that imitates the
ancient dragons are the true vanguard.</text>
<text id="62100000">Token recognizing that the owner has
traveled worlds to help others.

When in other worlds, it can also be used to
restore the master of the world's HP, but
this is only a secondary effect of the item.
Simply carrying these tokens shows
the depth of the holder's fidelity.</text>
<text id="62110000">Token recognizing that the owner has
traveled worlds to defeat others.
When used, you are more likely to summon
invaders from other worlds for a period of time.

Simply carrying these tokens shows
the bitterness of the grudges the holder
has accumulated.</text>
<text id="62120000">A medal depicting the sun.
Offer it to the altar to strengthen
the bond with your covenant.

The slight warmth of the medal makes
valor brim within one's bosom.
The brave fighters who bore these medals are
gone, but the sun never sets. On this day
begins the contest to find the Sun's truest son.</text>
<text id="62130000">A scale from the body of an ancient dragon.
Offer to the dragon to bring your own flesh
closer to that of the eternal ancient dragon.

Touching an ancient dragon scale
gives one a glimpse into the abyss.
Believers in the dragon will rise above
this petty corporeal existence.</text>
<text id="62140000">A severed rat's tail.
Demonstrate fidelity by offering it to the Rat King,
and strengthen the bond with your covenant.

The Rat King is proud and merciful,
as any king true to his stature should be.
The Rat King looks favorably upon those who
follow the path of right, even disgraceful humans.</text>
<text id="62150000">A stone that is terribly heavy for its size.
Offer it to the Victor's Stone to strengthen
the bond with your covenant.

The Victor's Stone thirsts for the souls of
fallen warriors, condensed within awestones,
as if they were once part of the same whole.</text>
<text id="62160000">A symbol of farewells that has been passed
down since time immemorial.

The crystal sends phantoms back to their
homes, or sends you back to yours.

Whether ending in hope or despair,
encounters are valuable experiences.
Beware fickle use of this item.</text>
<text id="62170000">A lump of something, obtainable from a Giant-tree.
Makes enemies react to invaders.

When the giants fell, they grew into great trees.
Death is not the end, for anything that has ever
once lived remains a part of a great cycle of
regeneration.

But what of those outside of the cycle?</text>
<text id="62190000">A large petrified egg.
Surely bears no life.

Eggs are vessels that harbor life itself,
and symbolize the deepest secrets of existence.
But what does a petrified egg harbor?</text>
<text id="64000000">Soul of the Pursuer,
who lurks in Drangleic.

The Pursuer, who seeks the bearer of the sign,
will not rest until his target is slain.

Use the special soul of the Pursuer to acquire
numerous souls, or to create something of
great worth.</text>
<text id="64010000">Soul of the surviving giant, who was bound
below the Forest of the Giants.

The lord of the Giants, who had brought wrack
and ruin to the entire kingdom, was said to have
been felled by an unknown warrior.
His beaten and broken remains were then dragged
beneath the stronghold, where he was sealed away.

Use the special soul of the Last Giant to acquire
numerous souls, or to create something of
great worth.</text>
<text id="64020000">Soul of a Dragonrider,
who faithfully served King Vendrick.

Long ago, the dragonriders mounted wyrms,
and were feared on the battlefield for their
unparallelled strength.

Use a Dragonrider soul to acquire
numerous souls, or to create something of
great worth.</text>
<text id="64030000">Soul of the Old Dragonslayer.

The Old Dragonslayer is reminiscent of
a certain knight that appears in old legends.

Use the special soul of the Old Dragonslayer
to acquire numerous souls, or to create
something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64040000">Soul of the Flexile Sentry.

The Flexile Sentry is a merciless creature
whose purpose is to punish the Undead.

Use the special soul of the Flexile Sentry
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64050000">Soul of the Ruin Sentinel,
a creation of the jailer.

The Ruin Sentinel has no corporeal form.
It is only an empty soul that haunts the armor.

Use the special soul of the Ruin Sentinel
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64060000">Soul of the Lost Sinner,
prisoner of Sinner's Rise.

The Lost Sinner eternally punishes herself
for the sins of her past.

Use the special soul of the Lost Sinner
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64070000">Soul of the Executioner's Chariot,
that holds control over the Undead Purgatory.

The chariot was created only to torment Undead,
and it took the form of a horrendous mad steed,
a window into the soul of its master.

Use the special soul of the Executioner's Chariot
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64080000">Soul of a Skeleton Lord, who reigned
from deep within the Huntsman's Copse.

The Old Iron King commanded the capture
of all Undead, but those charged with
the task were overcome by the curse.

Use the special soul of the Skeleton Lord
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64090000">Soul of the Covetous Demon,
that devours all things.

Eating is an expression of desire. 
There once was a man whose deep 
affections were unrequited. 
He transformed into the Covetous Demon, 
which only made him lonelier than before. 

Use the special soul of the Covetous Demon
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64100000">Soul of Mytha, the Baneful Queen,
who lives in the Earthen Peak.

The Queen sought the King's affection,
even poisoning herself to attain beauty,
despite the monstrous consequences.
All for the compelling madness known as love.

Use the special soul of the Queen
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64110000">Soul of the Smelter Demon, that haunts
the castle that sunk into a pool of iron.

The Old Iron King's life was taken by a mass of
iron that had been given a soul.
Was this metal goliath there from the beginning,
or was it a product of the king's conceit?

Use the special soul of the Smelter Demon
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64120000">Soul of the Old Iron King, who succumbed
to the flames that swallowed his castle.

The Iron King's flesh was charred, and his
soul possessed by the things that lurk below.

Use the special soul of the Old King
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64130000">Soul of the Rat King's vanguard,
of the underground realm.

The Rat King's loyal servant judges the
worthiness of those who seek royal audience.

Use the special soul of this soldier
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64140000">Soul of the Rotten,
who writhes deep within the Gutter.

The Rotten embraces all, in his sanctuary for
all things unwanted or tossed away.

Use the special soul of the Rotten
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64150000">Soul of Scorpioness Najka.

Najka was born of the misdeeds of an ancient
being, a frail soul from the beginning,
that soon succumbed to madness.

Use the special soul of Scorpioness Najka
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64160000">Soul of the Royal Rat Authority,
of the underground realm.

Those who choose to serve the Rat King
must have the courage to face His challenges.

Use the special soul of this rat
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64170000">Soul of the Duke's Dear Freja,
the Writhing Ruin's Keeper.

The Writhing Ruin is an ancient thing whose
shadow remains cast over the land.
It first took possession of a solitary insect,
but grew its power, feasting on the wealth
of twisted souls found in the land.

Use the special soul of the Keeper
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64180000">Soul of the Looking Glass Knight,
who challenges visitors to the lordless castle.

Long ago, the King's Passage was a route taken
by the bravest warriors to prove themselves,
but now it only prevents one from pursuing
the runaway king.

Use the special soul of this knight
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64190000">Soul of the Demon of Song
at the Shrine of Amana.

When this demon developed a taste for
human flesh, it was contained within the
Shrine of Amana, but the line of priestesses
who looked after the shrine and appeased
the creature have died off.

Use the special soul of this demon
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64200000">Soul of the Velstadt,
defender of the King inside the Undead Crypt.

Velstadt was always at the King's side,
as if he were his lord's own shadow.
After the King retired to the Undead Crypt,
Velstadt followed, never to return.

Use the special soul of this knight
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64210000">Soul of Vendrick, King of Drangleic.

This great soul beckoned the Dark,
overwhelming the King.
Perhaps this King, who once ruled the world
of men, was a lacking vessel for the true throne.

Use the soul of he who would link the flame
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64220000">Soul of a dragon that guards
the path to the shrine.

Do the dragons watch over the land
of their own will, or are they in the grip of
one of Aldia's spells?

Use the special soul of this dragon
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64230000">Soul of the great ancient dragon that
stands magnificently, deep within the shrine.

This powerful being stands and waits,
for whoever may visit him.

Use the dragon soul, created by those who
peered into the essence of the soul,
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64240000">Soul of the Giant Lord,
who once conquered Drangleic.

Vendrick crossed the seas, took prisoner
the Giants, and brought them back to his castle,
clapped in irons. However, after this modest
triumph, his countenance could be seen to
grow darker with each passing day.

Use the special soul of this Giant
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64250000">Soul of Nashandra, Queen of Drangleic.

The fragments of the abyss, of untold origin,
nourished their beings by the sides of would-be
monarchs. Perhaps they were simply ordeals
on the road to kinghood.

One day, the flames will fade, and only darkness
will remain. Unless, of course, an heir arrives.

Use the special soul of this prisoner of desire
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64260000">Soul of the Throne Defender.

The throne of the King is sacred,
and requires an appropriate guardian.

Use the special soul of the Defender
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64270000">Soul of the Throne Watcher.

The throne of the King is sacred,
and must be observed closely at all times.

Use the special soul of the Watcher
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64280000">Soul of what lurks in the Dark Chasm.

The Dark Chasm of Old is the remnant of
some ancient, dissipated being.

Use the special soul of what lurks within
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64290000">Soul of a Gargoyle of the Lost Bastille.

The elaborate stone statues on the belfry
mysteriously came to life.

Use the special soul of this living statue
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64300000">Soul of the ineffable.

This once-magnificent soul continues to
exert influence over the land, even after
the eons have reduced it to these remnants.

Use it to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64310000">Soul of the ineffable.

This once-magnificent soul continues to
exert influence over the land, even after
the eons have reduced it to these remnants.

Use it to acquire numerous souls,
or to create a something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64320000">Soul of the ineffable.

This once-magnificent soul continues to
exert influence over the land, even after
the eons have reduced it to these remnants.

Use it to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64330000">Soul of the ineffable.

This once-magnificent soul continues to
exert influence over the land, even after
the eons have reduced it to these remnants.

Use it to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64500000">Soul of Sinh the Dragon, who sleeps
in the lowermost depths of this land.

The King erected a magnificent city,
and the dragon slept soundly.
Until Sir Yorgh disturbed it with a
single great strike, and the dragon
could bear its store of poison no longer.
The rain of death toppled the city,
but restored the dragon's purity.

The wondrous soul of this dragon
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64510000">Soul of the fume knight that guards
the dungeon of Brume Tower.

Raime was a distinguished knight who
became infatuated with the Bride of Ash,
and settled in this land of smoke and fog.

The wondrous soul of this knight
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64520000">Soul of Aava, who served the Ivory King.

Each of the Ivory King's seven beasts
was conferred a specific duty.
Aava's was the guardianship of
the King's beloved child of Dark.

The wondrous soul of this beast
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64530000">Soul of Elana, the Squalid Queen, who rests beside
the slumbering dragon of the Eternal Sanctum.

This child of Dark accompanies the dragon,
slowly amassing souls in anticipation
of the coming day of vengeance.

The wondrous soul of this augur of wrath
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64540000">Soul of Nadalia, Bride of Ash, who renounced
her flesh and wandered Brume Tower.

In the act of dancing, the Bride of Ash
was transfigured as smoke, enticing people
to her residence. And so her seat of power
came to be known as the Brume Tower.

The wondrous soul of this augur of solitude
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64550000">Soul of Alsanna, oracle of Eleum Loyce,
who prays in silent vigilance.

This child of Dark, in reverence of the
apocalypse, devotes herself to a ritual
in hopes of appeasing the raging flame.

The wondrous soul of this augur of fear
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64560000">Soul of Sir Alonne, who once served
the Old Iron King.

Sir Alonne came from an eastern land,
and became the King's most trusted knight.

Use the wondrous soul of this knight to acquire
numerous souls, or to create something
of great worth.</text>
<text id="64580000">Soul of the Ivory King of Eleum Loyce.

The proud Ivory King was ever-merciful,
and devoted himself to the protection
of his great land, until he was devoured
by the flames of chaos.

The wondrous soul of this great king
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64590000">Soul of Zallen, who served the Ivory King.

Each of the Ivory King's seven beasts
was conferred a specific duty.
Zallen's was the mercy killing of exiles.

The wondrous soul of this beast
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="64600000">Soul of the Knights of Loyce.

The Knights of Loyce were taken by Chaos,
and lost all sense of purpose and being.
The few woeful souls that trudged back home
were guided by some faint vestige of self.

This soul is pure sorrow,
and only Alsanna can put it to rest.</text>
<text id="64610000">Soul of Lud, who served the Ivory King.

Each of the Ivory King's seven beasts
was conferred a specific duty.
Lud's was the mercy killing of exiles.

The wondrous soul of this beast
can be used to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
<text id="50640000">Tool used to reinforce
weapons.

Rest at a bonfire to make
weapon reinforcement possible.</text>
<text id="50650000">Tool used to reinforce
armor.

Rest at a bonfire to make
armor reinforcement possible.</text>
<text id="60220000">Troches with a strangely musty odor.
Temporarily boosts equipment break resist.

Verbal histories often mention Saint Elizabeth;
her uniquely concocted medicines and potions
are still widely used today.</text>
<text id="60245000">A mysterious sticky substance that
radiates a dim yellow light.
Applies powerful magic to right-hand weapon.

The affected weapon inflicts magic damage
for a short time. Particularly effective against
heavily armored foes or creatures with
thick scales.</text>
<text id="60340000">The beloved magic stone of Rhoy the Explorer.
High chance of detecting treasure chest
traps, indicated by a red light.

There are more than a few men who take
advantage of the undoing of others. Many more.</text>
<text id="60380000">A tiny charm embedded with imitative magic.
Use to transform into a treasure chest.

Use this talisman to trick invaders.
Only provides the most superficial camouflage,
but for those desperate for quick riches,
you will appear quite attractive indeed.</text>
<text id="60390000">A tiny charm embedded with imitative magic.
Use to transform into a corpse.

Use this talisman to trick invaders.
Only provides the most superficial camouflage,
but for those who fail to respect the dead,
your disguise will be quite effective.</text>
<text id="60400000">A tiny charm embedded with imitative magic.
Use to transform into a phantom.

Use this talisman to trick invaders.
Only provides the most superficial camouflage,
but for those naïve enough to never question
what they see, you should be very convincing.</text>
<text id="60420000">A torch made by soaking the end of a long
stick in pine resin.

Light the torch on the fire of a sconce
to illuminate areas for a short time.
Find new torches to extend this period.

Torches can even be lit on bonfires,
the flames of which do not normally
set objects alight, due to the coating
of the bones used to fuel them.</text>
<text id="64620000">Soul of the Rotten,
who writhes deep within the Gutter.

Gryth, the king of Shulva,
was consumed by the poison that flooded the Sanctum City,
but some part of him live on.
Now he watches over the discarded and abandoned
in his sancturary deep under the ground.

Use the special soul of the Rotten
to acquire numerous souls,
or to create something of great worth.</text>
</entries>