<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="31010000">An elementary sorcery.
Fires a small soul arrow straight ahead.

To use sorceries, attune a sorcery
at a bonfire and equip a staff.</text>
<text id="31020000">A spell superior to the Soul Arrow.
More powerful, and effective at damaging
enemies resistant to physical attacks.

The strength of this spell is influenced
by one's intelligence.</text>
<text id="31030000">Advanced soul spell.
Fires a devastating, thick soul arrow.

But beware. The more powerful the soul arrow,
the longer the casting time.</text>
<text id="31040000">A spell superior to Heavy Soul Arrow.
Fires an even stronger soul arrow.

Difficult to handle, but very powerful.
Only the well-trained can handle these arrows.</text>
<text id="31050000">One of the sorceries devised by Straid,
the great mage of ancient Olaphis.

Fires soul arrows that follow their
targets to the ends of the earth.</text>
<text id="31060000">One of the sorceries devised by Straid,
the great mage of ancient Olaphis.

Fires thick, powerful soul arrows that seek
their targets to the ends of the earth.</text>
<text id="31070000">Multiple soul masses appear above the head.
When fired, they home in on their target.

This spell was said to have been devised
by a master sorcerer, but his name is
long forgotten.</text>
<text id="31080000">Soulbeads made more lethal with crystallization.
When fired, they home in on their target.

Crystallization makes souls and sorceries all the
more powerful.</text>
<text id="31090000">Sorcery that fires souls shaped into a spear.
Pierces enemies, causing heavy damage.

This spell was said to have been devised
by a master sorcerer, but his name is
long forgotten.</text>
<text id="31100000">Soul spear sharpened through crystallization.
Pierces enemies, causing heavy damage.

Superior to the most finely sharpened weapons.
When wielded precisely, it can take down several
enemies at once.</text>
<text id="31110000">Does not inflict damage, but unleashes a
large shockwave, toppling opponents.

Intended to stun opponents and make them
vulnerable to attack. Some call this child's play,
but for an innovative caster, it is a deadly tool.</text>
<text id="31120000">Fires a flurry of soul spears.
Inflicts high damage when multiple spears hit.

A reworking of an ancient spell concocted
at the Melfian Magic Academy.

A simple idea, but potentially highly effective.
When used properly, of course.</text>
<text id="31130000">Hurls a huge soul mass which splits
into smaller souls that rain from above.

Requires real talent and is difficult
to handle. Only works in certain places,
and against certain foes.</text>
<text id="31140000">A sorcery that attacks foes using a sword made
of souls. Energy is focused in a single point,
and wielded as a sword with both hands.

Use of this sorcery is not too dissimilar to
swordplay, and so inherently endangers the caster.</text>
<text id="31150000">One of the lost sorceries preserved only
in the Undead Crypt.
Fires successive homing souls.

Extremely difficult sorcery to evade,
making it very effective against frisky foes.</text>
<text id="31160000">One of the sorceries devised by Straid,
the great mage of ancient Olaphis.
Fires a blinding, piercing bolt of light.

Straid started with an unwieldy spell
that back-fired on its caster,
and in time, perfected it.</text>
<text id="31170000">A secret art unleashes a gush of souls.
The homing soul mass pierces its target,
then hits repeatedly for additional damage.

This blasphemous spell is a family heirloom of
Lord Aldia's. It was designed to pummel foes
until its power is entirely exhausted.</text>
<text id="31180000">Sorcery that imbues weapon in other hand 
with magic. Adds magic damage to the types of
damage the weapon already inflicts.

Wielding a sword and casting a sorcery
are two different things, and some members
the Melfian Magic Academy view these varieties
of spells as impure.</text>
<text id="31190000">A sorcery superior to Magic Weapon. Reinforces
weapon in other hand with intense magic,
allowing for infliction of heavy magic damage.

The old purists of the Melfian Magic Academy
view swordplay as a barbaric form of engagement.</text>
<text id="31200000">Imbues weapon in other hand with crystal magic.
More powerful than standard magic reinforcement.

The utilization of crystals to enhance soul power
is an ancient form of magical reinforcement.</text>
<text id="31210000">Imbues off-hand shield with magic.
Reinforce shield to absorb additional damage.

Certain members of the Melfian Magic
Academy scoff at these types of magic.
The purists, in particular, are disdainful of
anything vaguely linked to sword fighting.</text>
<text id="31220000">Creates a warm soul-like orb that serves
as a decoy and lures foes toward itself.

People regret loss, and yearn for what they
do not have. Perhaps the name of this
sorcery harkens to this irony.</text>
<text id="31230000">A sorcery that facilitates surreptitious activity.
Reduces the sound made by its caster.

The eastern land of Mirrah is not only the
home of proud knights. There is also a
traditional order of shadow knights,
who quietly carry out unspeakable tasks.</text>
<text id="31240000">A sorcery that facilitates surreptitious activity.
Reduces the damage taken from falls.

The eastern land of Mirrah is not only the
home of proud knights. There is also a
traditional order of shadow knights, who use
any means necessary to carry out their orders.</text>
<text id="31250000">A sorcery that dates farther back than recollection.
Makes weapon in other hand invisible.

Effective use of this, like any tool, perhaps,
is reliant upon the ingenuity of its caster.</text>
<text id="31260000">A sorcery that dates farther back than recollection.
Repairs equipped weapons and armor.

Uses light to repair damaged weapons and armor.
Supposedly this sorcery restores items to a past
state, but with the knowledge of this art lost,
the finer details of the phenomenon are unknown.</text>
<text id="31270000">A sorcery that dates farther back than recollection.
Creates a light that illuminates one's surroundings.

Light banishes dark, and reveals all.
Whether this is desired, is another matter.</text>
<text id="31280000">A sorcery that dates farther back than recollection.
Allows you to blend into your surroundings.

Those who fear the unseen are cowards.
Those who never doubt their eyes are fools.</text>
<text id="31290000">Boosts magic within the body beyond even
your own limits, but at great cost to HP.

The terrible deeds carried out in Aldia led
to the unintentional birth of several shadowy
things, all of them eerily malformed.</text>
<text id="31300000">One of the ancient sorceries that
were lost when Eleum Loyce froze over.
Rapidly fire a barrage of small souls.

Intended to protect its caster
more than damage enemies.</text>
<text id="31310000">An ancient sorcery of Shulva, the Sanctum City.
Fires a focused beam of souls.

The development of sorceries was stunted
in Shulva, as they were considered taboo.
Even so, there were some occasional gems
created by a group of nameless enthusiasts.</text>
<text id="32010000">A healing miracle widely used by clerics.
Slightly restores HP.

To use miracles, equip a sacred chime
and attune a miracle at a bonfire.</text>
<text id="32020000">Superior spell to Heal.
Restores HP.

The strength of miracles are influenced
by one's faith.

Miracles are tales of the Gods passed down
long ago, but only a small number of the
original tomes remain in their entirety,
and most that exist are restorations.</text>
<text id="32030000">A highly advanced miracle.
An excerpt from the Great Heal tome.
Greatly restores HP.
Its effect is the same as Great Heal,
but has limited uses.

The erudite Great Heal tome requires
extensive training to properly interpret,
making it accessible to only a select few.</text>
<text id="32040000">A glorious miracle only accessible to a small
minority of clerics. Greatly restores HP.

Only a select few have learned to recite this
epic romance in its entirety, but those who do
are amply rewarded. </text>
<text id="32050000">A special miracle passed down through the ages.
Greatly heals HP of self and nearby allies.

This miracle, once kept by the Lindelt Monastery,
was stolen and never recovered.</text>
<text id="32060000">An intermediate miracle.
Gradually restores HP.

This miracle is used by the resolute Lindelt
cleric knights when fighting on the front lines.

There is a story, passed down through generations,
claiming this band of knights once felled a
poisonous dragon which menaced an entire nation.</text>
<text id="32070000">A great miracle used by highly-ranked clerics.
Slowly restores a large amount of HP.

Cleric Forsalle of Lindelt was a master of
miracles who fought battles across the lands.
His allies called him a holy knight, but his
enemies feared him for his "demonic powers."</text>
<text id="32080000">A special miracle passed down through the ages.
Slowly heals a great amount of HP of self
and nearby allies.

This miracle, once kept by the Lindelt Monastery,
was stolen and never recovered.</text>
<text id="32090000">An elementary miracle for clerics.
Purifies the body, removing all poison.

Affects both the caster and nearby allies.

This spell was recently developed,
and may not be an authentic miracle.</text>
<text id="32100000">An elementary miracle.
Releases a shockwave that staggers foes.

Pushes nearby foes back, but leaves them unhurt.
Does not directly cause damage, but can be
highly effective with a little ingenuity.</text>
<text id="32110000">Miracle that releases local shockwave,
staggering nearby foes and causing heavy damage.

Little is known about the origins of this miracle,
except its shared roots with the Force spell.
It makes mention of certain Gods, but alas,
their actual names are long forgotten.</text>
<text id="32120000">A miracle derived from Force.
Emits a forward-moving shockwave.

Throughout history, there have been many
examples of imitative miracles.
When discerning original from imitator is nigh
on impossible, which is which hardly matters.</text>
<text id="32130000">Emits lightning in random directions.
Scholars bicker over whether this is
the original Lightning Spear, or a derivative.

One can never gain full control of the power
of the Gods, but with a little favor from lady luck,
this spell will destroy your foes.</text>
<text id="32140000">A miracle that launches a spear of lightning.
Said to be the legacy of an ancient clan
whose leader was revered as the God of Sun.

The name of the clan has been lost to time,
but the gross incandescence of our magnificent
father shall never wane.</text>
<text id="32150000">A miracle that launches a great spear of lightning.
Said to be the legacy of an ancient clan
whose leader was revered as the God of Sun.

The name of the clan has been lost to time,
but the gross incandescence of our magnificent
father shall never wane.</text>
<text id="32160000">A miracle that launches a spear of sunlight.
Powered with immense wondrous souls.

One of the ancient original miracles,
said to have existed from the infancy
of the very world.</text>
<text id="32170000">One of the lost miracles preserved only
in the Undead Crypt. Inflicts heavy
damage on mindless Hollows, but has
no effect on anything else.

The Undead Crypt is a place of rest
for the living. Those afflicted by the curse
can only pray to one day gain entrance.</text>
<text id="32180000">A miracle that creates a giant soul mass
and transforms it into a lightning-spouting
orb of light.

Crafted in ancient times by the God of Sun,
but later forbidden by the same deity. Was it
to protect the world from hatred, or sorrow?</text>
<text id="32190000">A miracle encasing the body in a magic barrier.
Increases resistance to magic, lightning,
fire, and dark.

This miracle is said to shield its caster with
the Rock's armor, and was common
amongst the wizard knights of Mirrah.</text>
<text id="32200000">Superior miracle to Magic Barrier.
Increases resistance to magic, lightning,
fire, and dark.

The knights of Mirrah are expected to fight
honorably, with reliance only upon swordsmanship.
They only resort to magic the only time they
truly need it: to face the magic of an enemy.</text>
<text id="32210000">A miracle that returns its caster to the
last bonfire rested at. Traditionally,
its destination was the caster's homeland.

The curse slowly erodes one's memory,
until even one's birthplace is reduced to
a figment of a clouded past.
But the bonfires are constant,
a beacon for the tragically afflicted.</text>
<text id="32220000">A miracle created to help those who have
lost their way. Reveals more messages
from other worlds.

Countless worlds loosely overlap,
and at the seams of contact, kindred souls,
who have lost their way, call out to one
another with fleeting messages of hope.</text>
<text id="32230000">An ancient miracle said to have been devised
by warriors who once served the God of Sun.

Provides a temporary boost to the attack and
defense of its caster and all nearby allies.</text>
<text id="32240000">A miracle that senses traitors.
Reveals the location of the nearest enemy,
or invading dark spirit.

Those who serve the Lindelt Monastery
willfully adhere to strict commandments.
This miracle was created to castigate those
who ignore the righteous teachings.</text>
<text id="32250000">Enwreathes its caster with a pure veil.
Grants temporary resistance to status effects.

Lindelt ascetics are sent to distant lands
for proselytizing and self-training,
but many of them decide not to return.</text>
<text id="32260000">An ancient miracle of the sun.
Reinforces weapon in other hand with sunlight,
a form of lightning.

The sun grants life to all things upon the earth,
even if the worshippers of sunlight no longer
bless the surface with their presence.</text>
<text id="32300000">An ancient miracle owed to the cardinal of Shulva.
Challenge fate one time when HP reaches 0.

Originally intended to grant the dying
a few moments for a final farewell.</text>
<text id="32310000">Developed from a primal miracle.
Launch splintering spears of lightning.

Ever since miracles came to be, learned
men have endeavored to rework and remold
them to their satisfaction.
This is one such effort.</text>
<text id="33010000">A standard spell for pyromancers.
Creates a fireball that is hurled at foes.

To use pyromancies, equip
a pyromancy flame to serve
as the catalyst, and assign
a pyromancy to an
attunement slot.

The power of a pyromancy is
directly affected by the
quality of the catalyst.</text>
<text id="33020000">A stronger form of Fireball.
Creates a fireball that is hurled at foes.
Also inflicts damage to foes near point of
contact.

The power of pyromancies is influenced
by one's pyromancy flame, which can be
strengthened through reinforcement.</text>
<text id="33030000">The strongest form of Fireball.
Creates a giant fireball that is hurled at foes.

The exalted flame, long pined after.
Even if it would scorch our very flesh.</text>
<text id="33040000">The chaos flame is said to have
devoured the mother of pyromancy.
Create a chaos flame, and hurl it at foes.

This special flame creates a short-lived
surge of molten lava wherever it lands.</text>
<text id="33050000">An ancient, primal pyromancy.
Pillars of flame erupt near the caster.

The Firestorm is said to be the wrath
and ire of the spell's creator.</text>
<text id="33060000">An ancient, primal pyromancy.
Giant pillars of flame erupt near the caster.

The fire tempest incinerates all life.
What menace was so great as to make
such a fearsome spell necessary?</text>
<text id="33070000">The chaos flame is said to have
devoured the mother of pyromancy.
Create multiple pillars of chaos flame.

Those who sought great power were
consumed by their own desires.
Where are these lost souls now?</text>
<text id="33080000">An elementary spell for new pyromancers.
Releases flame in front of the caster.

The simplest pyromancy of all,
but surprisingly effective.</text>
<text id="33090000">Superior spell to Combustion.
Releases intense flame in front of the caster.

A very powerful spell, but so simple that
it can be awkward to use.</text>
<text id="33100000">An ancient, primal pyromancy.
Sweep foes with a whip-like flame.

One of the original pyromancies.
Effective use of it demands agile footwork,
making it a difficult spell for most.</text>
<text id="33110000">A fringe pyromancy of unknown origin.
Creates a cloud of poison mist.

This spell contradicts the very principles of
pyromancy, suggesting that its creator
had a heretical streak.</text>
<text id="33120000">A fringe pyromancy of unknown origin.
Creates a powerful cloud of poison mist.

The poison gradually erodes the target's body,
inflicting damage all the while.
Whoever created this spell did not believe
his enemies deserved a swift death.</text>
<text id="33130000">A fringe pyromancy of unknown origin.
Sprays an equipment-eroding acid.

Does not directly damage foes, but eats away
at their equipment instead. Yet another
pyromancy inspired by perniciousness.</text>
<text id="33140000">One of the pyromancies devised by Straid,
the great mage of ancient Olaphis.
Release a static fireball that explodes when
foes draw near.

Straid was an oddly gifted mage, well-versed
in both sorceries and pyromancies, but his
curious temperament never allowed him
to settle down in one place for very long.</text>
<text id="33150000">One of the pyromancies devised by Straid,
the great mage of ancient Olaphis.
Great flames envelop and immolate faraway foes.

Straid, always immersed in magic,
never accepted an apprentice.
As a result, much of his extensive
knowledge is permanently lost.</text>
<text id="33160000">Pyromancy developed in Aldian rites.
Fires a giant fireball with a widely
encompassing explosion.

What could possibly justify such excessive
destructive power? In all likelihood, the madmen
of Aldia never even questioned the need.</text>
<text id="33170000">Pyromancy that imbues weapon in other hand 
with fire. Adds fire damage to the types of
damage the weapon already inflicts.

Pyromancy and sorcery are said to be
like oil and water, but in fact their origins
can be traced to a common source.</text>
<text id="33180000">A pyromancy that internalizes the power of flame.
Sweat profusely, reducing fire damage.

Most useful when facing other flame-manipulating
pyromancers.
Just don't take the looks you get personally.</text>
<text id="33190000">A pyromancy that internalizes the power of flame.
Turns the body into iron,
increasing defense and resistance.

As one might guess, the rock-solid flesh enabled
by this spell dramatically slows movement.
Guaranteed to cause trouble if used
at an inopportune moment.</text>
<text id="33200000">One of the lost pyromancies preserved only
in the Undead Crypt. Creates a gentle,
warm flame that heals those who touch it.

Fire can be a show of strength, but it is
also a symbol of wisdom and comfort.
Fire is what the caster wishes it be.</text>
<text id="33210000">A pyromancy that creates a coating of flame,
allowing the caster to incinerate nearby foes.
Needless to say, this is a perilous spell
that burns the caster while active.

If a person is truly desirous of something,
perhaps being set on fire does not seem so bad.</text>
<text id="33300000">Pyromancy created by the magus Eygil,
loyal follower of the Old Iron King.
Creates several pillars of flame
in front of the caster.

Eygil sought to grant fire a will of its own.
This pyromancy was conjured up to behave
like a snake, writhing toward its prey,
with a mind to strike.</text>
<text id="33310000">Pyromancy created by the magus Eygil,
loyal follower of the Old Iron King.
Cast flame in a sweeping motion across
a targeted area.

The fire seems to dance, and makes its
victims dance with it.</text>
<text id="33320000">A pyromancy of Nadalia, Bride of Ash.
Spouts multiple Dark flames.

This child of Dark, bearing inconceivable
strength, found herself in a kingless land
devoid of souls. And in journeying there, has
all but condemned herself to a fate most wretched.</text>
<text id="34010000">A hex modified from an old sorcery by
Gilleah, the father of Hexing.
Fires a heavy orb of darkness.

To use hexes, equip a sacred chime or staff,
and attune a hex at a bonfire.
Required equipment depends on hex.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34020000">A hex modified from an old sorcery by
Gilleah the Hexer.
Fires several orbs of darkness.

Hexing is rooted in both sorcery and
miracles, but is viewed as a perilous affront
to all life, and banned in most lands.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34030000">A hex that releases a temporary localized mist.
Those who breathe in the mist are instantly
assailed by poison.

This hex is regarded as a poison due to
the outward symptoms, but in fact the mist
eats away at the target's inner essence.
Just the traits that led to the prohibition
of hexing.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34040000">An advanced hex based on an ancient sorcery.
Creates a dark mass that seems to pursue
its target with a will of its own.

It appears to be a manifestation of an emotion.
Perhaps of hate, perhaps of love.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34050000">Hex that casts a dark flame upon corpses,
causing them to combust violently.

Hexes such as these, that tamper with
life itself, are particularly abhorred.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34060000">Felkin the Outcast applied his art
to transform Magic Weapon into a hex.
Adds dark damage to the types of damage
the weapon already inflicts.

Those who choose the path of dark
are admonished by all manner of sorcerers.
But this does not stop the curious from
being drawn to this strangely alluring craft.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34070000">A hex that releases verbose darkness.
The darkness echoes words of despair,
reducing the defense of opponents.

The Dark blankets the world in black.
A thing of tranquility, a thing serene.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34080000">A hex that distorts local space.
For a brief moment, no damage can be inflicted.

The hexer Gilleah took no apprentice, and it is
unclear how his spells were passed down.
It is even possible that hexes originated from
another source altogether.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34090000">A hex that distorts local space.
For a brief moment, spells are deflected.

Hexer Gilleah never took an apprentice, making
it unclear how his spells were passed down.
It is even possible that hexes came from
another source entirely.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34100000">A hex that transforms its caster's flesh.
Temporarily reduces received damage,
but darkens one's sight.

If it cannot be observed, it does not exist.
Certainly a common conception, but one
with far too many exceptions in this world.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34300000">Hex adapted from an ancient sorcery.
Brandish Dark like a sword.

By its nature Dark is normally tranquil,
but this hex releases a focused blade
of Dark in an uncharacteristic flash
of brilliance.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="34310000">Hex created by the children of Dark.
Fire multiple Dark orbs that seek their target.

Hexes that grant a fleeting volition to Dark
have existed from ancient times,
and it appears that the children of Dark
have some recollection of the creator
of these spells.

Catalyst: staff</text>
<text id="35010000">An esoteric spell created by Navlaan,
the infamous exiled sorcerer.
Awakens the souls of the long-buried dead.

The heretic Navlaan was executed along with
his entire village, and the mere utterance of
his name became a crime. Some say it was
because he sought to restore the banned art
of resurrection.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35020000">An esoteric spell created by Navlaan,
the infamous exiled sorcerer.
Creates a local vortex of dark flame.

The heretic Navlaan was executed along with
his entire village, and the mere utterance of
his name became a crime. Some say it was
because he sought to restore the banned art
of resurrection.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35030000">A hex that distorts the power of life.
Emits a dark mass at the cost of souls.

Can be used even without souls,
but at greatly reduced strength.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35040000">A hex that distorts the power of life.
Emits a large mass of dark at the cost of souls.

Can be used even without souls,
but at greatly reduced strength.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35050000">A hex that distorts the power of life.
Emits a mass of dark, but at the cost of all souls.

Strength varies depending on the number
of souls. Not a hex to be used lightly.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35060000">A hex developed independently by Outcast Felkin.
Transforms a certain number of souls
into HP over a period of time.

Something gained, something lost.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35070000">A hex developed independently by Outcast Felkin.
Transforms a certain number of souls
into attack power over a period of time.

Something gained, something lost.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35080000">Consume a number of souls and
affix dark to a certain spot.
Inflicts damage upon those who touch it.

This distorted dark, brewed by hexers,
drains the life-force of those who touch it.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35090000">A hex created by an ostracized cleric.
Blocks the spells of nearby casters.

This hex, born of jealousy and humiliation,
is a locus of dark thoughts. The very things
that reflect the true essence of life itself.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
<text id="35300000">A hex created from an ancient miracle
of unknown origin. Slows the walking pace
of its caster and those in the vicinity.

To stand and glare at one another,
steaming with ire and wrath,
but without making a move.
Such is the nature of peace.

Catalyst: Sacred Chime</text>
<text id="35310000">Hex that converts souls into a large mass of Dark.
This momentous mass of Dark dances to
signal the joy of its own release, or perhaps
merely to taunt foes as it veers towards them.

Hexes are an expression of human depravity,
of which this dance is a perfect example.

Catalyst: sacred chime</text>
</entries>