<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="40010000">An old ring set with a red jewel.
Raises maximum HP.

Each ring has a different power,
and even very modest rings can be
a great boon on a perilous journey.</text>
<text id="40020000">The ring is named for
its decorative green blossom,
but its luster is long since faded.

Raises stamina recovery speed.</text>
<text id="40030000">A ring bearing a soldier's seal.
Increases the load that can be carried.

These rings were granted to warriors who
distinguished themselves in the service of
King Vendrick. The king favored simple
warriors who staked their every battle on
strength alone.</text>
<text id="40040000">A dragon signet ring.
Grants its bearer the protection of dragons.
Increases HP, stamina, and maximum load,
but is easily broken.

Raulmond, knight of Drangleic, served the
King by guarding the fort until his own demise,
and was said to have cherished this ring
throughout his life of service.</text>
<text id="40050000">Wearer gains the protection of steel.
Increases physical defense.

Said to be the ring of the once legendary
Knight King, though his tales are long
forgotten, and even the greatly wizened
have no recollection of his exploits.</text>
<text id="40060000">A ring bestowed upon students of a
certain standard at the Melfian Magic Academy.
Its soul-based quartz increases magic defense.

Pyromancer Glocken crafts these replicas, much to
the dismay of the conservative old-guard faculty.</text>
<text id="40070000">A ring bestowed upon students of a
certain standard at the Melfian Magic Academy.
Its fire-based quartz increases fire defense.

There are rumors that Pyromancer Glocken
has made a hefty profit selling these replicas.</text>
<text id="40080000">A ring bestowed upon students of a
certain standard at the Melfian Magic Academy.
Its lightning quartz increases lightning defense.

Pyromancer Glocken crafted so many of these
replicas that they became widespread, such that
his fellow magicians harshly scolded him for
undermining lessons gained from harsh training.</text>
<text id="40090000">A ring bestowed upon students of a
certain standard at the Melfian Magic Academy.
Its dark-infused quartz increases dark defense.

Pyromancer Glocken was criticized for crafting
these replicas, but it is well known that they
have saved the life of many a traveler.</text>
<text id="40100000">One of several "bite" rings,
known for their peculiar design.
Increases poison resistance.

The similar, oddly disturbing design
of these rings suggests a common source.
Whoever the master craftsman was,
he clearly knew his trade.</text>
<text id="40110000">One of several "bite" rings,
known for their peculiar design.
Increases bleeding resistance.

The similar, oddly disturbing design
of these rings suggests a common source.
Whoever the master craftsman was,
he clearly knew his trade.</text>
<text id="40120000">Knuckle ring worn by Rhoy the Explorer.
Slows equipment degradation.

Expensive, flashy gear will not always
make life easier for you. Sometimes,
you just need your tried-and-true
equipment to last the long haul.</text>
<text id="40130000">One of several "bite" rings,
known for their peculiar design.
Increases curse resistance.

The similar, oddly disturbing design
of these rings suggests a common source.
Whoever the master craftsman was,
he clearly knew his trade.</text>
<text id="40135000">Knuckle ring worn by Rhoy the Explorer.
Increases petrification resistance.

Petrification is tantamount to death,
and in that sense, this knuckle ring
is a charm that may save your life.</text>
<text id="40140000">A protective ring set with gemstones
of four different colors.
Increases the wearer's resistance to magic,
lightning, fire and dark.

The artistry required to attune the varying
powers of four different stones within one ring
could only be described as transcendental.

There is only one sorcerer who could have
done this; a man from the lost land of Olaphis.</text>
<text id="40150000">A protective ring adorned with four blessed
gems. Increases resistance to poison, bleeding, 
petrification and curses.

A creation of the lost land of Olaphis.
The sorcerer who created this was so
powerful that he became widely feared.</text>
<text id="40160000">The Ring of Blades is modeled after the
mad knight of Alken's weapon of choice.
Increases physical attack.

The kingdoms of Alken and Venn
long ago flourished on these very grounds.
They were both founded by the same man,
but were reduced to rivalry and spite.</text>
<text id="40210000">A ring blessed by the High Priest of Volgen.
Increases intelligence.

The clerics of the great city of Volgen are
perennially entrenched in scandalous power
struggles, but among them remain a few
strong-willed, upstanding noblemen.</text>
<text id="40220000">A ring blessed by the High Priest of Volgen.
Increases faith.

The clerics of the great city of Volgen are
perennially entrenched in scandalous power
struggles, but among them remain a few
strong-willed, upstanding noblemen.</text>
<text id="40230000">The beloved ring of the gallant
Shieldless Lothian, formerly of Forossa.
Hits greatly reduce enemy poise.

The effect may seem trivial, but for those
who comprehend how critical it is to exploit a
hole in enemy defenses, the significance of
this ring will be clear.</text>
<text id="40260000">A ring set with a rare tearstone.
Reacts when the wearer is in danger,
temporarily increasing its wearer's
attack power.

Caitha, goddess of tears, mourns the undeserving
dead, shedding tears as red as blood.
It is said that the stone set in this ring
is one such tear.</text>
<text id="40280000">A ring set with a rare tearstone.
Reacts when the wearer is in danger,
temporarily increasing its wearer's
defense.

Caitha, goddess of tears, mourns those who have
lost loved ones by shedding pure tears of blue.
It is said that the stone set in this ring
is one such tear.</text>
<text id="40290000">The beloved ring of the gallant
Shieldless Lothian, formerly of Forossa.
Increases poise.

Lothian was born a peasant, and died a general.
His determination and diligence were unmatched,
especially on the battlefield, where he earned
his name by choosing to fight without a shield.</text>
<text id="40295000">The beloved ring of a dragon-slaying knight.
Strengthens thrust weapon counter attacks.

After many years of use, the ring's face has
worn down, but close inspection reveals an
engraved lion.</text>
<text id="40300000">Divine ring that watches over one's soul.
Created by Ivory Rhones, sage of Lindelt.

Its great protective power will protect you
from any loss upon death or petrification,
but after its power is spent, the ring will break.</text>
<text id="40310000">Divine ring that watches over one's life.
Created by the students of Ivory Rhones,
sage of Lindelt.

Its great protective power will protect you
from any loss upon death, but after
its power is spent, the ring will break.</text>
<text id="40320000">A ring used long, long ago in a land
that existed where Drangleic does now.
Extends length of spell effect.

The ancient dragons were once worshipped in
several nations, and rumors concerning objects
of similar enchantment to this uncommon ring
abound in many lands, though their origins
are no longer verifiable.</text>
<text id="40330000">A ring that belonged to Fiorenza, the only
truly moneyed merchant in Volgen.
Shortens spell casting time.

Fiorenza used his riches to buy up trinkets of
luxury and rare collectibles, but was ruined
after years of excessive debauchery.</text>
<text id="40340000">One of the secret treasures restored in Aldia.
Increases spell uses, but at the cost of HP.

This modest-looking ring contains
very powerful magic. To imagine
what unspeakable deeds were performed
to create such rings, one need only recall
the cruel fate of the residents of Aldia.</text>
<text id="40350000">One of the secret treasures restored in Aldia.
Raises the number of spells you may attune.

This modest-looking ring contains
very powerful magic. To imagine
what unspeakable deeds were performed
to create such rings, one need only recall
the cruel fate of the residents of Aldia.</text>
<text id="40360000">A gold ring depicting the snake,
both the servant and manifestation
of the god of desire, Zinder.
Greed is traditionally viewed as a vice,
but only a coward sees every chance
as something to fear.</text>
<text id="40370000">A silver ring depicting the snake,
both the servant and manifestation
of the god of greed, Zandroe.

Greed is traditionally viewed as a vice,
but only a fool allows that to ruin
a good opportunity.</text>
<text id="40390000">A modest, but inexplicably disturbing ring.
Absorb HP for each enemy defeated.

Peer too closely at the rare stone that
forms the eye of this ring, and things that
writhe and stir may come into focus.</text>
<text id="40400000">A protective ring passed down in House
Osteria. Gradually restores HP.

In the sacred land of Lindelt, this ring
symbolized prosperity and longevity
for the great House Osteria.

But the ring is fragile and breaks easily,
as if it hates being taken for granted.</text>
<text id="40410000">An unusual ring of unknown origin.
Limits the wearer's HP reduction when Hollow.

Alas, this ring will not make you human.
What is lost is not easily retrieved.</text>
<text id="40420000">Silver ring depicting a leaping feline.
Reduces damage from falling.

Legend has it that when cats grow old,
a force brews within them, and
they are reborn as something new.</text>
<text id="40430000">A cursed ring depicting a demon eye.
Becomes easier to be detected by enemies.

If it is tranquility that you seek,
then you should never have left your home.
If you seek strife, then fair enough,
but no need to overdo it.</text>
<text id="40440000">The ring of the assassin Gower,
who has killed a half-dozen kings,
and several distinguished clergymen.
Reduces damage taken from behind.

For an assassin, whose own life is always
at stake, the greatest liability is one's
exposed back.</text>
<text id="40450000">A special ring that can be engraved
with the name of a god.
Becomes easier to connect to worlds of
players who chose the same god.

There are countless vestiges of long-lost
gods in the ruins of Drangleic.
Or perhaps they are the very same gods
as ours, only known by different names.</text>
<text id="40460000">An old ring of the Melfian Magic Academy.
Depicts a soundly slumbering dragon.
Masks the sounds made by its wearer.

Though unknown for certain, some say
the founders of the academy were
sinful men who came from across
the northern seas.

The sorceries they left behind were
fragmentary, and barely legible,
leading to the loss of much of their wisdom.</text>
<text id="40470000">A ring graced with the engraving of a hawk.
Extends the range of arrows.

Blue-eyed Durgo, the nomadic bowman,
had many a valiant victory in battle,
half owing to the boon of this ring.</text>
<text id="40480000">An odd stone ring containing a fiery heat.
Accumulates power as the user is harmed, then
explodes, damaging surrounding enemies
while leaving its wearer unscathed.

Our deeds will come back to us
in some form or another, both good and bad.</text>
<text id="40500000">A ring of blue stone.
The stone is misshaped, however imperceptibly.
Renders certain equipment invisible.

Do not judge your foes by their appearance.
He who approaches without a sword
carries two behind his back.</text>
<text id="40510000">A soul is much like a curse.
And those with strong souls must bear
within themselves an even stronger curse.

Vendrick, King of Drangleic, used a
powerful soul to keep the curse at bay.
In the end, he sought the flame that began it all.

Wear this ring to open the King's Gate.</text>
<text id="40520000">The wearer of this ring appears human
even when Hollow.

They say that in the Undead Crypt,
we can reacquaint ourselves with the dead.
We all suffer loss.
And none of us can escape death.
Then, what is the fascination with reclaiming
that which has already passed into the beyond?</text>
<text id="40530000">Ring granted protection by Kremmel,
god of Struggle.
The ring's spikes drive into the wearer's
skin, so that each blow taken fuels spite
toward the perpetrator.

When damage is taken, the ring retaliates
and inflicts damage upon enemy.</text>
<text id="40540000">A soft string-like ring tied around the finger.
Makes it easier for invaders to find your world.

Who would create such a ring, and why?
Perhaps the answer is better left unknown.</text>
<text id="40550000">A precious ring which grants the protection
of  Quella, god of dreams.
Makes its wearer appear as a phantom,
misleading invaders.

He who sets the trap must be wary.
For traps are known to spring upon their owners.</text>
<text id="40560000">A ring of red stone.
The stone is misshaped, however imperceptibly.
Renders certain equipment invisible.

Do not judge your foes by their appearance.
He who approaches without a sword
carries two behind his back.</text>
<text id="40570000">A ring of black stone.
The stone is misshaped, however imperceptibly.
Renders certain equipment invisible.

Do not judge your foes by their appearance.
He who approaches without a sword
carries two behind his back.</text>
<text id="40610000">Ring worn by Rhoy the Explorer.
Hear the inner voices of surrounding foes.

Useful for locating hidden enemies,
and perhaps for a few other things, as well.</text>
<text id="40620000">A ring of yellow stone.
The stone is misshaped, however imperceptibly.
Renders certain equipment invisible.

Do not judge your foes by their appearance.
He who approaches without a sword
carries two behind his back.</text>
<text id="40700000">Ring of the Rat King covenant.

Join this covenant and wear this ring
to lure trespassers of the Rat King's territory
into your world.

If you receive this ring,
rejoice in the opportunity to demonstrate
your allegiance to an eminently noble being.</text>
<text id="40710000">Ring of the Bell Keeper covenant.

Join this covenant and wear this ring
to be automatically summoned to the world
of an invader of the bell keepers' domain.

The twin bells symbolize the bond between
two lovers who could never be united.
The bell keepers are their eternal guardians.
For that is their love; that is their curse.</text>
<text id="40720000">Ring of the Blue Sentinel covenant.

Join this covenant and wear this ring
to be automatically summoned
to the worlds of blue apostles
who have been invaded by dark spirits.

The ring is engraved with the crest of the
Way of Blue, symbolizing the dignified oath to
protect each world's master from dark spirits.</text>
<text id="40730000">Ring of the Brotherhood of Blood covenant.

This ring is nothing special. Perhaps,
in the end, an oath is but a window
into the ambitions of the oath taker.

If you have taken this oath,
then you know what you want.
To be soaked in the blood of your kind.</text>
<text id="40740000">Ring of the Way of Blue covenant.
Increases HP slightly.

The Way of Blue is not a developed religion.
It is a humble prayer that spread naturally
amongst those seeking help.

When apostles of Blue are invaded by
dark spirits, they can receive assistance
from masters of other worlds.</text>
<text id="40750000">Ring of the Pilgrims of Dark covenant.
Increases the attack strength of hexes,
but casting them reduces HP.

What is dark?
Perhaps we already know.
We fear dark, yet find solace in it.

Those who join this covenant can see
the hidden Dark Chasm.</text>
<text id="40760000">Ring of the Company of Champions covenant.
Greatly increases attack power of bare hands.

The souls of fallen heroes found along the way
salute those who scoff at danger and bravely
seek the harder path.

Joining this covenant strengthens the enemies
within your world.</text>
<text id="40770000">Ring of the Heirs to the Sun covenant.
Slightly increases miracle attack power.

Worship of the sun, now a lost belief,
was once widespread amongst great warriors.

Members of this covenant can leave their
golden signs to be more easily summoned
to join brethren in jolly cooperation.</text>
<text id="40780000">Ring of the Dragon Remnants covenant.
Slightly increases Estus Flask HP recovery.

Possessing a dragon scale is proof of its owner's
prowess. Strength should always be displayed
boldly, and meted out justly.

Members of the covenant who bear dragon scales
can fight with one another. The survivor of the
duel claims the dragon scale of the opponent.</text>
<text id="41000000">Ring depicting a simpleton's flower.
Wearer becomes invisible while rolling.

This ring was worn by the soldiers of
the Old Iron King, said to be blessed
with divine protection.

This ring only does one thing, but with
ingenuity it can be fearsomely effective.</text>
<text id="41010000">An oddly deformed iron ring.
Increases the strength of its wearer.

The Old Iron King ruled over
a great age of iron.

The King's power allowed him
to mold iron freely, as if he held sway
over the forces of life and creation.</text>
<text id="41020000">An oddly deformed iron ring.
Increases the dexterity of its wearer.

The Old Iron King ruled over
a great age of iron.

The King's power allowed him
to mold iron freely, as if he held sway
over the forces of life and creation.</text>
<text id="41030000">Ring of the guardians of Eleum Loyce.
Attacks greatly decrease enemy stamina.

Eleum Loyce existed to subdue
the raging flame, but when the ivory
gates were flung open, the land grew cold
and lifeless.</text>
<text id="41040000">Ring depicting a hand grasping a stone.
Increases magic attack,
but reduces physical defense.

The origin of this ring is unknown,
but its design suggests one of the
darker deities.

Effective use of this ring requires
skill on the part of its wearer.</text>
<text id="41050000">Ring depicting a hand grasping a stone.
Increases lightning attack,
but reduces physical defense.

The origin of this ring is unknown,
but its design suggests one of the
darker deities.

Effective use of this ring requires
skill on the part of its wearer.</text>
<text id="41060000">Ring depicting a hand grasping a stone.
Increases fire attack,
but reduces physical defense.

The origin of this ring is unknown,
but its design suggests one of the
darker deities.

Effective use of this ring requires
skill on the part of its wearer.</text>
<text id="41070000">Ring depicting a hand grasping a stone.
Increases dark attack,
but reduces physical defense.

The origin of this ring is unknown,
but its design suggests one of the
darker deities.

Effective use of this ring requires
skill on the part of its wearer.</text>
<text id="41090000">Ring of Raime the traitor.
Reduces stamina loss when blocking
with shield.

Raime was an agile swordsman who
served King Vendrick, but after resigning
from his post, he reconsidered his
way of life and was born again as
a stalwart warrior.</text>
<text id="41100000">Ring of Flynn, the infamous thief.
Utilizes the strength of the wind,
such that lower equip load proportionally
increases physical attack.

Flynn was known as a tiny fighter
who packed a mighty punch.
Even the most skilled warriors
in the land failed to capture him.</text>
<text id="41110000">Ring crafted from the chains of the Embedded.
Receive various benefits, but at the cost
of increased damage taken.

The chains of the Embedded have the power
to transform people into slaves of pleasure,
setting them on a path of ruin.
This ring augments that peculiar quality.</text>
<text id="41120000">A ring bearing a sharp stud.
Appear human when a phantom.

This ring jabs into the skin, creating 
a throbbing pain that serves as
a constant reminder of one's humanity.</text>
<text id="41130000">Ring of Sir Yorgh, who sought the blood
of a dragon and invaded Shulva.
Can deflect spells.

When Sir Yorgh faced Sinh, the slumbering
dragon, he drew blood with a flash of his steel,
but Sinh responded by spewing forth the
poison that had long brewed within him,
blanketing the city in a miasmic cloud.</text>
<text id="42000000">A ring affixed with an open vessel.
The vessel insatiably absorbs souls
in place of its wearer, who is left
unaware even of their collection.

All things are rooted in souls,
but what drives our thirst for them?
Abstinence from this elixir may be
the truest homage to an enduring self.</text>
</entries>