<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<entries>
<text id="1000000">A standard dagger.

Has only modest attack and short reach,
but can be jabbed in rapid succession.

With a powerful critical attack, this is
a potent weapon in the hands of the capable.</text>
<text id="1010000">A knife with a slightly broad single edge.
Its tip is shaped to leave a wound that
won't easily close.

Designed for unsavory work,
and beloved by those of unsavory ilk.</text>
<text id="1040000">Dagger forged from the soul of Mytha,
the Baneful Queen. Coated with a potent poison.

Mytha was the fairest queen in the land,
until something unhinged her.
Was it the poison found deep within the earth,
or the passion that consumed her heart?</text>
<text id="1050000">Dagger used by those who lurk in the shadows.
Formed by bending a sword into the
shape of a dagger.

In Mirrah, the land of knights, there exists
an order of shadow knights who carry out
assassinations in the cover of darkness.

Those who fled even the order of shadow
knights had rejected all forms of honor,
and resorted to unseemly mercenary work.</text>
<text id="1060000">Dagger with a crooked tip.

A common accessory of thieves,
shoddily crafted and without much bite.</text>
<text id="1070000">A broken straight sword.
Handled as a dagger due to its length.

This inexpensive sword is terribly worn,
but nevertheless a favorite amongst thieves.</text>
<text id="1100000">Unlike standard weapons, this dagger is
intended for parrying.

Accomplishments are forever out of reach
to those who constantly fear failure.
A true warrior hones his body and mind,
and peers far beyond immediate hardship.</text>
<text id="1110000">Knife of the manikins of Harvest Valley.

The peculiar art of puppetry
is a vestige of the two lost lands. 
The Queen, entranced by poison,
used it to beckon unknowing souls
to the defiled valley.</text>
<text id="1130000">A dagger fashioned from rare geisteel,
boasting an unusually long blade.

Geisteel was a precious alloy created in the
eastern land of Mirrah, its composition long
kept secret from foreign lands.

That is, until Chancellor Wellager was ordered
by King Vendrick to grant the gifted blacksmith
Llewellyn a lifetime contract, whatever the cost,
in order to introduce the rare alloy to Drangleic.</text>
<text id="1140000">Dagger used by fume sorcerers
when a battle draws too close for comfort.

An ordinary-looking dagger laced with magic.
Strengthens spells, but also increases
vulnerability to them.</text>
<text id="1150000">A sharp dagger.

Crafted to facilitate assassinations
with a focused backstab.
One true strike with this blade,
and your work will be done.</text>
<text id="1160000">Short sword wielded by retainers
in the Garrison Ward.

Long ago, the retainers attended to the
priestesses, but with their disappearance,
the retainers were left to wander
frigid Eleum Loyce without purpose.</text>
<text id="1200000">Straight sword with its blade broken near in half.

Nearly useless in battle, but "nearly useless"
trumps "empty-handed".</text>
<text id="1210000">A small straight sword.
Longer than a dagger, but still lightweight.
Widely used, as it requires no particular strength.

A reasonable choice that will suffice in many
situations, but not the thing to take along if you
expect to face any serious challenge.</text>
<text id="1220000">Standard straight sword.

This straight sword is sufficient in most
respects, and effective in most situations if
wielded properly. Those who aspire to master the
sword are certain to wield this at some point
during their journey.</text>
<text id="1230000">Standard straight sword.

This straight sword is sufficient in most
respects, and effective in most situations if
wielded properly. Those who aspire to master
the sword are certain to wield this at some
point during their journey.</text>
<text id="1240000">Inexpensive straight sword.
Standard issue for Drangleic foot soldiers.

No masterpiece, this weapon won't be used to
fend off any truly threatening foe.</text>
<text id="1250000">A sword with a segmented blade.
When swung, its segments separate
and the sword strikes in a whipping slash.

Crafted with a rare magnetic stone of
remarkable strength only found deep within
caves of the Gutter.</text>
<text id="1260000">Straight sword wielded by possessed armor.
Has a heated blade imbued with fire.

These suits of armor were once decorations,
until the black fog ruling the tower seized
control of them.</text>
<text id="1270000">Straight sword wielded by Varangians
and engraved with a skull.

A former king launched a campaign to
capture these terrors of the high seas,
but rather than imprison them, forced
them into hard labor at No-man's Wharf.

The king, wracked with fear and suspicion,
began to see the progenitor of the curse in
anything and everything. During his reign,
sorcerers in particular suffered dreadful
persecution.</text>
<text id="1280000">Straight sword wielded by Leydia apostles.
Imbued with a special magic that makes the
Blue Flame both a sword and magic catalyst.
Execute a strong attack to emit magic.

The Leydia apostles, adept at magic, wielded
unique weapons but were hunted down as
traitors.

Effect: use sorcery (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1290000">Straight sword forged from
the soul of the fume knight, and
imbued with the Dark of Nadalia.

The exile swordsman Raime had the
ability to expunge the black fog,
but chose instead to live alongside it,
in the company of the child of Dark
that haunts his sword.</text>
<text id="1320000">Straight sword originating in Heide.
A special alloy makes it very durable.

The composition of the alloy of these swords
remains a mystery, but in Drangleic the attempt
to imitate it resulted in the similar bradden
steel.</text>
<text id="1330000">Straight sword of warrior Vengarl of Forossa.

This sword is battle-worn and terribly rusted,
but remains a deadly weapon owing to
its incredible weight.

Legend has it that it was built to test the
limits of the strength of Forossa knights,
until Vengarl swung it about like a wooden
plaything, claiming ownership by demonstration.</text>
<text id="1350000">In legend, this oddly-shaped straight sword
is said to be forged from the black dragon's tail.

As it is told, the black dragon lost its tail to
a brave warrior in a magnificent battle,
and the tail was later used to forge
several legendary weapons.</text>
<text id="1360000">A well-forged long sword.
Of unknown origin, and exhibiting
no special power, but sturdily crafted.

Perhaps it does not live up to its name,
but nevertheless, merely wielding this sword
seems to cause warmth to well up within
one's bosom.</text>
<text id="1370000">An extremely sturdy pitch-black straight sword.

Colossal warriors staunchly watch over
the shrine, ready to defend its resident,
or allow one worthy enough to be granted
audience.</text>
<text id="1380000">Straight sword wielded by ashen warriors.
As brittle is it appears.

The jagged edge of this tired and worn blade
tears into the hides of foes.</text>
<text id="1390000">Sword of Fabian, knight of Eleum Loyce.
This blade, crafted with ivory ore native
to the land, harnesses souls to slash at foes.

Sir Fabian led the loyal knights of Eleum Loyce
straight into the depths of chaos to exterminate
the terrible things that dwelled there,
but not one of the selfless knights returned.</text>
<text id="1400000">A large thrusting sword with a blade.

The sturdy, slender long blade is designed
to pierce the armor of enemies, and its
strong attack can even inflict damage upon
foes hiding behind shields.

Though primarily a thrusting sword, its blade
can also be used to slash your enemy.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1410000">A slightly stubby thrusting sword.
Has a sharp, sturdy blade designed for thrusting.

The Mail Breaker has limited reach,
but a powerful critical attack.
Effective against foes donning thick armor
or with naturally hard skin.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1420000">Rapier of darkness and chaos.

Once, a brilliant young sorcerer cast away his
earthly desires, devoting himself entirely to the
Dark that bewitched him.

Nebulous, inky and serene, the Dark holds an
allure matched only by the fear it strikes
in men's hearts. Could it be nature,
holding a mirror to mankind?</text>
<text id="1430000">Thrusting sword forged from the soul
of the Duke's Dear Freja.
Its needle-like blade can easily pierce the
seams of the toughest armor.

Supposedly, the duke himself, an eccentric soul
fascinated with spiders, went on to take a form
that was far from human.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1440000">Thrusting sword of Chancellor Wellager.
Forged with rare geisteel.

A masterpiece of the great blacksmith Llewellyn
that he brought along as a gift when he
left Mirrah for Drangleic.</text>
<text id="1500000">A standard thrusting sword.

Thrusting swords are light swords with fine tips
that can be used while holding up a shield,
and are effective for parrying.

Use quick thrusts to damage hard-skinned foes.
Also effective when fighting in narrow spaces.</text>
<text id="1520000">Manscorpion Tark's thrusting sword.

The scorpion pincer guard contains poison,
which is injected into foes pierced by the blade.

Tark's past is a thing obscure.
But then again, do any of us know who we are,
let alone what we may have been?</text>
<text id="1530000">An exquisitely decorated rapier.
Said to belong to a prince who appears
in an ancient tale.

There are numerous variations of the story
of the prince who wandered the lands and
eventually became Undead.
The majority of these tales end in tragedy,
but there are some exceptions.</text>
<text id="1580000">Rapier wielded by sorcerers of Eleum Loyce.
Imbued with a magic that is released
with a strong attack.

A great protective wall was erected to
protect Eleum Loyce from the encroaching
chaos, and these sorcerers were among its
defenders.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1600000">A standard curved sword.

Each slash of a curved sword does
less damage than a straight sword, but can deal
a series of hits in flowing succession.

The sharp blade is effective at causing bleeding,
but is soon dulled. Beware when facing
rock-solid foes.</text>
<text id="1610000">A uniquely-shaped curved sword.
The name of its creator is unknown,
but he was clearly a true craftsman.

The curved blade is designed to reach around
an opponent's shield to deal damage.
Use the strong attack to utilize.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1620000">A curved sword forged from the soul
of the Flexile Sentry. Once straight,
but later twisted to reflect its warped owner.

The sentry crammed inmates of the
overflowing Bastille onto a rickety ship,
and cast them out to the open sea.

The majority of them drowned or starved,
but a few hardy survivors made land
to the south, and imparted their knowledge
of sorcery to the people there.</text>
<text id="1630000">Curved sword forged from the soul of Alsanna.
Formed by two curious blades,
this sword can restore an ally's HP
with a hit from its strong attack.

The enigmatic Alsanna quietly found a place
at the Ivory King's side, and when his strength
was fully drained, he conferred this sword,
inscribed with the name of the land, to her.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1640000">Small curved sword of the
manikins of Harvest Valley.

The peculiar art of puppetry
is a vestige of the two lost lands. 
The Queen, entranced by poison,
used it to beckon unknowing souls
to the defiled valley.</text>
<text id="1650000">A small curved sword with a narrow blade.

The rapid slashing of the lightweight scimitar
hardly allows the victim to catch a breath.
Has a sharp blade, but is rather ineffective
against armor and hard skin.</text>
<text id="1660000">Curved sword of warrior Vengarl of Forossa.

This sword is battle-worn and terribly rusted,
but remains a deadly weapon owing to
its incredible weight.

Legend has it that it was built to test the
limits of the strength of Forossa knights,
until Vengarl swung it about like a wooden
plaything, claiming ownership by demonstration.</text>
<text id="1670000">Curved sword forged from
the soul of the Duke's Dear Freja.
Its blade is coated with a sticky silk
that is cast with each strong attack,
slowing enemy movement.

Supposedly, the duke himself, an eccentric soul
fascinated with spiders, went on to take a
form that was far from human.

Effect: movement slowdown (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1680000">Scimitar of Laddersmith Gilligan.

Nothing notable about this weapon,
except perhaps the luxurious jewels
embedded in the hilt. If your aim is
to appear dazzling on the battlefield,
this might just do just the trick.</text>
<text id="1690000">Crafted at the Lindelt Monastery to replicate
an ancient, sacred scimitar characterized by
its uniquely shaped tip.

When a true master wields this scimitar,
their graceful chained attacks are described
as mystical dances, and their deadly slashes
as lingering nightmares.</text>
<text id="1700000">A katana of unknown origin.
Crafted with a peculiar yet refined technique.

The finely-sharpened blade of a katana
slices with unmistakable smoothness,
but should be wielded with caution, as its
delicate constitution means it's easily worn.</text>
<text id="1710000">A katana of unknown origin.
Crafted with a peculiar yet refined technique.

The extremely long blade allows for strikes
from great distance, but its construction
makes it extremely fragile.</text>
<text id="1720000">A katana of unknown origin.
Damage to foes also damages its owner.

The peculiar pattern upon the blade suggests
the sinister nature of this cursed blade.
It is an alluring vortex, and a lonely soul. 

Effect: attacks also damage player</text>
<text id="1730000">Blacksteel katana wielded by Alonne Knights.
One of the sturdiest types of katana,
preferred by masters of the quick-draw.

In the heyday of his land, the Old Iron King
fancied entertaining dubious and eccentric
guests from faraway lands.

Most of them were charlatans, but among
the riff-raff was an unusual knight from
the far east. He trained the Iron King's men
in the sword, in obeisance to his new lord.</text>
<text id="1740000">A katana with a terribly worn blade.
Appears useless, but is in fact coated
with deadly poison.

This sword has claimed countless victims,
and the bloodstains upon its blade have
turned to poison.</text>
<text id="1760000">Katana of Grave Warden Agdayne.
Has a crystal-clear blade and a strong attack
that slices through enemy shields.

This katana was originally wielded by
the one who gave us the first death,
and still exists imperfectly between planes.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1770000">The katana of a berserker, by its name.

The thick, shiny black blade cuts exquisitely.
Its origins and owner are unknown, but at some
point the blade became known by this name.</text>
<text id="1790000">Katana forged from the soul of Sir Alonne.
The captivating, undulating design serves to
enhance this weapon's mystical allure.

Alonne came from the east, and soon became
the Iron King's most trusted knight.
When he departed, the Old Iron King bequeathed
Sir Alonne's name to his iron warriors.</text>
<text id="1800000">A standard greatsword.

Heavy greatswords are designed to
be wielded two-handed.

Normally swung in large arcs and effective
against multiple foes, be wary that such attacks
leave the wielder wide open.</text>
<text id="1810000">A greatsword with an undulating blade.
The unique shape is designed to pare the flesh,
and is highly effective at causing bleeding.

Flamberge literally means "flame blade,"
but it also seems to bear a certain creature's
likeness.</text>
<text id="1820000">A very large greatsword.
Very heavy, and designed for use with both
hands.

Allows for broad attacks that are effective
against multiple foes. Requires great strength
and experience to handle effectively.</text>
<text id="1830000">An ancient greatsword of unknown origin.
This sword was passed down through
generations, until it reached Gordin,
wandering knight of Forossa,
and was lost upon his death.

Uncannily, every last one of the prominent
swordsmen who inherited this weapon
was left-handed.</text>
<text id="1850000">Greatsword of Drummond, Royal Army Captain.
An old and unadorned sword, perhaps,
but the pride and joy of this venerable captain.

An heirloom passed from grandfather to father,
and then from father to son. Drummond,
and those before him, used this sword to
repel those who would threaten their great land.</text>
<text id="1860000">A greatsword forged from the soul
of the Looking Glass Knight.
Strong attack unleashes its latent power.

Fearing something wicked, the King fled
the castle and never returned. But his warrior,
forever true to his command, stands ready
to expunge those who would challenge him.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1870000">The blade of this greatsword shines like
the brilliant rays of the moon. In the oldest
legends, rarely spoken of today, it is said that
the sword was born of a great white being.

Then, what explains this lifeless weapon?
Perhaps there has been some mistake...</text>
<text id="1871000">The blade of this greatsword shines like
the brilliant rays of the moon. In the oldest
legends, rarely spoken of today, it is said that
the sword was born of a great white being.

The strong attack unleashes its strength,
launching a wave of moonlight.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="1880000">Greatsword of the Primal Knights
that defend Drangleic castle.

The brutish and mighty Primal Knights
wield this sword like a feather-light twig,
but to the ordinary warrior it is a chore
to even hold up, owing to its great weight.

Terrible experiments were said to have
taken place in a hidden manor in Drangleic.
The mastermind presiding over the
deeds was known as Lord Aldia.</text>
<text id="1900000">Greatsword of Vendrick, King of Drangleic.
The strength of this sword is relative to
the number of souls possessed by its wielder.

One fragment of Dark, having taken human shape,
became obsessed with the King's soul.
Impelled by its own cravings, it sought souls,
and strove to make the strength of the Giants
its own.

Effect: attack boosted by souls held</text>
<text id="1910000">Greatsword issued to the proud knights
of Mirrah's official order.
This one was wielded by Lucatiel.

This greatsword demands advanced skill
in a rare and unique sword technique.

A tiny message is inscribed in the blade,
a promise to someone special.</text>
<text id="1911000">Greatsword issued to the proud knights of
Mirrah's official order.

This greatsword demands advanced skill
in a rare and unique sword technique.

A tiny message is inscribed in the blade,
a promise to someone special.</text>
<text id="1920000">In legend, this oddly-shaped long sword
is said to be forged from the black dragon's tail.

As it is told, the black dragon lost its tail to
a brave warrior in a magnificent battle,
and the tail was later used to forge
several legendary weapons.</text>
<text id="1930000">Greatsword wielded by knights who served
a lord of light in a long-forgotten age.

Even after their flesh was charred by
flame, they remained as strong as ever,
and stood watch, challenging visitors to
their land.</text>
<text id="1940000">Greatsword of the royal swordsmen.
Its undulating blade draws blood from its foes.

Despite the magnificence of this weapon,
it was terribly inadequate in the war against
the mighty Giants.</text>
<text id="1950000">An old undated greatsword.

Wielded by a warrior from a time so ancient
that there exists no record of his endeavors.
Has extremely low durability.

Sometimes, just as a thing falls to pieces,
it unleashes its last flash of great power...</text>
<text id="1960000">Greatsword wielded by the Throne Defender.
Unleash its true power to enwreath in magic.

The Defender has stood by the throne for ages.
Will his wait be worth the while?</text>
<text id="1970000">Greatsword wielded by the Throne Watcher.
Unleash its true power to enwreath in magic.

The Watcher has stood by the throne for ages.
Will his wait be worth the while?</text>
<text id="1980000">Sword that opens the Embedded's door.
Shaped like a weapon, but is in fact a key.

Plunge the key into the Embedded
to bring a rhapsodic end to his fate.

The once-human Embedded, realizing that he
could never resist the temptations of the flesh,
bound himself eternally with chains. Since then,
he has awaited the day that somebody will
find this key, and bury it within his bosom.</text>
<text id="1990000">Greatsword wielded by the Drakeblood Knights,
led by the honorable Sir Yorgh. The insignia
chiseled upon its hilt symbolizes dragon's blood.

To the Drakeblood Knights, fresh dragon blood
was sacrosanct. They believed that by obtaining it,
they could achieve a true understanding of life,
transcending their own banal existence.</text>
<text id="1995000">Greatsword of the Knights of Loyce.

The Knights of Loyce were commanded
to strike down each malformed terror that
arose from Chaos, and they would not
hesitate even if it were their own king.</text>
<text id="1996000">A charred greatsword of the Knights of Loyce,
its blade burned black by flame.

These Knights of Loyce lacked all sense of self,
and were driven only by the urge to expunge
any who might disturb the flame, even
former compatriots.</text>
<text id="1997000">Greatsword of the Forlorn,
who wander the land of the Undead.

The King's elder brother Aldia sought to
overcome the curse through means
unalike his sibling's.

The Forlorn were born of
Aldia's sinful infatuation.</text>
<text id="2000000">A crude hand axe.

More of a tool than a weapon.
Its short range necessitates close-range,
and therefore perilous, combat.
Does a respectable amount of damage, however,
considering its relatively light weight.</text>
<text id="2010000">An axe crafted for battle.

Axes generally deal more damage than swords,
but each swing leaves its wielder vulnerable.

One is tempted to swing axes with wild abandon,
but in fact their effective manipulation demands
caution and precise timing.</text>
<text id="2020000">An axe of bandits of the Forossan outskirts.
Very sturdily built for the armament of a bandit.

When Forossa fell to war, its citizens were left
landless, and entirely to their own devices.
Many were reduced to thievery, while Forossan
knights scattered to other lands as sellswords.</text>
<text id="2030000">An axe wielded by Drangleic infantry.

A makeshift, crude weapon that deals an
underwhelming amount of damage.</text>
<text id="2070000">An axe used by the nomadic Gyrm.

At first glance this axe appears crude,
but with further examination one sees the
fine craftsmanship of Gyrm blacksmiths.
Quite heavy for a human, but flung about
with reckless abandon by the Gyrm.</text>
<text id="2080000">The beloved black axe of the gallant
Shieldless Lothian, formerly of Forossa.

No warrior matched the ferocity of unbeatable
Lothian, but he abruptly retired from the
battlefield and was never heard from again.
Some say that he grew tired of the frailty
of human foes, and set off to slay the
legendary dragon.</text>
<text id="2090000">An oddly large butcher's knife.
Not your standard weapon, but certainly
deadly enough to be utilized as one.
Absorbs the HP of foes.

Who in their right mind would create such
a thing? Perhaps it is best not to dwell
on how it was likely used in the past.

Effect: HP absorb</text>
<text id="2100000">A silver-black sickle imbued with the
power of dark. The large arced blade
reaches around shields and inflicts damage.

The grave wardens vowed to ensure the
tranquility of those who slumber in the
Undead Crypt. If one dares disturb them,
the grave wardens make no allowance for
stature or riches, and will readily bury them
along with the others.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="2200000">A bronze greataxe with a crescent-shaped blade.
Its long handle gives the weapon great reach.

One senses that this axe was once imbued
with a sacred power, but only traces of it
remain.

Perhaps those who blessed this axe
are no longer with us.</text>
<text id="2210000">A greataxe wielded with both hands.

This greataxe, crafted with a gigantic, weighty
blade, is designed to inflict heavy damage,
and requires inhuman strength to handle.

Each swing of the greataxe requires the full
force of the body, leaving the wielder wide open.
Mastering this weapon will require the
most thorough training of both body and mind.</text>
<text id="2220000">A greataxe of bandits of the Forossan outskirts.
Very sturdily built for the armament of a bandit.

When Forossa fell to war, its citizens were left
landless, and entirely to their own devices.
Many were reduced to thievery, while Forossan
knights scattered to other lands as sellswords.</text>
<text id="2240000">Greataxe wielded by Lion Clan warriors.

The finely-crafted blade cuts smoothly,
evidence that the lion clansmen
are much more than vulgar beasts.</text>
<text id="2250000">Greataxe forged from the Last Giant's soul.

This weapon resembles a primitive stone tool,
but is quite powerful owing to its immense size.

King Vendrick disappeared as of the war with
the Giants reached its ferocious peak,
leaving his castle and people in turmoil.
Some swear that upon hearing the news,
the Queen's face remained as still as her portrait.</text>
<text id="2260000">A greataxe used by the nomadic Gyrm.

At first glance this greataxe appears crude,
but with further examination one sees the
fine craftsmanship of Gyrm blacksmiths.
Quite heavy for a human, but swung about
with reckless abandon by the Gyrm.</text>
<text id="2290000">In legend, this oddly-shaped greataxe
is said to be forged from the black dragon's tail.

As it is told, the black dragon lost its tail to
a brave warrior in a magnificent battle,
and the tail was later used to forge
several legendary weapons.</text>
<text id="2300000">Greataxe wielded by knights who served
a lord of light in a long-forgotten age.

Even after their flesh was charred by
flame, they remained as strong as ever,
and stood watch, challenging visitors to
their land.</text>
<text id="2310000">An extremely sturdy pitch-black greataxe.

Colossal warriors staunchly watch over
the shrine, ready to defend its resident,
or allow one worthy enough to be granted
audience.</text>
<text id="2400000">A wooden club.

A primitive weapon, to be certain,
but quite powerful, so much so that
it can break the guard of a shield.</text>
<text id="2410000">A club fitted with a head
crafted for battle.

The mace is the archetypal blunt weapon.
It has a primitive appearance, but also
many advantages, including the ability to
break the guard of a shield.

Keep the proper distance from your foe,
and this can be a very effective weapon.</text>
<text id="2420000">A club fitted with a spiked head.

The spikes of this blunt weapon cause bleeding.
Normally wielded by clerics, but clearly intended
to draw blood.</text>
<text id="2430000">A wooden club headed with nails.

Designed as a deadlier club,
and certainly offers a stronger attack,
but this club also seems quick to fall apart,
perhaps due to its shoddy craftsmanship.</text>
<text id="2440000">An old smithing hammer.

Looks like a typical hammer,
but is in fact incredibly sturdy.
Some say it was the hammer used long ago
by a famed blacksmith of yore.</text>
<text id="2470000">The mace of formerly high-ranking clerics.
It is combined with a sacred chime, and can
cast miracles and hexes with strong attack.

The clerics held venerated positions once,
but now, their souls wander aimlessly
in the depths of a murky darkness.

Effect: use miracle and hex (strong attack)</text>
<text id="2500000">An ordinary kitchen ladle.

He who chooses this as a weapon either
faces extenuating circumstances or has
an odd sense of humor. If you care for
your life, leave this one in the kitchen.</text>
<text id="2520000">An ordinary hammer used by a blacksmith.

Can be used as a hammer, but not to
any great effect, as it was made to shape
weapons, not serve as one.</text>
<text id="2530000">In legend, this oddly-shaped war hammer
is said to be forged from the black dragon's tail.

As it is told, the black dragon lost its tail to
a brave warrior in a magnificent battle,
and the tail was later used to forge
several legendary weapons.</text>
<text id="2540000">Hammer used by Aldian acolytes.
Not used as a weapon, but as an instrument
to dissect the bodies of the victims of
their experimentation.

They say that Lord Aldia was the King's
elder brother and helped found Drangleic,
but he later lost interest in the land's fortunes.</text>
<text id="2560000">A club forged from the soul of the
Flexile Sentry. The spikes covering its length
are as vile as the sentry itself.

The sentry crammed inmates of the
overflowing Bastille onto a rickety ship,
and cast them out to the open sea.

The majority of them drowned or starved,
but a few hardy survivors made land
to the south, and imparted their knowledge
of sorcery to the people there.</text>
<text id="2600000">A large wooden club.

Not an elegant weapon by any means,
but a beastly thing with plenty of weight
to easily break a shielded defense.</text>
<text id="2610000">A pickaxe used for mining.
Not intended as a weapon,
but packs a powerful punch.

This tool, designed to crush hard rock,
can easily puncture weaker forms of armor.</text>
<text id="2620000">A giant wooden club made from the
branches of a towering tree.

Designed to smash foes. Simple but
terribly effective against common shields.</text>
<text id="2630000">A great hammer used by the nomadic Gyrm.

A makeshift weapon created
from a blacksmith's anvil.
As heavy as it appears.

Crafted rather shoddily, but each hit landed
is certain to inflict serious damage.</text>
<text id="2660000">Great hammer forged from the soul of
the Old Iron King.
The tip is formed of molten rock.

The corpse of the Old Iron King became
the vessel that bred Ichorous Earth.

The heavy rock tip is formed of cooled
magma, with a still-smoldering core.
Strong attack releases its inner power.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="2670000">The skull of some unidentified creature.
Swing as a great hammer to use as a weapon.

Possibly the skull of a dragon.
A rare specimen, likely too rare to
be swung about willy-nilly. </text>
<text id="2680000">A giant dragon tooth used as a great hammer.
As solid as a boulder, this tooth is said
to be taken from a dragon, but the truth
of this claim is unclear.

What is certain is that it bears some mystical
power, and its wielder gains resistance to
magic and fire.

Effect: resistance to magic and fire</text>
<text id="2690000">Club of the Giants that besieged Drangleic.
Nothing more than a boulder bound to a
tree, but a very powerful, if primitive, weapon.

King Vendrick, in adherence to Queen
Nashandra's counsel, led his armies north
in an effort to subjugate the Giants, and
claim their powerful souls for his own.</text>
<text id="2700000">One of the malformed weapons developed
in Aldia. Swung like a great hammer.
Appears to be a fragment of a giant shell,
but its precise origins are unknown.

The peculiar figure known as Lord Aldia
attempted to uncover the secrets of life itself,
and viewed the Undead as a key to this mystery.</text>
<text id="2710000">Great hammer made of unknown materials.
Perhaps it is stone, or even wood.

The origins of its name are unclear.
Its tremendous weight suggests that it
was never intended for humans.
Perhaps it was an offering to the
demons that appear in legend.</text>
<text id="2720000">A mace normally issued to clerics
of the Archdrake sect of Lindelt.

The land of Lindelt is governed by
stringent laws, and those who dare defy
them are punished without mercy.

It is often the sinful who seek piety,
spurred only by a selfish desire for salvation.</text>
<text id="2730000">An undated great hammer.

Wielded by a warrior from a time so ancient
that there exists no record of his endeavors.
Has extremely low durability.

Sometimes, just as a thing falls to pieces,
it unleashes its last flash of great power...</text>
<text id="2740000">An extremely sturdy pitch-black great hammer.

Colossal warriors staunchly watch over
the shrine, ready to defend its resident,
or allow one worthy enough to be granted
audience.</text>
<text id="2750000">Great hammer of the Royal Aegis.
The power of this hammer's blessing has
not faded completely, despite its being
exposed to the dark of the Undead Crypt.
Unleash its latent power with a strong attack.

Sir Velstadt, known as the Royal Aegis,
gave himself to the King in both life and death.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="2760000">A mace wielded by sanctum soldiers.

This mace was corrupted by poison
when Sinh, the slumbering dragon, awoke.

A mere mortal would be asphyxiated
by the poison emitted when wielding
this mace, but for the noxious sanctum
soldiers, this fact matters none.</text>
<text id="2800000">A standard spear.

Spears allow one to attack a foe from
a distance, and while holding up a shield.

Thrusting attacks are effective even against
opponents with strong defense, but they have
a narrow point of contact and won't effectively
break through a shielded defense.</text>
<text id="2810000">A spear with winged lugs.
Longer than standard spears, allowing for
attacks from further away.

Thrusting attacks are effective even against
opponents with high defense, but they have
a narrow point of contact and won't effectively
break through a shielded defense.</text>
<text id="2820000">A spear with an extended pole.
Offers a very long reach, even for a spear,
allowing for attacks from safer distances.

Traditionally a weapon of regimental rather
than single combat due to its unwieldiness.
However, if you can manage to effectively
step around an opponent, they will hardly
have a chance to hit back.</text>
<text id="2830000">A spear with a broad blade.
The blade is widened and given extra weight
to allow for slashing.

The broader attacks of the partizan, however,
make it less effective in narrow spaces.</text>
<text id="2840000">Spear of the castle stone soldiers.

Sir Velstadt could always be found at
the King's side, and followed him upon his exit.
The knights in his service waited patiently
for his return, until they turned to stone.</text>
<text id="2850000">A spear said to have been forged in Aldia.
Contains the power of a great flame,
which is unleashed in a strong attack.

The mysterious Lord Aldia secluded himself
inside a manor to conduct various experiments.
Those invited to the manor disappeared,
replaced over time with malformed beasts
that roamed its halls.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="2855000">Spear wielded by Sir Yorgh during his
invasion of the Sanctum City.

After his defeat of the Sunken King,
Sir Yorgh pierced Sinh, the slumbering dragon,
with this spear to claim its blood.

But Sinh immediately awoke, spewing
a poisonous fog that blanketed the
city in death, and Sir Yorgh disappeared
into the Eternal Sanctum.</text>
<text id="2860000">A silver-black spear imbued with the
power of dark.

The grave wardens vowed to ensure the
tranquility of those who slumber in the
Undead Crypt. If one dares disturb them,
the grave wardens make no allowance for
stature or riches, and will readily bury them
along with the others.</text>
<text id="2870000">A spear originating in Heide.
A special alloy makes it very durable.

The composition of the alloy of these spears
remains a mystery, but in Drangleic the attempt
to imitate it resulted in the similar bradden
steel.</text>
<text id="2880000">A long spear wielded by Pate.
This appears to be a very ordinary spear,
but seems to have accumulated power over
the course of countless battles.

It is not always advisable to stand out.
Especially if you have something to hide.</text>
<text id="2890000">A trident wielded by an old sorcerer.
The tip is sharpened so smoothly
that it suggests a degree of madness.

Use strong attack to perform a power-
channeling dance, the madness of which
boosts the morale of nearby allies.

Effect: attack boost (Two-handed strong attack)</text>
<text id="2895000">A two-pronged spear that imitates a weapon
mentioned in an ancient text.

Gargoyles are said to guard castles and forts
from ill fortune, and they have appeared in many
forms in all the great lands throughout history.

Some of them are so meticulously crafted
that they look as if they might come to life.</text>
<text id="2896000">A ranseur forged from the soul of
the Old Dragonslayer.

The spear of the knight known as the
Dragonslayer was imbued with the
power of lightning, and shattered the
stone scales of dragons.
Strong attack unleashes its latent power.

Effect: lightning, special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="2900000">A lance originating in Heide.
A special alloy makes it very durable.

The composition of the alloy of these lances
remains a mystery, but in Drangleic the attempt
to imitate it resulted in the similar bradden
steel.

Lances are normally wielded by mounted knights,
and it takes considerable training to handle
one on the ground.</text>
<text id="2920000">A lance originating in Heide.
A special alloy makes it very durable.
The tip of the lance has been extended.

The composition of the alloy of these lances
remains a mystery, but in Drangleic the attempt
to imitate it resulted in the similar bradden
steel.

Lances are normally wielded by mounted knights,
and it takes considerable training to handle
one on the ground.</text>
<text id="2930000">A lance fashioned from rare geisteel.
Designed for high-ranking Drangleic knights,
hence the decorative design.

Geisteel equipment is of the finest make,
but geisteel is so rare that very few of
these weapons were actually used in combat.</text>
<text id="2940000">Lance forged from the soul of
the Executioner's Chariot.
Its cross-shaped blade causes bleeding.

The perverse design of this spear mirrors
the chariot from which it came, a merciless
creation that endlessly tortured the Undead.</text>
<text id="2950000">Lance wielded by the rampart golems,
granted life by the Ivory King.

The golems were charged with the
containment of the creatures of chaos
within the boundaries of the wall.

When the doors of Eleum Loyce were
flung open, the place turned frigid and lifeless,
but the golems remained dutifully on guard. </text>
<text id="2960000">Weapon wielded by the iron warriors
that wander Brume Tower.

Appears to have once been an axe,
but in this terribly melted state it is little more
than a great lump that crushes its foes
by virtue of its sheer weight.</text>
<text id="3000000">A great scythe used to harvest grain.

Normally used as a farm tool, not a weapon.
It feels almost as if there were power in its
giant blade, perhaps drawn from the fears of
those hunted by this fearsome thing.</text>
<text id="3010000">Created by strapping a large blade to a hilt.
A crude makeshift weapon with low durability.

Primitive weapons can be more effective
at evoking fear than more advanced efforts.
Perhaps this is why the wielder chose this
fearsome creation.</text>
<text id="3020000">A large sickle with a round blade.

The thin blade, fortified with bradden steel,
slices with a fine smoothness.
Hooks into flesh, then rips it apart
to cause bleeding.</text>
<text id="3040000">A sickle with a crescent-shaped blade.

This sickle, enchanted by magic,
is not intended as a weapon,
but rather a ceremonial instrument.</text>
<text id="3050000">The scythe used by Titchy Gren, and
by believers in Nahr Alma, god of blood.

Normally used only in ceremonies.
Imbued with the power of dark.

This is no place for talk of such things, however.</text>
<text id="3060000">Scythe forged from the soul of
the Covetous Demon.

The curved spine of the Covetous Demon is
as hard as rock, and rather than slicing
through flesh, this weapon seems to grind it apart.

That thing that ended up as a monstrous fiend,
what was it to begin with, and why did it never
leave the queen? Perhaps it was entranced
by some perversion of love.</text>
<text id="3070000">A scythe born from the soul of Nashandra.

The old one of the Abyss was reborn in death,
split into miniscule fragments, and spread
across the land. After regaining their shapes,
they crawled forth, yearning for strong souls,
in search of greater power.</text>
<text id="3080000">Scythe of the Forlorn,
who wander the land of the Undead.

The King's elder brother Aldia sought to
overcome the curse through means
unalike his sibling's.

The Forlorn were born of
Aldia's sinful infatuation.</text>
<text id="3200000">A halberd characterized by a sharp beaked spike.

This weapon is swung down upon foes like
a pickaxe, utilizing its own weight in a powerful
attack. Can break through a shielded guard
and deal damage.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="3210000">A scythe fitted with a large custom blade.

Has an extended slashing reach when
swung broadly, but beware, these
attacks make the wielder very vulnerable.</text>
<text id="3220000">Halberds are combinations of axes and spears
with unique bladed tips.

Can be used in spear-like thrust attacks,
or in axe-like sweeping attacks.

The halberd challenges a warrior's skills,
but can be a very effective weapon when
its two functions are applied properly.</text>
<text id="3240000">A halberd with a helix-shaped handle, headed
with a double blade. A complex design,
some would say excessively so, that hides
a spear within its handle.

Although its precise origins are unclear,
its construction appears to utilize
techniques from the lost land of Olaphis.</text>
<text id="3250000">A spear that was embedded in a stone statue.

According to an old local legend, a great spear
was used to defeat Santier, the walking statue.
Perhaps this is that very spear...

But it will be difficult to utilize such a thing
in the manner of a spear. Your only choice is
to swing it around, and smite foes about the head.</text>
<text id="3251000">A spear that was embedded in a stone statue.

According to an old local legend, a great spear
was used to defeat Santier, the walking statue.
Perhaps this is that very spear...

But it will be difficult to utilize such a thing
in the manner of a spear. Your only choice is
to swing it around, and smite foes about the head.</text>
<text id="3270000">Halberd of the Primal Knights
that defend Drangleic castle.

The brutish and mighty Primal Knights
wield this halberd like a feather-light twig,
but to the ordinary warrior it is a chore
to even hold up, owing to its great weight.

Terrible experiments were said to have
taken place in a hidden manor in Drangleic.
The mastermind presiding over the
deeds was thought to be Lord Aldia.</text>
<text id="3280000">Halberd of Targray, Knight of the Blue.
A fitting weapon for a shepherd of lost souls.

Those who put faith in an absolute good
also believe in the existence of true
evil. But to others, the distinction between
the two can be quite unclear.</text>
<text id="3290000">Halberd of the Dragonriders,
King Vendrick's royal guard.
A highly versatile weapon that can slash,
sweep, and thrust when wielded nimbly,
and is also imbued with magic.

Demands great skill of its wielder, and thus
served to test the worthiness of those
who aspired to join the Dragonriders.</text>
<text id="3300000">Halberd wielded by knights who served
a lord of light in a long-forgotten age.

Even after their flesh was charred by
flame, they remained as strong as ever,
and stood watch, challenging visitors to
their land.</text>
<text id="3310000">Replica of the halberd of the loyal knight Syan.
A meticulously-crafted, distinguished weapon.

Sir Syan was widely known as the kingdom's
most loyal knight, and when the Giants invaded,
he volunteered to lead the advance party,
but was slaughtered most dishonorably.

The King commissioned replicas of Syan's
accoutrements and bestowed them to
promising knights, but not long after they
donned the armor did they go thoroughly mad.</text>
<text id="3320000">Halberd forged from the soul of a Skeleton Lord.
Imbued with the power of dark.

The unsettling skull carved into this halberd
recalls the final moments of the Skeleton Lord
from whom it was created.</text>
<text id="3330000">An undated halberd.

Wielded by a warrior from a time so ancient
that there exists no record of his endeavors.
Has extremely low durability.

Sometimes, just as a thing falls to pieces,
it unleashes its last flash of great power...</text>
<text id="3340000">An undated pike.

Wielded by a warrior from a time so ancient
that there exists no record of his endeavors.
Has extremely low durability.

Sometimes, just as a thing falls to pieces,
it unleashes its last flash of great power...</text>
<text id="3350000">An extremely sturdy pitch-black war hammer.

Colossal warriors staunchly watch over
the shrine, ready to defend its resident,
or allow one worthy enough to be granted
audience.</text>
<text id="3370000">An armament forged from the soul of
Elana, child of Dark.
Use strong attack to unleash its latent power.

When the Abyss dissipated, the things
that called it home were fragmented
and scattered across the realm.
Eventually these pieces regained form,
in ways that hinted at humanity's true nature.</text>
<text id="3410000">A weapon that attaches to the hands.
The wearer attacks in a scratching motion
with these three-pronged claws.

Claws inflict deep wounds and
cause bleeding.</text>
<text id="3420000">One of the malformed weapons developed
in Aldia. Appears to be a crustacean pincer,
but its precise origins are unclear.
Use strong attack to inflict damage even upon
foes with raised shields.

The peculiar figure known as Lord Aldia 
attempted to uncover the secrets of life itself,
and viewed the Undead as a key to this mystery.

Effect: shield piercing (strong attack)</text>
<text id="3430000">Claws used by the manikins of Harvest Valley.

The peculiar art of puppetry
is a vestige of the two lost lands. 
The Queen, entranced by poison,
used it to beckon unknowing souls
to the defiled valley.</text>
<text id="3440000">A hook that covers the hand.

Clearly not intended as a weapon,
but certainly sharp enough to
shred an enemy's skin.</text>
<text id="3500000">Weapon used to strike with one's fists.
The thick leather covering bears iron studs,
and protects the hands while augmenting
their striking power.

Attacks with the fists are solely dependent on
one's strength. With this weapon, any encounter
becomes a brawl.</text>
<text id="3530000">Bone that is bound to the fist.
Used to enhance hand-to-hand combat.
Salvaged from a malformed creature.

Enables one to fight with inhuman strength,
as if the very spirit of the bone's malicious
owner has taken control.</text>
<text id="3600000">A leather whip.
Not normally used on the battlefield.

Very effective against bare flesh, but not
against enemies with armor or like protection.</text>
<text id="3610000">A whip covered in spikes.
Shreds skin and causes bleeding.

Very effective against bare flesh, but not
against enemies with armor or like protection.</text>
<text id="3620000">A blood-stained whip.
A tool made for a purpose forbidden by the gods.

Its effect is augmented by its pointed tip,
but still only marginally effective against
protective covering such as hard armor.</text>
<text id="3630000">A whip born from the soul of
the Demon of Song.
Covered with strange spots that
betray its poisonous effects.

The Demon's sonorous voice, in stark
contrast to its hideous form, is surely
intended to lure people close so that
it may devour them.</text>
<text id="3660000">A leather whip that has seen plenty of use.
It appears no different than an ordinary whip,
but is charmed by an ancient blessing
that boosts damage inflicted on Hollows.

The blessing is likely the work of a cleric,
but whether the spell is good or evil is unclear.

Effect: attack boost against Hollows</text>
<text id="3800000">The first staff of most sorcerers.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

To use sorceries, attune a sorcery
at a bonfire and equip a staff.
The strength of most sorceries is
affected by the caster's intelligence.</text>
<text id="3810000">Staff held by a priestess of Amana.
A ritual staff that was not intended for
use in battle, but nevertheless it functions
as a catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

The Demon was contained within the
shrine by sacred rituals, but over time the
tradition was lost, and the Demon set free.
It gained knowledge, and learned to lure
humans into its lair using song.

Effect: spell damage modifier while human</text>
<text id="3820000">Branch of a forest-wandering witchtree.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

Now it is used as a weapon, but this was
originally a part of a witchtree.</text>
<text id="3830000">Staff used by hollowed Drangleic sorcerers.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

The lizard affixed to its tip is a simple charm,
and has no bearing on the staff's powers.</text>
<text id="3850000">Staff of Olenford the sorcerer.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

Olenford, revered as the father of sorcery
in Melfia, sought knowledge that surpassed
mankind's ken, and so ventured into the
Undead Crypt, and did away with his humanity.

Some hold the theory that Melfian sorceries
and pyromancies originated within the
boundaries of Drangleic, in ages past.</text>
<text id="3860000">Staff of members of
the Archdrake sect of Lindelt.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

In Lindelt, known for its clerics
and their miracles, sorcery is
believed to be a profane practice.
But as with anything, such beliefs
are part faith and part front,
and this staff was born of that hypocrisy.</text>
<text id="3870000">Staff used by hollowed Drangleic sorcerers.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

The bat affixed to its tip is a simple charm.
It has no bearing on the staff's powers,
but the germs on the cadaver poison
foes upon contact in strike attacks.</text>
<text id="3880000">Staff crafted with animal bones.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

Properly trained sorcerers receive
their first staff from their master after
reaching a certain level of accomplishment.
Those without proper training must
devise something of their own making.</text>
<text id="3890000">Staff of the lost land of Olaphis.
Sorcery-dedicated catalyst.
Cannot be used to cast hexes.

The crystal at the tip of the staff
greatly augments spell strength.

Already a finely-crafted staff,
made even more effective by its crystal,
the brilliance of which has been polished
over time with powerful magic.</text>
<text id="3900000">A staff said to have been forged in Aldia.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.
Particularly powerful for casting hexes.

The mysterious Lord Aldia secluded himself
inside a manor to conduct various experiments.
Those invited to the manor disappeared,
replaced over time with malformed beasts
that roamed its halls.</text>
<text id="3910000">Spontoon used by warriors on pilgrimage.
Rather worn from the long journey
it has doubtless seen.

A spear which also doubles as
a catalyst for sorceries, making it an
ideal choice for light-footed pilgrims.

Effect: use sorcery (strong attack)</text>
<text id="3930000">Staff of Azal, sage of Forossa.

Rather roughly crafted, but
imbued with the magic of Azal.
Greatly intensifies spells, but also
drastically reduces spell usages.

This staff, unfit for the inexperienced,
is evidence of sage Azal's prowess.</text>
<text id="3940000">Staff wielded by the retainers
in the cathedral city.

Long ago, the retainers attended to
the priestesses, but with them gone,
the retainers were left to wander
frigid Eleum Loyce without purpose.</text>
<text id="4010000">Most clerics receive this as their first
sacred chime. A catalyst for miracles and hexes.

To use miracles, equip a sacred chime
and attune a miracle at a bonfire.
The strength of most miracles is
affected by the caster's faith.</text>
<text id="4020000">Witchtree bellvine that sprouts amongst old
growth. A catalyst for miracles and hexes.

Clerics who were ostracized devised this
as an alternative catalyst for casting miracles.

Most clerics who are stripped of their status
are good-for-nothings, but among them are
powerful spell casters who represented
real threats to the establishment.

Although not a proper catalyst,
the bellvine is quite powerful.</text>
<text id="4030000">Sacred chime granted to high-ranking clerics.
A catalyst for miracles and hexes.

Drangleic was the home of many clerics,
but King Vendrick held a lukewarm opinion of
their powers, and kept them only as attendants
to ceremony. In this sense, Drangleic was
not the place for a cleric with any ambition.</text>
<text id="4040000">A sacred chime shaped as a dragon.
A catalyst for miracles and hexes.

This chime sat long in the Dark Chasm,
but still one senses a sublime purity.
Only those with the deepest faith can
wield this chime, but they will be rewarded
with greatly amplified spells.</text>
<text id="4050000">Sacred chime created from the soul of
Nashandra.

The old one of the Abyss was reborn in death,
split into miniscule fragments, and spread
across the land.
After taking their shapes, they courted monarchs
of considerable power, which they desired
to make their own.</text>
<text id="4060000">Sacred chime used by members of the
Archdrake Sect of Lindelt.
A catalyst for miracles and hexes.

The land of Lindelt is governed by
stringent laws, and those who dare defy
them are punished without mercy.

It is often the sinful who seek piety,
spurred only by a selfish desire for salvation.</text>
<text id="4080000">Sacred chime of Licia of Lindelt.
A catalyst for miracles and hexes.

In any town there will be a few folk with
unusual urges. They either endeavor to resist
these urges, or act upon them out of the view
of others. The world is not so welcoming they
may bare their souls true.</text>
<text id="4090000">Sacred chime blessed by Caitha, goddess of tears.
Hex-dedicated catalyst.
Cannot be used to cast miracles.
Caitha, the goddess of tears, is known as a
compassionate being that is with us in
times of tragedy, but some believe that she
is a demoness that guides us toward misfortune.</text>
<text id="4100000">Sacred chime commonly used
by clerics of Lindelt.
A catalyst for miracles and hexes.

A sacred chime serves to conduct the
power of miracles, but in the past, something
entirely different served the same purpose.</text>
<text id="4110000">A rare sacred chime of unknown origin.
Can be used as a shield.

This chime, likely brought here by a visiting saint,
slightly augments the effects of miracles.
Use strong attack to emit miracles and hexes.

Effect: use miracles and hexes (strong attack)</text>
<text id="4120000">Sacred chime forged from
the soul of Nadalia, Bride of Ash.
Nothing appears sacred about the frightful
design of this chime, but it does have the
benefit of raising one's faith.

The oozing, frozen iron forming the bell
seems to anticipate a scream.</text>
<text id="4150000">Staff used by Leydia witches.
Imbued with a special magic, making it
a catalyst for sorceries, miracles, and hexes.

Leydia apostles are adept at magic, and wielded
unique weapons, but were deemed
blasphemous and slaughtered.

Effect: use sorceries, miracles, and hexes</text>
<text id="4200000">The type of small bow used by hunters in
training. Equip arrows to use.

Equip up to two types of arrows to give
yourself immediate options in battle.
Use arrows to hit enemies from afar to gain
the upper hand by drawing first blood.</text>
<text id="4210000">A standard bow used by hunters.
Equip arrows to use.

Equip up to two types of arrows to give
yourself immediate options in battle.
Use arrows to hit enemies from afar to gain
the upper hand by drawing first blood.</text>
<text id="4220000">A bow crafted from various materials.

Inflicts more damage than ordinary bows,
but has a shorter range, making it unfit
for sniping.</text>
<text id="4230000">A bow built for sea-faring marine warriors.
Has an extended range for hunting down
sea monsters from afar.

A great sea lies to the north of Drangleic,
and beyond that is an unexplored continent
that is home to things inhuman.</text>
<text id="4240000">Bow wielded by the Dragonriders,
King Vendrick's royal guard.
Merely drawing this bow requires inhuman
strength, but each shot has deadly potential.

Demands great skill of its wielder, and thus
served to test the worthiness of those
who aspired to join the Dragonriders.</text>
<text id="4270000">Wooden bow used by bell keepers.
Very light, and requiring hardly any strength.

The bells symbolize forbidden love;
the bell keepers, their faithful guardians,
ever-ready to annihilate trespassers.

They will stand watch, for ever and ever,
these determined, if ill-fated, marionettes.</text>
<text id="4280000">A bow created from the soul of Nashandra.

The old one of the Abyss was reborn in death,
split into miniscule fragments, and spread
across the land.

Light and Dark are two sides of the same coin,
much like the soul and the curse. The beings
who presented themselves to those in search
of kinghood were drawn to their awesome strength.</text>
<text id="4290000">A black bow designed for long distances.
Difficult to handle at first, and requiring
some amount of practice to master.

The hunting goddess Evlana was no goddess
at all, but rather a brave and highly skilled
bow huntress. Long after her demise,
the passing of lore transformed her into a deity.</text>
<text id="4400000">Unique bow equipped by Alonne Knights.

This very powerful bow uses greatarrows,
but each draw of the string requires a great
deal of time, leaving the shooter vulnerable.

In the heyday of his land, the Old Iron King
fancied entertaining dubious and eccentric
guests from faraway lands.

Most of them were charlatans, but among
the riff-raff was an unusual knight from
the far east. He trained the Iron King's men
in the sword, in obeisance to his new lord.</text>
<text id="4420000">A greatbow said to be used to down
ancient dragons flying high above the clouds.
Extremely large for a mere bow, and more
destructive than any ranged weapon imaginable.

Shooting this bow first requires the grounding
of its stabilizing anchor, which takes time and
leaves the shooter vulnerable. Also requires
greatarrows.</text>
<text id="4430000">Greatbow wielded by possessed armor.
Crafted with multiple layers of iron,
resulting in almost excessive sturdiness.

These suits of armor were once decorations,
until the black fog ruling the tower seized
control of them.</text>
<text id="4440000">A greatbow made of animal bone.
The fine craftsmanship suggests that
it originates in Lanafir.

The unusual design appears to have
ceremonial implications, but may simply
be intended to intimidate foes.</text>
<text id="4600000">A standard crossbow.
Equip bolts to use. Unlike bows,
a crossbow can be held in one hand.

Equip up to two types of bolts to give
yourself immediate options in battle.</text>
<text id="4610000">A large crossbow that deals heavy damage.
Equip bolts to use. Unlike bows,
a crossbow can be held in one hand.

Equip up to two types of bolts to give
yourself immediate options in battle.</text>
<text id="4630000">Crossbow created from the soul
of the Executioner's Chariot.
Iron plate serves as a shield while firing.

The merciless chariot inflicted agony upon
others with utter impunity, and the crossbow
created from its soul strives to protect
from possible retribution.

Effect: guard while firing</text>
<text id="4660000">An extremely rare rapid-firing crossbow.

Fire three successive bolts. Inflict heavy
damage by making all three shots count.

Fiorenza, the richest merchant in all of Volgen,
recreated this lost weapon after reading of it
in an old book.</text>
<text id="4670000">Crossbow wielded by sanctum knights.
Strong attack fires dark bolts.

These guardian knights were sentenced to eternal
stewardship of the Sanctum in a clandestine ritual
carried out in the great depths, but today the
sanctum receives nary a visitor.</text>
<text id="4680000">Repeating crossbow wielded by sanctum knights.
Strong attack fires dark bolts.

These guardian knights were sentenced to eternal
stewardship of the Sanctum in a clandestine ritual
carried out in the great depths, but today the
sanctum receives nary a visitor.</text>
<text id="5000000">A curved greatsword said to have been
brought to this land by a foreign warrior.
Hold with both hands to make parrying possible.

The exquisitely crafted wide blade makes deadly
use of both its weight and smooth slicing action.
A tough training regimen is required to master
this sword.</text>
<text id="5010000">A curved greatsword forged from
the soul of the Flexile Sentry.
There is something unsettling, and at the
same time beautiful, about its long curved blade.

The sentry crammed inmates of the
overflowing Bastille onto a rickety ship,
and cast them out to the open sea.

The majority of them drowned or starved,
but a few hardy survivors made land
to the south, and imparted their knowledge
of sorcery to the people there.</text>
<text id="5040000">A curved greatsword forged from
the soul of the Ancient Dragon.

In the Age of Ancients, the world was unformed,
shrouded by fog. A land of grey crags, archtrees,
and everlasting dragons.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="5050000">A great curved sword with an ominous blade.
One of the forbidden weapons sealed away
by the Ivory King.

Formed by rock, tree, and the remnants
of a most peculiar soul.

It is said that the farther its wielder travels,
the deadlier the blade becomes.</text>
<text id="5200000">A straight sword with a very long blade.
One of few ultra greatswords.

As the name suggests, the Zweihander is held
with two hands, but its weight is such that even
wielding it in this manner requires strength
worthy of the blade.</text>
<text id="5210000">A straight sword with a very long blade.
One of few ultra greatswords.

No human was intended to wield a sword
of this weight or destructiveness.

Only a few famed warriors have ever
wielded this great blade, for it challenges
the very limits of human ability.</text>
<text id="5220000">An ultra greatsword forged from
the soul of the Smelter Demon.
Its blade bears the strength of terrible flames,
a latent power unleashed by a strong attack.

The earth spouted fire, and a beast arose from
the flames. The short-sighted king was incinerated
by the creature in one swing, and his castle
devoured in a sea of flames.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="5225000">Ultra greatsword crafted from the soul
of the Smelter Demon.
Its blade is imbued with a great flame.
Use strong attack to unleash its latent power.

When the old king acquired the power to grant life
to heaps of iron, he molded a great array of
metallic automatons. The iron monstrosity itself
was perhaps one of the king's puppets.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="5230000">A sword decorated with drake wings.
Use strong attack to unleash its latent power.

The blade of this sword is split into two,
and is best swung in smashing motions
rather than slices.

Drakes are likely descendants of the ancient
dragons, and although their strength pales in
comparison to what is described in legend,
to mere humans they are still mighty beasts.

Effect: special attack (strong attack)</text>
<text id="5240000">An ultra greatsword forged from the soul
of King Vendrick.
Inflicts heavy damage on enemy armor.

Only the King knows whether the depiction
of the Queen is a resentful mockery,
or an affectionate exaltation.</text>
<text id="5250000">Ultra greatsword forged from
the soul of the fume knight.

The exile swordsman Raime had the
ability to expunge the black fog,
but chose instead to live alongside it,
in the company of the child of Dark
that haunts his sword.</text>
<text id="5255000">Ultra greatsword of the Ivory King of Eleum Loyce.
Wield with both hands to realize its full strength.

It is said that the Ivory King was once
the highest ranking knight in his home
of Forossa, famed for its god of war.
After taking his crown, they say he was the
first to swing his sword in times of need,
be it for his homeland or his people.</text>
<text id="5270000">Ultra greatsword of the Pursuer.
Known as the mightiest of the straight
swords, it demands great strength
and dexterity of its wielder.

The Pursuer hunts down those branded by
the curse, as if each Undead soul that he
claims will atone one of his sins.</text>
<text id="5275000">An extremely sturdy pitch-black greatsword.

Colossal warriors staunchly watch over
the shrine, ready to defend its resident,
or allow one worthy enough to be granted
audience.</text>
<text id="5280000">Ultra greatsword symbolizing guardianship
over the Undead Crypt. The sword has never
seen the light of day, and is steeped in dark.</text>
<text id="5285000">An undated ultra greatsword.

Wielded by a warrior from a time so ancient
that there exists no record of his endeavors.
Has extremely low durability.

Sometimes, just as a thing falls to pieces,
it unleashes its last flash of great power...</text>
<text id="5290000">Ultra greatsword wielded by knights who
served a lord of light in a long-forgotten age.

Even after their flesh was charred by
flame, they remained as strong as ever,
and stood watch, challenging visitors to
their land.</text>
<text id="5295000">An ultra greatsword forged from the soul
of the Lost Sinner.
Its blade saps the life of its wielder.

The true nature of this sword is unknown,
even to the Lost Sinner herself.
Those who choose this sword will share
the burden of the Lost Sinner's misdeeds.

Effect: attacks damage wielder</text>
<text id="5310000">Twinblade of the castle stone soldiers.

Sir Velstadt could always be found at the
King's side, and followed him when he fled.
The knights in his service waited patiently
for his return, but turned to stone before he did.</text>
<text id="5330000">Twinblade of the Dragonriders,
King Vendrick's royal guard.
Twinblades are wielded with an unusual
technique. This one strikes hard, but is very
heavy.

Demands great skill of its wielder, and thus
served to test the worthiness of those
who aspired to join the Dragonriders.</text>
<text id="5340000">A twinblade fashioned from rare geisteel.
Designed for high-ranking Drangleic knights,
hence the decorative design.

Geisteel equipment is of the finest make,
but geisteel is so rare that very few of
these weapons were actually used in combat.</text>
<text id="5350000">A twinblade with heavy blades on each end.
More suited to smashing foes than slashing them.
Requires a great deal of muscle to wield artfully.

The twinblade closely imitates the design of
a foreign-made weapon that has blades affixed
to both ends of its hilt.</text>
<text id="5360000">A twinblade imported from a foreign land.
The razor-sharp blades cause bleeding,
but as a result, are easily worn and dulled.

When wielded by a master, this dual-tipped
blade is an unparalleled weapon that hardly
allows a foe the opportunity to retaliate.</text>
<text id="5370000">A twinblade originating in Melfia.
Doubles as a catalyst for sorcery.

A rare weapon used by very few warriors,
owing to its dependence on honed skills
with both staff and sword.

Effect: use sorcery (strong attack)</text>
<text id="5400000">A flame catalyst used by pyromancers.
Pyromancers rouse this flame to produce
various fire arts.

Equip pyromancy flame to produce pyromancy.
Attune pyromancies at a bonfire.

The strength of a pyromancy depends on the
strength of one's pyromancy flame, which can
be improved through reinforcement.</text>
<text id="5410000">A flame catalyst used by pyromancers.
Pyromancers rouse this flame to produce
various fire arts.

The flame rewards those with a thirst for power.
The more Hollowed one is, the stronger its effect.

Effect: Spell power scales with Hollowing</text>
<text id="5500000">A dagger affixed with a black crystal.
Found deep inside the Gutter, in the Black Gulch.
Heavier than a standard dagger, but with a
fine crystal that gives it a smoother slice.

Some of the more determined souls exiled
to the Gutter sought to scale the walls of the
forsaken place and walk the earth once again,
but failed, and wasted away mired in misery and
resentment.</text>
<text id="5510000">A straight sword affixed with yellow quartz.
This longsword was found in the Iron Keep.
Breaks easily due to corrosion, but is light
and still inflicts very significant damage.

In the Old Iron King's great iron keep
was a vast collection of weapons, erected
as a display of strength to the world.
But they were lost when the king's conceit
doomed the castle to sink into a lake of fire.</text>
<text id="5520000">An axe with an unusual design.
Found in the Undead Purgatory.
The chains and spikes wrapped around the
axe cause bleeding, but weaken the axe's
effectiveness when slashing.

Accessories that are added to a weapon
for the sole purpose of tormenting foes
can often detract from the weapon's
natural effectiveness.</text>
<text id="5530000">A pole with lumps attached to it.
Found in the manor in Aldia.
Heavier than a standard mace, but with more
effective striking owing to its hard lumps.

In the far eastern outskirts of Drangleic lies an
old manor that is now long forgotten.
As it should be, for the things that lurk there
are better left unknown.</text>
<text id="5540000">A staff enwreathed in a matte blackness.
Found in the heart of the Dark Chasm.
A catalyst for sorceries and hexes.

No one knows what lies beyond the
dark passages found across Drangleic,
but perhaps they are better left undisturbed.</text>
<text id="6100000">Binoculars are used to peer at distant sights.
Equip in place of a weapon to use.

A rare tool crafted in Volgen.
These won't help you in battle, but with a
little creativity, can be put to good use.</text>
<text id="11000000">A traditional small metal shield.

Small shields are very light and easy to use,
but have low stability when attacked.

The center of a buckler is convex,
designed to brush attacks aside,
making parrying easier.</text>
<text id="11005000">Small shield of Benhart of Jugo.

This parma, emblazoned with a family crest
of some sort, has clearly been around for
several generations, but has no special value.</text>
<text id="11010000">Small, leather-covered shield.
A particularly traditional type of small shield.

Small shields are very light and easy to use,
but not very stable when attacked.</text>
<text id="11020000">A small shield made of iron.
The unusual design suggests a foreign origin.

Lightweight despite its iron construction,
and sturdy despite its small size, but not
sufficient to protect one from real danger.</text>
<text id="11030000">A small shield used by Drangleic foot soldiers.

A clearly makeshift shield that does not offer
significant defense. The only advantage of this
shield is that it makes parrying easier.</text>
<text id="11040000">Small metal shield with protrusions.

Small shields are very light and easy to use,
but are not very stable when attacked.

The protrusions on the center of the shield
are designed to brush attacks aside and
make parrying easier.</text>
<text id="11050000">Small shield used by Volgen Falconers.
Appears like a glistening gold falcon from afar.

Domestic Volgen soldiers are infamously timid,
so it is no wonder that this fierce band of
mercenary falconers was hired to compensate.

The falconers are rumored to be untrusting of
others, and demanding of prompt, full payment.
But no wonder; they deliver much more than
they are paid, and are well aware of it.</text>
<text id="11070000">A shield used by the
manikins of Harvest Valley.

The peculiar art of puppetry
is a vestige of the two lost lands. 
The Queen, entranced by poison,
used it to beckon unknowing souls
to the defiled valley.</text>
<text id="11080000">A small shield fashioned from rare geisteel.

A masterpiece of the great blacksmith Llewellyn
that he brought along as a gift when he
left Mirrah for Drangleic.</text>
<text id="11091000">A standard wooden parma.

The fancy name and nifty paint are
surely a merchant's efforts to make
this very ordinary shield more attractive.</text>
<text id="11110000">A parma used by clerics on pilgrimage.
Enchanted with a somewhat fragile blessing that
allows spells to be deflected by parrying.

Unfortunately, the shield provides very little
physical defense, and is more of a lucky charm
than a proper shield.</text>
<text id="11120000">A small shield used by clerics on pilgrimage.
Enchanted with a somewhat fragile blessing that
allows spells to be deflected by parrying.

Specially-crafted to provide extra durability
and some level of physical defense.</text>
<text id="11130000">Small shield used by Leydia apostles.
Imbued with a special magic that allows
spells to be deflected by parrying.

The Leydia apostles were inhabitants of the
Undead Crypt, but failed to treat death
with the proper respect. As punishment,
they were denied peaceful deaths.</text>
<text id="11140000">Small shield used by Aldian warlocks.
Reinforced by a covert ritual that granted
the shield the power of flame.
Can deflect spells by parrying.

The peculiar figure known as Lord Aldia
kept Giants in his manor, and attempted
to recreate a dragon, but after some time,
was not heard from again.</text>
<text id="11150000">A shield with a curious design.
One of the treasures of the Sunken King.

A mixture of mystical tree branch
and sacred chime iron allows this shield
to serve as a catalyst for miracles
and sorceries.

Most of the miracles and sorceries
created in the Sanctum City were lost,
but the quality of their armor and shields
suggests highly advanced craftsmanship.</text>
<text id="11160000">Small Varangian shield engraved with a strange
pattern.

A former king launched a campaign to
capture these terrors of the high seas,
but rather than imprison them, forced
them into hard labor at No-man's Wharf.</text>
<text id="11185000">Small shield used by the Throne Watcher.
Made from an old sacred chime.

The Watcher has stood by the throne for ages.
Will his wishes be fulfilled?</text>
<text id="11200000">A leather-covered shield.
Preferred by hunters.

Inferior to metal shields in terms of
stability and physical damage reduction,
but easy to use and weighing so little
that it hardly requires any strength to bear.</text>
<text id="11210000">Wooden shield used from ancient times.

Inferior to metal shields in terms of
stability and physical damage reduction,
but easy to use and weighing so little
that it hardly requires any strength to bear.</text>
<text id="11220000">Medium-sized metal shield.
A commonly-used, standard shield.

Has a pointed top designed for ease
of use while on horseback.</text>
<text id="11230000">Captain Drummond's shield.
Even with its embossing terribly worn,
this shield exudes pride and authority.

An heirloom passed from grandfather to father,
and then from father to son. Drummond,
and those before him, held this shield when
facing those who would threaten their great land.</text>
<text id="11240000">Shield used by the Lion Clan warriors.
Made of wood, but reinforced with metal.
Light yet sturdy.

The design on the shield appears to have some
religious significance, but we will never know
what sort of gods these warriors answer to.</text>
<text id="11250000">Shield of the Archdrake sect of Lindelt.
The dragon was engraved for ritual purposes,
but the shield itself is highly functional.

The secrets of Lindelt rituals are protected
by the Archdrake sect, and only a select few
are given access to their canon of knowledge,
which includes the truthful origins of the
Archdrake sect itself.</text>
<text id="11260000">Shield of Vendrick, King of Drangleic.

One fragment of Dark, having taken human shape,
became obsessed with the King's soul.
Impelled by its own cravings, it sought souls,
and strove to make the strength of the Giants
its own.</text>
<text id="11270000">Shield issued to the proud knights
of Mirrah's official order.

In Mirrah, a land perennially beset by unrest,
this shield was a symbol of the great knights'
strength and willingness to give their lives for
their country.</text>
<text id="11280000">An undated ancient shield.

Wielded by a warrior from a time so ancient
that there exists no record of his endeavors.
Has extremely low durability.

Sometimes, just as a thing falls to pieces,
it unleashes its last flash of great power...</text>
<text id="11290000">Shield of the Knights of Loyce.
Gradually restores HP while equipped.

The Knights of Loyce were commanded
to strike down each malformed terror that
arose from Chaos, and they would not
hesitate even if it were their own king.</text>
<text id="11295000">Charred shield of the Knights of Loyce,
burned black by flame.
Gradually restores HP while equipped.

These Knights of Loyce lacked all sense of self,
and were driven only by the urge to expunge
any who might disturb the flame, even
former compatriots.</text>
<text id="11300000">A shield with a blue relief of a spirit tree.

A rather well-built shield decorated by
the spirit tree that appears in the allegory
of Quella, god of dream.

Has a faint residue of magic,
and can deflect spells by parrying.</text>
<text id="11310000">A blue shield with a gold relief of wings.
Likely a symbol of guardianship used
by Knights of the Blue.

Contains materials enchanted by magic,
allowing spells to be deflected by parrying.</text>
<text id="11320000">Shield depicting a priestess
of Eleum Loyce.

Emanates a certain heat that
heightens the abilities of its bearer.

The priestesses, who devoted themselves
to appeasing the ancient flame, are no longer.</text>
<text id="11330000">The shield of formerly high-ranking clerics.
The effects of a blessing are still with it,
and the shield recovers one's stamina.

The clerics held venerated positions once,
but now, their souls wander aimlessly
in the depths of a murky darkness.

Effect: stamina recovery</text>
<text id="11350000">A silver-black shield imbued with the
power of dark.

The equipment of the wardens of the
Undead Crypt are soaked in its darkness,
and permeated by its power.

The grave wardens are said to know the name
of every guest who rests in the crypt,
no matter how long they have been with them.</text>
<text id="11360000">Shield of the castle stone soldiers.

Sir Velstadt could always be found at the
King's side, and followed him when he fled.
The knights in his service waited patiently
for his return, but turned to stone before he did.</text>
<text id="11370000">Shield of the blue spirit tree that
and is said to possess divine powers.

Appears in the allegory of Quella, 
God of Dream, and can deflect spells 
by parrying. 

Once there was a boy who was easily
frightened, until the talking tree of dreamworld
transformed itself into a shield to protect him.</text>
<text id="11380000">Shield depicting the moon butterfly.
A decorative shield not intended for battle,
but effective at poisoning foes.

Little is known about the moon butterfly,
which only appears on full-moon nights in winter.
Some say the butterfly is a magical being,
and its larvae have never once been spotted.</text>
<text id="11390000">Shield of the Archdrake sect of Lindelt.
Represents a slumbering dragon,
and is intended for use in covert rituals.

The fools who woke the slumbering dragon
earned not only its ire, but also the
destruction of an entire country.

The survivors buried their wrongdoings in
the past, and in a show of terrible conceit,
attempted to make amends by carrying on
the knowledge of the wasted land.

Effect: stamina recovery</text>
<text id="11395000">Shield of darkness and chaos.

Once, a brilliant young sorcerer cast away his
earthly desires, devoting himself entirely to the
Dark that bewitched him.

Nebulous, inky and serene, the Dark holds an
allure matched only by the fear it strikes
in men's hearts. Could it be nature,
holding a mirror to mankind?</text>
<text id="11400000">A long wooden shield.
Its face features a lion.

Its wooden construction makes it lightweight
and easy to use, but as a shield is inferior
to its metal counterparts.</text>
<text id="11420000">Shield of hollowed royal soldiers.
The thing is in tatters, and only serves
as a shield in a most minimal respect.

The accoutrements of royal soldiers feature
a depiction of a brave knight from an old parable.</text>
<text id="11430000">A metal shield issued to knights.

Nothing special about this shield, which is
precisely why it is so easy to use,
and the likely reason for its popularity.

People rarely agree over what constitutes
quality, but the broad popularity of these
shields proves that there are exceptions.</text>
<text id="11450000">Shield of warrior Vengarl of Forossa.

The chisels on the face were carved by
Vengarl, to count the heads he claimed.
The shield is terribly rusted and worn,
but incredibly powerful,
as if the deeds of its previous owner
have rubbed off on it.</text>
<text id="11455000">Shield wielded by the rampart golems,
granted life by the Ivory King.

The golems were charged with the
containment of the creatures of chaos
within the boundaries of the wall.

When the doors of Eleum Loyce were
flung open, the place turned frigid and lifeless,
but the golems remained dutifully on guard. </text>
<text id="11470000">A wooden parma issued to bell keepers.
Very light, and requiring hardly any strength.

The bells symbolize forbidden love;
the bell keepers, their faithful guardians,
ever-ready to annihilate trespassers.

They will stand watch, for ever and ever,
these determined, if ill-fated, marionettes.</text>
<text id="11475000">Shield of the Throne Defender.
Permeated by powerful magic.

The Defender has stood by the throne for ages.
Will his wait be worth the while?</text>
<text id="11480000">A shield that appears in ancient legends.
Strangely shaped, and said to be crafted
from the talons of the black dragon.

The legend of the pale dragon is told in
various locales, but each account is fragmentary.
Very rarely is the black dragon mentioned,
and some say that it is merely an embellishment
adopted in later retellings of the story.</text>
<text id="11485000">An extremely sturdy pitch-black shield.

Colossal warriors staunchly watch over
the shrine, ready to defend its resident,
or allow one worthy enough to be granted
audience.</text>
<text id="11490000">A strangely porcine shield.

The pig head looks eerily authentic, but is an
imitation. Though the shield's defensive capacity
is ordinary, it may spook an unsuspecting foe.</text>
<text id="11495000">Shield used by Aldian acolytes.
Crafted from the skull of some creature that
outlived its usefulness for experimentation.

The peculiar figure known as Lord Aldia
kept Giants in his manor, and attempted
to recreate a dragon, but after some time,
was not heard from again.</text>
<text id="11500000">A wooden greatshield featuring twin dragons.
Quite light for this size of shield.

One requires strength to handle a greatshield,
but they are very stable. In battle, one fights
using shield bash instead of parrying.</text>
<text id="11510000">A metal greatshield.
Very heavy, and requiring great strength to
handle, but provides excellent defense.

One requires strength to handle a greatshield,
but they are very stable. In battle, one fights
using shield bash instead of parrying.</text>
<text id="11530000">Shield of the knights who long ago
attempted to conquer the Undead Crypt.

They bore no weapons, only a shield split into
left and right halves, which they used to
playfully crush their foes until their corpses
were kneaded beyond recognition.

The engraving depicts two messengers from the
hereafter who welcome the recently dead by
reviewing the merits of their deeds in life.</text>
<text id="11540000">Shield of the knights who long ago
attempted to conquer the Undead Crypt.

They bore no weapons, only a shield split into
left and right halves, which they used to
playfully crush their foes until their corpses
were kneaded beyond recognition.

The engraving depicts two messengers from the
hereafter who welcome the recently dead by
reviewing the merits of their deeds in life.</text>
<text id="11550000">A greatshield created from the soul
of the Looking Glass Knight.
Can deflect spells.

The Looking Glass at the castle is said
to have been a passage to another world.</text>
<text id="11560000">Greatshield of the Dragonriders,
King Vendrick's royal guard.

The rank of Dragonrider was reserved for
honorable warriors who helped found Drangleic.
Together with the King, they crushed its former
inhabitants and erected a magnificent kingdom
upon their graves.</text>
<text id="11570000">Shield of the Primal Knights
that defend Drangleic castle.
Very heavy, and has the power of lightning.

The brutish and mighty Primal Knights
wield this shield as if it were made of paper,
but to the ordinary warrior it is a chore
to even hold up, owing to its great weight.

Whatever was created by Lord Aldia
was lost with his disappearance,
but the King attempted to revive these
things, even if only fragments remained.</text>
<text id="11590000">A shield formed by chiseling a giant boulder.
As solid as rock, this shield offers incredible
defense, but is also terribly heavy.

So heavy, in fact, that he who takes it
into battle is not allowed to flee,
until he or his opponent has fallen.</text>
<text id="11600000">A greatshield used by the nomadic Gyrm.

Appears to be a stone monument that was
converted into a makeshift shield.
Naturally, it is quite heavy, and haphazardly
crafted, but very few attacks will make it
past this monster.</text>
<text id="11610000">Greatshield of the Pursuer.
For those who can handle the weight of
this shield, it offers resistance to curses.

The Pursuer hunts down those branded by
the curse, as if each Undead soul that he
claims will atone one of his sins.</text>
<text id="11620000">Pate's favorite greatshield.
Appears rather humdrum, but in fact was
forged by layering thin sheets of iron,
a process that creates a shield with
excellent defense for its weight.

It is not always advisable to stand out.
Especially if you have something to hide.</text>
<text id="11630000">An undated ancient greatshield.

Wielded by a warrior from a time so ancient
that there exists no record of his endeavors.
Has extremely low durability.

Sometimes, just as a thing falls to pieces,
it unleashes its last flash of great power...</text>
<text id="11640000">An extremely sturdy pitch-black greatshield.

Colossal warriors staunchly watch over
the shrine, ready to defend its resident,
or allow one worthy enough to be granted
audience.</text>
<text id="11650000">Greatshield of the King's loyal knight Syan.

The King commissioned this greatshield
specifically for his loyal knight, but Syan
met his demise before its completion.</text>
<text id="11700000">A small shield decorated with a phoenix.

The sea of flame that swallowed the
Iron Keep took this shield as well, but when
it was retrieved it was mysteriously unscathed,
save a degree of discoloration.</text>
<text id="11710000">A small shield depicting a hero of yore.

Perhaps these famed champions are no more,
or perhaps they have no desire to appear in
public view.

But their very absence has made tales of their
brave deeds all the more alluring, and this
shield memorializes one of their brethren.</text>
<text id="11720000">A shield decorated by intertwined dragons.

The black and white contrast depicts the
ebb and flow of the fate of all things living,
and the serpentine dragons that watch over
the march of time.

The bearer of this shield will be blessed
by great fortune in battle.</text>
<text id="11730000">A rare shield depicting a blossoming flower,
that soothes the weary heart of its bearer.

What makes flowers beautiful, and why
are we comforted when we gaze upon them?
Sadly, the flower depicted on this shield
went extinct long ago.

Effect: stamina recovery</text>
<text id="11740000">Shield of the rebel Raime.

Raime and Velstadt were known as
the left- and right-arms of the King,
until their wills clashed, and Raime was
deemed a traitor.

The black raven is despised as an augur
of death, but it was Raime's favorite bird.</text>
<text id="11750000">A greatshield with an unsettling design.
Covered in the prints of countless hands.

The true origin of this shield is unknown.
No amount of polishing can clear its face
of the mysterious hand prints.

Effect: HP absorb</text>
<text id="11800000">A shield affixed with a black crystal.
Found deep inside the Gutter, in the Black Gulch.
Heavier than a standard small shield but the hard
crystal boosts its defense against slashing.

Some of the more determined souls exiled
to the Gutter sought to scale the walls of the
forsaken place and walk the earth once again,
but failed, and wasted away mired in misery and
resentment.</text>
<text id="11810000">A small shield affixed with a yellow quartz.
This shield was found in the Iron Keep.
Breaks easily due to corrosion,
but is light and still very stable.

In the Old Iron King's great iron keep
was a vast collection of weapons, erected
as a display of strength to the world.
But they were lost when the king's conceit
doomed the castle to sink into a lake of fire.</text>
<text id="11820000">A shield with an unusual design.
Found in the Undead Purgatory.
The chains and spikes wrapped around the
shield cause bleeding, but weaken the shield's
effectiveness.

Accessories that are added to a weapon
for the sole purpose of tormenting foes
can often detract from the weapon's
natural effectiveness.</text>
<text id="11830000">A shield with lumps attached to it.
Found in the manor in Aldia.
Heavier than a standard shield,
but more stable owing to the hard lumps.

In the far eastern outskirts of Drangleic lies an
old manor that is now long forgotten.
As it should be, for the things that lurk there
are better left unknown.</text>
<text id="11840000">A shield enwreathed in a matte blackness.
Found in the heart of the Dark Chasm.

No one knows what lies beyond the
dark passages found across Drangleic,
but perhaps they are better left undisturbed.</text>
<text id="60760000">Inexpensive wooden arrows.
Easily acquired, but not very threatening.

Bows are excellent tools for attacking
foes from a safe distance, but require
the equipping of some type of arrow.</text>
<text id="60770000">Standard arrows made of iron.
Sturdy arrows that pierce effectively.

Iron arrows are powerful, but not cheap.
Be certain not to overuse them.</text>
<text id="60780000">Arrows imbued with magic.
Tipped with a Aromatic Ooze.

Weapons fortified with magic are particularly
effective against heavily armored foes
or creatures with thick scales.
Useful in the short term for those who have
learned no magic, or whose magic is exhausted.</text>
<text id="60790000">Arrows imbued with lightning.
Tipped with Gold Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with lightning are effective
against foes resistant to magic and fire.
Useful in the short term for those who have
learned no magic, or whose magic is exhausted.</text>
<text id="60800000">Arrows imbued with fire.
Tipped with Charcoal Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with fire are effective against
against foes vulnerable to magic and fire, such
as Undead or beasts.

Useful in the short term for those who have
learned no magic, or whose magic is exhausted.</text>
<text id="60810000">Arrows imbued with dark flame.
Tipped with Dark Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with dark are effective
against those who fear the dark, such as
clerics and magical creatures.

Useful in the short term for those who have
learned no magic, or whose magic is exhausted.</text>
<text id="60820000">Arrows imbued with poison.
Tipped with Rotten Pine Resin.

Poisoned foes slowly lose HP over time.</text>
<text id="60830000">Arrows that cause bleeding.
Tipped with finely sharpened arrow heads.

Bleeding foes' max HP is lowered.</text>
<text id="60850000">Standard greatarrows made of iron.

More effective than regular arrows,
but considerably heavier.</text>
<text id="60870000">Greatarrows imbued with lightning.
Tipped with Gold Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with lightning are effective
against foes resistant to magic and fire.

If you require magic but have learned none
yourself, these will serve you well.</text>
<text id="60880000">Greatarrows imbued with fire.
Tipped with Charcoal Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with fire are effective against
against foes vulnerable to fire, such
as Undead or beasts.

If you require magic but have learned none
yourself, these will serve you well.</text>
<text id="60900000">Greatarrows with intricately crafted tips.
Designed to destroy equipment with impact.

Bravery does not necessarily entail going
head-on with a foe, especially if they have
better armor than you. Use these arrows,
and grind them down from afar.</text>
<text id="60910000">Inexpensive wooden bolts.
Not very intimidating, but highly portable
and easy to use.

Use of a crossbow requires the equipping
of bolts, which are shorter than arrows.</text>
<text id="60920000">Standard crossbow bolts made of iron.
Effective at piercing enemies.

Very effective in ranged attacks,
though somewhat expensive to
use willy-nilly.</text>
<text id="60930000">Bolt imbued with magic.
Tipped with Aromatic Ooze.

Weapons fortified with magic are particularly
effective against heavily armored foes
or creatures with thick scales.

Crossbows and specialized bolts allow warriors
with low dexterity to inflict elemental damage.</text>
<text id="60940000">Bolt imbued with lightning.
Tipped with Gold Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with lightning are effective
against foes that are resistant to magic and fire.

Crossbows and specialized bolts allow warriors
with low dexterity to inflict elemental damage.</text>
<text id="60950000">Bolt imbued with fire.
Tipped with Charcoal Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with fire are effective
against foes vulnerable to fire, such
as Undead or beasts.

Crossbows and specialized bolts allow warriors
with low dexterity to inflict elemental damage.</text>
<text id="60960000">Bolt imbued with dark flame.
Tipped with Dark Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with dark are effective
against those who fear the dark, such as
clerics and magical creatures.

Crossbows and specialized bolts allow warriors
with low dexterity to inflict elemental damage.</text>
<text id="3510000">Claws used by those who lurk in the shadows.
A sharp blade is attached to each of the fingers.

Those who abandoned the knight's code
stooped to all manner of unspeakable deeds,
all for a bit of coin.</text>
<text id="60840000">Inexpensive wooden greatarrows.

Bows are excellent tools for attacking
foes from a safe distance, but naturally,
require an arrow to be equipped.

Greatbows will not function with ordinary
arrows. Equip specially-designed greatarrows.</text>
<text id="60860000">Greatarrows imbued with magic.
Tipped with a Aromatic Ooze.

Weapons fortified with magic are particularly
effective against heavily armored foes
or creatures with thick scales.

If you require magic but have learned none
yourself, these will serve you well.</text>
<text id="60890000">Greatarrows imbued with dark flame.
Tipped with Dark Pine Resin.

Weapons fortified with dark are effective
against those who fear the dark, such as
clerics and magical creatures.

If you require magic but have learned none
yourself, these will serve you well.</text>
<text id="900008400">This standard small dagger possesses only modest attack,
	but can be jabbed in rapid succession.

Though daggers are the most basic weapons,
their light weight allows for powerful critical hits.
Masters of this weapon will find it sufficient for combat.</text>
<text id="900008401">Dagger fashioned from rare geisteel,
boasting an unusually long blade.

Though this dagger was bestowed as a gift
by the king of these lands to his chancellor,
the fate of its owner remains obscure.</text>
<text id="900008402">Standard straight sword.

Though the sword excels in no one area,
it is an accessible weapon widely used by many,
from novice adventurers to experienced warriors.</text>
<text id="900008403">A widely-used small straight sword.

Particularly easy to wield,
allowing even the weak to make effective use of it.
This weapon alone should be enough to fight with,
provided one isn't too hard-pressed by circumstance.</text>
<text id="900008404">Black axe from the tales of Shieldless Lothian.
Balances maneuverability and power,
but requires strength and dexterity.

Long ago, many tried and failed
to seek out this legendary axe,
and with time it faded into obscurity.</text>
<text id="900008405">This greataxe is a veritable mass of iron.
Its weight sends foes flying,
but makes it difficult to handle without inhuman strength.

Each swing of the greataxe requires
the full force of the body,
making this weapon suitable only
for those confident in their accuracy.</text>
<text id="900008406">Halberd used by the Dragonriders, the retinue
of the king. Though otherwise traditional in
design, these halberds are particularly heavy.

A tremendously versatile weapon,
allowing for slashing, sweeping,
and even thrusting attacks.</text>
<text id="900008407">Branch sawn from one of the witchtrees
	that wander the forests.
Catalyst for sorceries and pyromancies.

Slight remnants of the witchtree's
mind channel power to the staff,
and it is for this reason that even
high-ranking sorcerers use these as catalysts.</text>
<text id="900008408">Staff used by the fallen sorcerers who wander this land.
A catalyst for both sorceries and pyromancies.
Particularly well-attuned for sorceries.

The lizard bound to its tip is a simple charm,
and has no bearing on the staff's powers.</text>
<text id="900008409">Sacred bell used by an order of knights.
Catalyst for miracles and hexes.

Though little is truly known about the order,
it is said that their well-honed miracles
and unwavering loyalty in the face of death
made them worthy rivals to this country in their day. </text>
<text id="900008410">Sacred bell imbued with the prayers of a renowned saint.
Catalyst for miracles and hexes.

The saint came to these lands from a peaceful country.
However, no more can be divulged
about her to such transient travellers.</text>
<text id="900008411">Standard projectile weapon.

Equip arrows to use.
You can change the arrows used by
equipping them to your belt slots.

Aim for the heads of foes to deal a great amount of damage.</text>
<text id="900008412">Standard projectile weapon.
Unlike bows, a crossbow can be held in one hand.

Equip bolts to use.
You can change the ammunition used by
equipping different bolts to your belt slots.</text>
<text id="900008413">Small, round metal shield with
protrusions that enhance parrying ability.

Small shields are generally suited to parrying,
but this shield is particularly specialized for the job.</text>
<text id="900008414">Small, leather-covered round shield.
A particularly traditional type of small shield.

Though the defensive abilities of small shields
pale in comparison to normal and greatshields,
they make it particularly easy
to deliver critical hits after parrying.</text>
<text id="900008415">A metallic shield with a wing design in gold.
Although it has low resistance to magic,
it can take a fair pounding.

This shield must have belonged to warriors
of an ancient covenant.</text>
<text id="900008416">Shield used by an order of knights.
Having been blessed,
this shield excels against miracles and hexes.

Though little is truly known about the order,
it is said that their well-honed miracles
and unwavering loyalty in the face of death
made them worthy rivals to this country in their day. </text>
<text id="900008417">Medium-sized metal shield.

Emblazoned in silver with an eagle crest,
a symbol of glory.
A commonly-used, standard shield.</text>
<text id="900008418">A certain man's favorite greatshield.
Forged by layering thin sheets of iron,
it provides excellent defense for its weight.

Perhaps you'll learn more
about the original owner when next you meet... </text>
<text id="900008419">Bell with a curious shape.
Can be used as a shield.

This type of bell is not used
by the clergy of these lands.
Perhaps it was brought from a foreign clime?

Provides a slight increase to
the effectiveness of miracles.</text>
<text id="900008420">Greatsword belonging to a man
known as "The Pursuer".
Known as the mightiest of the straight swords,
it also asks great strength and dexterity of its wielder.

This sword was held one-handed by its previous owner,
but now is not the timeto discuss him.</text>
<text id="900008421">An ultra greatsword, the heaviest of weapons.

As the name suggests,
the Zweihander is held with two hands,
but its weight is such that even wielding it in this manner
requires strength worthy of the blade.</text>
<text id="900008422">A long-hilted spear that boasts considerable reach,
and can be used from behind a raised shield.

It takes its name from the
wing-like protrusions beneath the blade,
which allow the spear to be pulled
more easily from pierced foes.</text>
<text id="900008423">A large thrusting sword.
Known for its sturdy, slender blade designed
to pierce foes through solid armor.

The blade's sharpness runs its length,
allowing for slashing attacks as well.</text>
<text id="900008424">This standard greatsword is normally wielded
with two hands due to its great weight.

Usually swung in large arcs and effective
against multiple foes. But such attacks leave
the wielder exposed, and effective use of the
weapon requires practice.</text>
<text id="900008425">Greatsword used by an orthodox order
of knights from the East.
Designed to be swung in a particular style,
requiring high dexterity to master.

Accomplished knights were allowed to
inscribe their oaths into the body of the blade.
It is believed that uninscribed swords belonged
to knights who failed to distinguish themselves.</text>
<text id="900008426">Katana used by the inquisitors.

Though there is no secret to the manner of its forging,
the katana's hefty blade glistens
with extraordinary sharpness.
Perhaps its great weight portends to
the great washes of blood it has supped upon.</text>
<text id="900008432">An ancient greatsword of unknown origin.
This sword was wielded by
the rebel Raime before he was exiled,
but in his shame he cast it aside as he fled Drangleic.
It was recovered by Gordin, wandering knight of Forossa,
and was thought to lost with him.

Uncannily, every last one of the prominent swordsmen
who inherited this weapon was left-handed.</text>
</entries>